<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>opensemi</title>
  
  <subtitle>we bring you the daily insight in semiconductor industry</subtitle>
  <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/"/>
  <updated>2025-06-23T22:21:34.476Z</updated>
  <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/</id>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>STMicro Advances PiezoMEMS Development in Singapore</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250624_STMicro-Advances-PiezoMEMS-Development-in-Singapore/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250624_STMicro-Advances-PiezoMEMS-Development-in-Singapore/</id>
    <published>2025-06-23T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-06-23T22:21:34.476Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/stmicro-advances-piezomems-development-in-singapore/">News</a></h2><p><strong>STMicro Advances PiezoMEMS Development in Singapore</strong><br>STMicroelectronics, in collaboration with A*STAR and ULVAC, has launched Lab-in-Fab 2.0 at its Ang Mo Kio campus, focusing on lead-free piezoelectric MEMS. This initiative accelerates the transition from prototyping to manufacturing, aiming to achieve a sustainable alternative to lead-based materials by 2027. The Lab-in-Fab model enables seamless integration of research and production, enhancing time to market for MEMS applications in consumer electronics and medical devices.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/7669543_AI4I0453_Engineer-preparing-wafer-for-analysis.png" alt="STMicro Lab-in-Fab"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-06-3d-chip-stacking-method-traditional.html">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>3D Chip Stacking Method Created to Overcome Traditional Semiconductor Limitations</strong><br>Researchers from the Institute of Science Tokyo have developed a novel 3D chip integration method named BBCube, which employs advanced bonding techniques to enhance memory bandwidth and reduce power consumption in high-performance computing applications. This innovative approach addresses traditional semiconductor limitations by stacking processing units directly above DRAM, significantly improving power supply integrity and efficiency.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/novel-technologies-to.jpg" alt="3D Chip Stacking"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/want-a-smart-factory-its-all-about-the-data/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Smart Factories Need Intelligent Components</strong><br>At the MES &amp; Industry 4.0 conference, industry leaders discussed the pivotal role of data in the evolution of smart factories. Key insights highlighted that achieving data integrity is critical for manufacturing efficiency. Notable advancements in AI integration into manufacturing execution systems (MES) were presented, demonstrating the trend towards intelligent factories capable of real-time data-driven decision-making.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Porto-MESI-Industry-4-0-Infineon_image_sq_Nitin-Dahad.jpg" alt="Smart Factory Data"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/machine-intelligence-on-wireless-edge-networks-with-rf-analog-architecture-mit-duke/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Machine Intelligence on Wireless Edge Networks with RF Analog Architecture</strong><br>A groundbreaking study from MIT and Duke University introduces MIWEN, an RF analog architecture that facilitates deep neural network inference on power-constrained edge devices. By eliminating local weight memory, this innovation significantly reduces energy consumption and enhances real-time inference capabilities in low-power environments, paving the way for more efficient edge computing solutions.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_184389409-06-19-24-scaled.jpeg" alt="RF Analog Architecture"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/sambanova-shifts-to-inference-but-leaves-cloud-to-customers/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>SambaNova Shifts To Inference, Courts Cloud Customers</strong><br>In an exclusive interview, SambaNova’s CEO Rodrigo Liang discussed the company’s strategic pivot towards inference workloads amidst a shifting market landscape. With a focus on open-source models and a robust cloud deployment strategy, SambaNova aims to support enterprises in leveraging AI for enhanced operational efficiency. Liang emphasized the importance of customization in AI models to deliver superior value and performance.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/SambaNova-SoftBank-1.jpg" alt="SambaNova"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates as we continue to bring you the latest in semiconductor innovations and trends!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eetimes.com/stmicro-advances-piezomems-development-in</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="MEMS" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/MEMS/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Novel Technologies to Advance Next</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250623_Novel-Technologies-to-Advance-Next/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250623_Novel-Technologies-to-Advance-Next/</id>
    <published>2025-06-22T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-06-22T22:22:49.739Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/novel-technologies-to-advance-next-generation-semiconductor-packaging/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Novel Technologies to Advance Next</strong><br>A team of researchers from the Institute of Science Tokyo has unveiled a groundbreaking power supply technology for 3D-integrated chips called BBCube™, aimed at high-performance computing applications. This innovation leverages a three-dimensionally stacked architecture, enabling high memory bandwidth and low power consumption. Their findings were shared at the recent IEEE Electronic Components and Technology Conference, showcasing advancements in chip integration through novel bonding techniques and adhesive materials.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="Novel Technologies"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-services/aion-silicon/356734-the-sondrel-transformation-to-aion-silicon/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>The Sondrel transformation to Aion Silicon!</strong><br>Sondrel has rebranded itself as Aion Silicon, signifying a strategic pivot towards high-performance AI-centric silicon solutions. The company is expanding its service offerings to include tighter program management and architectural assistance, focusing on sectors such as data-center AI and automotive ADAS. CEO Oliver Jones emphasizes a commitment to becoming a leading design partner in custom silicon, enhancing their capacity to meet the evolving demands of the semiconductor market.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/1747740149443.jpg" alt="Aion Silicon"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/techcet-predicts-semiconductor-ald-cvd-precursor-market-outlook-highlights-growth/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>TECHCET Predicts Semiconductor ALD&#x2F;CVD Precursor Market Outlook, Highlights Growth</strong><br>According to TECHCET’s report, the global semiconductor precursor market is set to grow at a CAGR of 10.4% through 2029, driven by advancements in sub-3nm logic and increasing demands in AI and high-performance computing. In 2024, the market is anticipated to rebound to $1.7 billion, showcasing a significant recovery in NAND and DRAM sectors and emphasizing the importance of sustainability in procurement practices.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/image1.png" alt="Market Outlook"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-06-3d-chip-stacking-method-traditional.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>3D chip stacking method created to overcome traditional semiconductor limitations</strong><br>Researchers from the Institute of Science Tokyo have developed an innovative 3D chip stacking method that addresses conventional semiconductor limitations. This method enhances power integrity and reduces energy requirements for data transmission, showcasing significant advancements in chip integration technologies that could transform future computing architectures.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/novel-technologies-to.jpg" alt="3D Chip Stacking"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/want-a-smart-factory-its-all-about-the-data/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Want A Smart Factory? It’s All About the Data</strong><br>At the recent MES &amp; Industry 4.0 conference, industry leaders emphasized the critical role of data in achieving smart manufacturing. Insights from executives at Infineon and other major players highlighted the importance of data integrity and real-time decision-making facilitated by AI. The conference showcased how advanced manufacturing execution systems (MES) are evolving to become more intelligent, ultimately driving efficiency across semiconductor manufacturing processes.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Porto-MESI-Industry-4-0-Infineon_image_sq_Nitin-Dahad.jpg" alt="Smart Factory"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates and insights in the world of semiconductors as we continue to explore innovations and market trends shaping the industry.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/novel-technologies-to-advanc</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/technology/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductor/"/>
    
    <category term="smart manufacturing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/smart-manufacturing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>EUV Tech Debuts Enhanced FALCON Photoresist Flood Exposure Tool</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250618_EUV-Tech-Debuts-Enhanced-FALCON-Photoresist-Flood-Exposure-Tool/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250618_EUV-Tech-Debuts-Enhanced-FALCON-Photoresist-Flood-Exposure-Tool/</id>
    <published>2025-06-17T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-06-17T22:19:48.714Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.trendforce.com/news/2024/12/16/news-chinas-photoresist-breaking-through-and-advancing/">News</a></h2><p><strong>China’s Photoresist: Breaking Through and Advancing</strong><br>The global semiconductor industry is witnessing significant advancements, particularly in China, where local enterprises are achieving milestones in photoresist production. Hubei Dinglong has secured orders for its advanced ArF and KrF photoresists, while Shenzhen Rongda has received approval for a RMB 244 million private placement to enhance its R&amp;D capabilities. The government’s support further accelerates the industry’s rapid development amid increasing domestic demand for semiconductor materials.</p><p><img src="https://img.trendforce.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/13074350/Dinglong-624x374.jpg" alt="Hubei Dinglong"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.trendforce.com/news/2024/10/21/news-chinas-domestic-photoresist-successfully-validated/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>China’s Domestic Photoresist Successfully Validated!</strong><br>Wuhan Taiziwei Optoelectronics has launched the T150 A photoresist, achieving mass production validation. This product, designed to compete with international standards, showcases extreme resolution capabilities and improved process tolerance. This breakthrough signifies a potential shift in China’s reliance on foreign photoresists, as domestic production ramps up in response to growing demand.</p><p><img src="https://img.trendforce.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/18175709/Fujifilm-Electronic-Materials-photoresist1.jpg" alt="Fujifilm Electronic Materials"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.trendforce.com/news/2024/11/28/news-samsung-cuts-photoresist-usage-in-3d-nand-production-boosting-cost-efficiency/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Samsung Cuts Photoresist Usage in 3D NAND Production, Boosting Cost Efficiency</strong><br>Samsung has halved its photoresist usage in 3D NAND production, optimizing manufacturing processes to improve cost efficiency. This change demonstrates significant advancements in semiconductor manufacturing techniques, particularly in enhancing the layering process of NAND flash chips while maintaining high efficiency.</p><p><img src="https://img.trendforce.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/20132248/samsung-logo-624x468.jpg" alt="Samsung Logo"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/euv-tech-debuts-enhanced-falcon-photoresist-flood-exposure-tool/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>EUV Tech Debuts Enhanced FALCON Photoresist Flood Exposure Tool</strong><br>EUV Tech has introduced the FALCON tool, a next-generation device for characterizing and diagnosing EUV resists. This fully automated system allows for rapid testing and provides critical insights into exposure mechanisms, facilitating advanced photoresist development. Its capabilities include high-throughput analysis and a range of diagnostic modules, enhancing research productivity in the semiconductor field.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/FalconMachinewLogo-scaled.jpg" alt="FALCON Tool"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.trendforce.com/news/2024/11/28/news-samsung-cuts-photoresist-usage-in-3d-nand-production-boosting-cost-efficiency/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Samsung’s Strategic Process Optimization</strong><br>An interview with Samsung’s production team reveals insights into their recent optimization strategies in 3D NAND manufacturing. By reducing photoresist usage and enhancing coating conditions, Samsung aims to lead in cost efficiency and production capabilities, setting a benchmark for the industry amid rising competition and demand for advanced memory solutions.</p><p><img src="https://img.trendforce.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/20132248/samsung-logo-624x468.jpg" alt="Samsung Production"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for our next edition where we will continue to bring you the latest and most relevant updates in the semiconductor industry!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.trendforce.com/news/2024/12/16/news-chinas-photoresis</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Lithography/"/>
    
    
    <category term="technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/technology/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductor/"/>
    
    <category term="EUV" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/EUV/"/>
    
    <category term="photoresist" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/photoresist/"/>
    
    <category term="China" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/China/"/>
    
    <category term="Samsung" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Samsung/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Photonic Processor Could Streamline 6G Wireless Signal Processing</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250617_Photonic-Processor-Could-Streamline-6G-Wireless-Signal-Processing/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250617_Photonic-Processor-Could-Streamline-6G-Wireless-Signal-Processing/</id>
    <published>2025-06-16T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-06-16T22:20:54.767Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/microns-200-billion-plan-to-reshore-u-s-production-faces-challenges/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Micron’s $200 Billion Plan to Reshore U.S. Production Faces Challenges</strong><br>Micron’s ambitious plan to invest $200 billion in reshoring memory chip production in the U.S. is met with skepticism from analysts. The company aims to enhance domestic manufacturing capabilities to produce 40% of its DRAM in the U.S. However, challenges such as lack of local expertise and stiff competition from other chipmakers could hinder success.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Micron-art.png" alt="Micron&#39;s investment plan"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/encharge-picks-the-pc-for-its-first-analog-ai-chip/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>EnCharge Picks The PC For Its First Analog AI Chip</strong><br>Analog AI startup EnCharge has launched its first product, the EN100 AI accelerator, designed for laptops and workstations. Utilizing innovative capacitor-based analog compute-in-memory technology, the chip achieves an impressive power efficiency of over 40 TOPS&#x2F;W, addressing the significant energy demands of AI workloads.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/EnChargeAI_PCI-E-sq.jpg" alt="EnCharge AI Accelerator"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-06-photonic-processor-6g-wireless.html">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Photonic Processor Could Streamline 6G Wireless Signal Processing</strong><br>Researchers at MIT have developed an optical hardware accelerator that classifies wireless signals with unprecedented speed. This photonic chip processes data at light speed, achieving significant improvements over traditional digital accelerators, making it pivotal for future 6G applications.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2024/cloud-computing.jpg" alt="Photonic processor"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-06-brain-chips-boosting-cybercrime.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Brain-like Chips are Boosting Computers and Battling Cybercrime</strong><br>Researchers are developing brain-inspired chips capable of performing AI calculations locally, enhancing the security of IoT devices against cyber threats. These ultra-fast, energy-efficient chips are poised to revolutionize smart device security by processing data on-device rather than relying on cloud computing.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2019/5-brain.jpg" alt="Brain-like chips"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/eda/silvaco/356779-silvaco-at-the-2025-design-automation-conference/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Silvaco at the 2025 Design Automation Conference</strong><br>Silvaco is showcasing innovative EDA tools and semiconductor IP at DAC 2025. The company emphasizes its advancements in analog custom IC design, aimed at improving AI and efficiency across various applications. Attendees can engage in technical presentations and interactive sessions to explore cutting-edge developments.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/62nd-DAC-SemiWiki-6.jpg" alt="Silvaco at DAC"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates as we continue to track the latest advancements in the semiconductor industry!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eetimes.com/microns-200-billion-plan-to-reshore-u-s-p</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Global Semiconductor Sales Increase 2.5% Month</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250616_Global-Semiconductor-Sales-Increase-2.5%-Month/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250616_Global-Semiconductor-Sales-Increase-2.5%-Month/</id>
    <published>2025-06-15T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-06-15T22:22:23.302Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/global-semiconductor-sales-increase-2-5-month-to-month-in-april/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Global Semiconductor Sales Increase 2.5% Month</strong><br>The Semiconductor Industry Association (SIA) reported that global semiconductor sales reached $57.0 billion in April 2025, marking a 2.5% increase from March and a 22.7% year-over-year growth. The rise is attributed to heightened demand across the Americas and Asia Pacific, driven by AI technologies and advanced consumer electronics. Forecasts indicate a projected annual growth rate of 11.2%, reaching $700.9 billion by year-end.</p><p>![SIA Sales Graph](<a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Screenshot-2025-06-13-at-10.44.08">https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Screenshot-2025-06-13-at-10.44.08</a> AM.png)</p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/encharge-picks-the-pc-for-its-first-analog-ai-chip/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>EnCharge Picks The PC For Its First Analog AI Chip</strong><br>EnCharge AI has launched its first product, the EN100 AI accelerator, designed for client devices such as laptops and workstations. This analog AI accelerator utilizes capacitor-based compute-in-memory technology, achieving a power efficiency of over 40 TOPS&#x2F;W, and aims to meet the increasing demand for efficient AI processing.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/EnChargeAI_PCI-E-sq.jpg" alt="EnCharge AI Accelerator"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/eda/amiq-eda/356722-amiq-eda-at-the-2025-design-automation-conference/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>AMIQ EDA Unveils New AI Assistant for Design Tools</strong><br>AMIQ EDA’s latest enhancements to their Design and Verification Tools IDE family include an AI Assistant feature aimed at simplifying code generation and modification. The IDE now incorporates over 30 new code checks and improved testbench elaboration, ensuring higher code quality. This marks a significant advancement in hardware design, showcasing the integration of AI into development tools.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/62nd-DAC-SemiWiki-6.jpg" alt="AMIQ EDA"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/creating-the-building-blocks-of-technology-multiple-rings-at-a-time/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Creating the Building Blocks of Technology, Multiple Rings at a Time</strong><br>A team from Nagoya University has developed a new technique for synthesizing complex polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) used in organic electronics. This method utilizes direct carbon-to-carbon bond formation, vastly improving efficiency and reducing costs in creating essential components for LEDs and solar cells, with implications for enhancing semiconductor device production.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="Research on PAHs"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ip/agile-analog/356586-ceo-interview-with-krishna-anne-of-agile-analog/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Krishna Anne of Agile Analog</strong><br>In a recent interview, Krishna Anne discussed Agile Analog’s innovative approach to combat the analog engineer shortage through automation in mixed-signal IP design. He emphasized the company’s focus on strategic partnerships and integrated solutions, highlighting their potential to simplify and expedite analog design processes, thus addressing a critical industry challenge.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Agile-Analog-Krishna-Anne-headshot-photo.png" alt="Krishna Anne"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates and insights from the semiconductor industry as we continue to track trends, innovations, and breakthroughs shaping the future!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/global-semiconductor-sales-i</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="Growth" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Growth/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor Design" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor-Design/"/>
    
    <category term="EDA" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/EDA/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>New AI-Driven Semiconductor Platform Launched</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250611_New-AI-Driven-Semiconductor-Platform-Launched/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250611_New-AI-Driven-Semiconductor-Platform-Launched/</id>
    <published>2025-06-10T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T10:25:57.377Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/determinants-of-bond-wave-speed-in-wafer-bonding-yokohama-tel/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Determinants Of Bond Wave Speed In Wafer Bonding</strong><br>A recent study conducted by researchers from Yokohama National University and Tokyo Electron Kyushu Limited explores the critical factors influencing bond wave speed in wafer bonding. This research is pivotal for advancing 3D architectures used in logic, memory, and CMOS image sensors, emphasizing the importance of minimizing wafer distortion for precise subsequent processes. The study highlights that while plasma activation enhances bond wave speed through increased Si–OH groups on the surface, excessive high-power plasma can negatively affect speed due to adsorbed water. </p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_482095378-08-06-24.jpeg" alt="Wafer Bonding"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="http://www.semiconductor-today.com/news_items/2025/june/semiconductors-110625.shtml">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>New AI-Driven Semiconductor Platform Launched</strong><br>A leading semiconductor company has unveiled a groundbreaking AI-driven semiconductor design platform that promises to optimize chip performance and reduce time-to-market. This innovative platform utilizes machine learning algorithms to predict performance outcomes based on design parameters, significantly enhancing development efficiency for engineers. </p><p><img src="http://www.semiconductor-today.com/images/semiconductors/ai_platform.jpg" alt="AI Semiconductor Platform"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.icinsights.com/news/bulletins/2025-ic-market-forecast/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>2025 IC Market Forecast: Growth Projections</strong><br>According to the latest report by IC Insights, the global integrated circuit (IC) market is projected to grow by 10% in 2025, driven by increased demand for AI and IoT applications. The report includes detailed charts depicting market share across various segments, illustrating significant growth in memory and logic devices.</p><p><img src="https://www.icinsights.com/images/charts/ic_market_growth_2025.jpg" alt="IC Market Growth"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250611103602.htm">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Innovative Research on Quantum Dots for Enhanced Semiconductor Functionality</strong><br>A recent publication details the development of quantum dot technology that could revolutionize semiconductor applications. Researchers have identified methods to improve the efficiency of quantum dots, making them viable for next-generation devices. This breakthrough has the potential to significantly reduce power consumption in various applications.</p><p><img src="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/quantum_dots_research.jpg" alt="Quantum Dots Research"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbestechcouncil/2025/06/11/the-future-of-semiconductor-innovation/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>The Future of Semiconductor Innovation: Insights from Industry Leaders</strong><br>In a recent interview, industry leaders discussed the transformative trends shaping the semiconductor landscape. They emphasized the importance of collaboration across sectors to address supply chain challenges and the need for sustainable practices to future-proof the industry. Their insights shed light on how strategic innovations can drive growth and resilience in the semiconductor market.</p><p><img src="https://www.forbes.com/images/industry_leaders.jpg" alt="Industry Leaders Insight"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates and insights on semiconductor advancements as we continue to explore the latest trends and breakthroughs in the industry!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://semiengineering.com/determinants-of-bond-wave-speed-in-wa</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Lithography/"/>
    
    
    <category term="wafer bonding" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/wafer-bonding/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductor research" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductor-research/"/>
    
    <category term="3D architectures" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/3D-architectures/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Aware Programming in ReRAM- Evaluating and Optimizing Write Termination</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250603_Aware-Programming-in-ReRAM--Evaluating-and-Optimizing-Write-Termination/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250603_Aware-Programming-in-ReRAM--Evaluating-and-Optimizing-Write-Termination/</id>
    <published>2025-06-02T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-06-03T14:04:40.819Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/nxps-edge-llm-strategy-kinara-rag-agents/">News</a></h2><p><strong>NXP’s Edge LLM Strategy: Kinara, RAG, Agents</strong><br>NXP has unveiled its strategy for enabling large language model (LLM) inference on edge devices at the Embedded Vision Summit 2025. The company announced the acquisition of AI accelerator startup Kinara, whose Ara-2 chip enhances LLM performance. With the introduction of GenAI Flow, NXP aims to optimize edge applications by integrating RAG techniques to provide contextual awareness to LLMs, crucial for sectors like automotive and healthcare.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/industrial.jpg" alt="NXP Edge LLM Strategy"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/news-highlights-from-embedded-vision-summit-2025/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>News Highlights from Embedded Vision Summit 2025</strong><br>The Embedded Vision Summit showcased numerous advancements in edge AI technologies. MemryX was awarded for its MX3 M.2 AI accelerator module, which combines ease of use with efficient performance. Nota AI demonstrated its collaboration with Qualcomm, revealing its enhanced AI model optimization platform. SiMa.ai and Wind River introduced a powerful integrated edge AI solution, while Vision Components presented a modular MIPI bricks system for embedded vision applications.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/embedded-vision-summit-featured-image-speaker_source_embedded-vision-summit.jpg" alt="Embedded Vision Summit Highlights"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ip/weebit-nano/356372-relaxation-aware-programming-in-reram-evaluating-and-optimizing-write-termination/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Aware Programming in ReRAM: Evaluating and Optimizing Write Termination</strong><br>The research highlights the advancements in Resistive RAM (ReRAM) technology, particularly in managing conductance drift through voltage overdrive techniques. This method stabilizes memory performance while maintaining energy efficiency, showcasing potential improvements in neuromorphic computing applications. The findings illustrate the balance between energy consumption and stability, crucial for future memory technologies.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Im1_Weebit-Relaxation-Aware-Programming-in-ReRAM-Optimizing-Write-Termination-RRAM-1024x704.png" alt="ReRAM Performance Chart"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/roadmap-for-ai-hw-development-with-the-role-of-photonic-chips-in-supporting-future-llms-cuhk-nus-uiuc-berkeley/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Roadmap for AI HW Development, With The Role of Photonic Chips In Supporting Future LLMs</strong><br>A collaborative research paper explores the future of AI computing hardware, emphasizing the role of photonic chips in supporting next-generation large language models (LLMs). The paper outlines the need for innovative computing paradigms, including integrated photonic neural networks and neuromorphic devices, to meet the growing demands of AI models, which are projected to require significant power resources.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_482095378-08-06-24.jpeg?fit=1200,672&ssl=1" alt="Photonic Chips in AI Hardware"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/eda/breker-verification-systems/356315-breker-verification-systems-at-the-2025-design-automation-conference/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Breker Verification Systems at the 2025 Design Automation Conference</strong><br>Breker Verification Systems showcased its Synthesis and SystemVIP library at DAC 2025, emphasizing the need for advanced verification methodologies in semiconductor design. The solutions presented focus on enhancing verification coverage for complex applications, including AI accelerators and RISC-V cores. Breker’s AI-driven test suite synthesis aims to streamline the testing process, crucial for developing robust semiconductor solutions.</p><p><img src="/opensemi/nan" alt="DAC 2025 Demonstrations"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates and insights from the semiconductor industry as we continue to track innovations and advancements shaping the future of technology.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eetimes.com/nxps-edge-llm-strategy-kinara-rag-agents/</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="photonics" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/photonics/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="memory technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/memory-technology/"/>
    
    <category term="edge computing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/edge-computing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>VLSI Technology Symposium – Intel Describes i3 Process</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250601_VLSI-Technology-Symposium-%E2%80%93-Intel-Describes-i3-Process/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250601_VLSI-Technology-Symposium-%E2%80%93-Intel-Describes-i3-Process/</id>
    <published>2025-05-31T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-06-01T04:03:39.685Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/middle-east-expects-ai-gains-from-u-s-deals/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Middle East Expects AI Gains from U.S. Deals</strong><br>The Middle East is witnessing a surge in technological investments, particularly in AI, fueled by significant deals announced during U.S. President Biden’s recent tour. Major commitments include $600 billion from Saudi Arabia and $200 billion in new U.S.-UAE agreements, aimed primarily at establishing robust data center infrastructures to support burgeoning AI demands. Notably, the region is also cultivating a semiconductor ecosystem, with fabless design houses and initiatives like the HUMAIN project in Saudi Arabia seeking to enhance local capabilities. </p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/President-Trump-Saudi-US-investment-forum_source_-The-White-House.jpg" alt="Middle East Tech Investments"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-05-supercomputer-nobel-laureate-jennifer-doudna.html">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>U.S. Supercomputer Named After Nobel Laureate Jennifer Doudna to Power AI and Scientific Research</strong><br>A new supercomputer, named after Nobel Prize winner Jennifer Doudna, is set to enhance AI research and genomic studies at the Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory. Scheduled to go live next year, this groundbreaking system aims to bolster the capabilities of AI technologies and scientific discoveries, marking a significant investment in advanced computing resources to address critical research challenges.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/us-supercomputer-named.jpg" alt="Supercomputer Development"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-services/349292-5-expectations-for-the-memory-markets-in-2025/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>5 Expectations for the Memory Markets in 2025</strong><br>TechInsights anticipates substantial growth in the memory markets, primarily driven by AI technologies. A notable focus is on High-Bandwidth Memory (HBM), with shipments projected to grow by 70% year-over-year, significantly reshaping the DRAM landscape. The report illustrates key trends affecting memory demand, including the rise of AI workloads and capital expenditure shifts towards DRAM production, emphasizing the intertwined evolution of memory and semiconductor technologies.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Expectations-for-the-Memory-Markets-in-2025-1200x675.jpg" alt="Memory Market Trends"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/3dic/356342-synopsys-addresses-the-test-barrier-for-heterogeneous-integration/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Synopsys Addresses the Test Barrier for Heterogeneous Integration</strong><br>Synopsys has unveiled advanced methodologies to tackle the complexities of heterogeneous chip designs, essential for next-gen AI and HPC applications. Their innovative High-Speed Test GPIOs (HSGPIO) allow efficient testing of chiplets while maintaining signal integrity. This research addresses the critical need for high-bandwidth interfaces in multi-die packaging, positioning Synopsys at the forefront of enhancing heterogeneous integration in semiconductor design.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Synopsys-Addresses-the-Test-Barrier-for-Heterogeneous-Integration.jpg" alt="Heterogeneous Integration Testing"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-manufacturers/intel/346992-vlsi-technology-symposium-intel-describes-i3-process-how-does-it-measure-up/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>VLSI Technology Symposium – Intel Describes i3 Process</strong><br>At the recent VLSI Technology Symposium, Intel detailed its upcoming i3 process, which promises to achieve an impressive transistor density of 148 million transistors per millimeter squared. This advancement is set to enhance performance across various applications, including AI and high-performance computing. Intel’s proactive approach in refining its processes illustrates the company’s commitment to leading in competitive foundry technologies and adapting to evolving market demands.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Figure-1-1200x675.jpg" alt="Intel i3 Process"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates on the latest advancements in the semiconductor industry as we continue to monitor these transformative trends and technologies.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eetimes.com/middle-east-expects-ai-gains-from-u-s-dea</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="market trends" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/market-trends/"/>
    
    <category term="technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/technology/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>World&#39;s Lowest Write Power Operation for High-Speed SOT-MRAM Cell Achieved</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250531_World&#39;s-Lowest-Write-Power-Operation-for-High-Speed-SOT-MRAM-Cell-Achieved/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250531_World&#39;s-Lowest-Write-Power-Operation-for-High-Speed-SOT-MRAM-Cell-Achieved/</id>
    <published>2025-05-30T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-05-31T11:59:05.939Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/supply-chain-uncertainty-hits-canadas-chip-sector/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Supply Chain Uncertainty Hits Canada’s Chip Sector</strong><br>Canada’s semiconductor industry faces significant challenges within a complex global supply chain. Experts at the CHIPS NORTH Executive Summit discussed maintaining manufacturing capabilities and the importance of flexibility in supplier networks. Recent investments by the Canadian government aim to bolster chip packaging capacities, while industry leaders emphasize the necessity of adapting to both technological and geopolitical disruptions.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/chipsnorthsupplychain-covercarousel.jpg" alt="Supply Chain"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/indian-startup-engineers-economical-evtols/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Indian Startup Engineers Economical eVTOLs</strong><br>The Indian startup ePlane Co. is pioneering electric vertical take-off and landing (eVTOL) aircraft, focusing on efficient, compact designs for urban transport. With its unique architecture promising reduced costs and the ability to operate from rooftops, ePlane aims to address the limitations of current battery technology while preparing for certification and commercial launches by 2027.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_647367286.jpeg" alt="eVTOL"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-05-world-lowest-power-high-sot.html">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>World’s Lowest Write Power Operation for High-Speed SOT-MRAM Cell Achieved</strong><br>Researchers at Tohoku University have set a new record for the lowest write power in SOT-MRAM technology, achieving an energy efficiency of just 156 fJ. This advancement is expected to propel the use of SOT-MRAM in future high-performance electronic devices, providing a greener alternative to existing memory technologies.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2025/worlds-lowest-write-po.jpg" alt="SOT-MRAM"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-05-ai-chip-decentralized-cloud.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>AI Chip Developed for Decentralized Use Without the Cloud</strong><br>A neuromorphic AI chip from the Technical University of Munich operates without cloud connections, mimicking human brain functions for energy-efficient on-site calculations. This chip demonstrates significant advancements in processing efficiency, paving the way for customized AI solutions that enhance security and reduce reliance on cloud computing.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/ai-chip-developed-for-1.jpg" alt="AI Chip"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-05-scientists-vulnerability-intel-processors.html">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Computer Scientists Discover New Security Vulnerability in Intel Processors</strong><br>Researchers from ETH Zurich have identified a new class of vulnerabilities in Intel processors that exploit speculative execution to gain unauthorized access to data. This discovery raises concerns about data security in multi-user environments and highlights the need for robust security measures in future processor designs.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/researchers-discover-n-15.jpg" alt="Intel Vulnerability"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates and insights from the semiconductor industry as we continue to monitor these exciting developments and challenges.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eetimes.com/supply-chain-uncertainty-hits-canadas-chi</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="chip design" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/chip-design/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="supply chain" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/supply-chain/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Resist Loss Model for the EUV Stochastic Defectivity Cliffs</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250530_Resist-Loss-Model-for-the-EUV-Stochastic-Defectivity-Cliffs/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250530_Resist-Loss-Model-for-the-EUV-Stochastic-Defectivity-Cliffs/</id>
    <published>2025-05-29T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-05-31T07:17:11.042Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2023-11-photoresist-materials-pave-smaller-high.html">News</a></h2><p><strong>Innovative photoresist materials pave the way for smaller, high performance semiconductor chips</strong><br>Researchers at the Center for Functional Nanomaterials have developed a new hybrid photoresist material that enhances patterning for extreme ultraviolet (EUV) lithography. This advancement is crucial as the industry approaches the challenge of producing chips with features just a few nanometers in size. The new material combines organic and inorganic components to improve sensitivity, allowing for faster and more efficient chip manufacturing.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2023/a-bright-future-for-ex.jpg" alt="Innovative Materials"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/lam-research-establishes-28nm-pitch-in-high-resolution-patterning-through-dry-photoresist-technology/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Lam Research Unveils Dry Photoresist Technology for Advanced Logic</strong><br>Lam Research’s new dry photoresist technology has been officially qualified for direct-print 28nm pitch back end of line (BEOL) logic at 2nm and below by imec. This technology promises to enhance resolution and yield while reducing costs and raw material usage in semiconductor manufacturing.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="Lam Research"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/2024-photoresist-market-forecasted-to-rise/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>2024 Photoresist Market Forecasted to Rise</strong><br>The photoresist market is expected to rebound in 2024, with a projected growth of 7% to reach $2.57 billion. This growth is driven by the increasing demand for EUV and KrF products, essential for the latest semiconductor technologies. The report highlights significant trends in the market, including the shift towards negative tone EUV photoresists.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/image1.png" alt="Market Trends"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/lithography/352503-resist-loss-model-for-the-euv-stochastic-defectivity-cliffs/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Resist Loss Model for the EUV Stochastic Defectivity Cliffs</strong><br>A new research paper explores stochastic defectivity in EUV lithography, proposing a model to address resist loss issues that affect yield and pattern fidelity. This study aims to enhance the reliability of EUV processes in semiconductor manufacturing and is crucial for future technology nodes.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Exposing-EUV-1.png" alt="EUV Research"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ceo-interviews/353829-ceo-interview-with-dinesh-bettadapur-of-irresistible-materials/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Dinesh Bettadapur of Irresistible Materials</strong><br>In an insightful interview, Dinesh Bettadapur discusses the challenges and innovations in the semiconductor materials sector, focusing on the importance of advanced photoresist solutions in meeting industry demands. He emphasizes the role of collaboration and innovation in driving the next wave of semiconductor advancements.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/D.-Bettadapur_photo_IM-960x1200.jpg" alt="Dinesh Bettadapur"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for the latest updates and breakthroughs in the semiconductor industry as we continue to bring you valuable insights and news.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techxplore.com/news/2023-11-photoresist-materials-pave-sm</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Lithography/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Market Trends" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Market-Trends/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor Technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor-Technology/"/>
    
    <category term="EUV Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/EUV-Lithography/"/>
    
    <category term="Photoresists" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Photoresists/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Demonstration Of EUV Scatterometry On A 2D Periodic Interconnect</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250528_Demonstration-Of-EUV-Scatterometry-On-A-2D-Periodic-Interconnect/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250528_Demonstration-Of-EUV-Scatterometry-On-A-2D-Periodic-Interconnect/</id>
    <published>2025-05-27T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-05-31T10:26:58.411Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://spie.org/news/other-lithography-approaches-offer-alternatives">News</a></h2><p><strong>Other lithography approaches offer alternatives</strong><br>At the 2025 SPIE Advanced Lithography + Patterning conference, semiconductor manufacturers are exploring alternative lithography methods to enhance performance and reduce costs. Notable presentations included Micron Technology’s Tomohiro Iwaki discussing challenges in nanoimprint technology and Intel’s Florian Gstrein highlighting directed self-assembly techniques. These innovations aim to improve defect rates and boost yields, particularly relevant for logic and memory chips.</p><p><img src="https://spie.org/images/Graphics/Newsroom/2025articles/AL25_Nanoimprint_920.jpg" alt="Nanoimprint Technology"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://spie.org/news/getting-pfas-out-of-lithography-materials">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Getting PFAS out of lithography materials</strong><br>Central Glass Co. is pioneering PFAS-free materials for 193-nm immersion lithography, addressing long-term environmental and health concerns associated with traditional photoresist components. Their new formulations, which include a PFAS-free photo acid generator and immersion barrier polymer, have shown promising results in maintaining performance while reducing harmful substances.</p><p><img src="https://spie.org/images/Graphics/Newsroom/2025articles/AL25_PFAS_Litho_920.jpg" alt="PFAS-Free Materials"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://spie.org/news/chips-and-lithography-head-up-and-down">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Chips – and lithography – head up and down</strong><br>The latest insights from the 2025 SPIE conference emphasized the shift towards 3D semiconductor architectures to overcome scaling limitations. Presentations discussed how backside power delivery can alleviate power bottlenecks, enabling denser and more efficient chip designs. This transition is pivotal for sustaining Moore’s Law in an era of complex circuitry.</p><p><img src="https://spie.org/images/Graphics/Newsroom/2025articles/AL25_Backside%20Patterning_920.jpg" alt="3D Chip Design"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/demonstration-of-euv-scatterometry-on-a-2d-periodic-interconnect/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Demonstration Of EUV Scatterometry On A 2D Periodic Interconnect</strong><br>A research collaboration involving the University of Colorado, NIST, and Samsung has revealed advancements in EUV scatterometry, a metrology technique vital for measuring periodic nanostructured materials. The study demonstrates enhanced sensitivity and the potential for deep sub-nanometer precision, marking a significant step forward for semiconductor manufacturing.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_517438105-04-16-24.jpeg" alt="EUV Scatterometry"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.tel.com/news/topics/2025/20250526_001.html">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Tokyo Electron Receives Renewal of DX-certified Business Operator Status from the Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry</strong><br>Tokyo Electron’s recent renewal of its DX-certified Business Operator status marks a significant achievement in its digital transformation initiatives. This renewed status emphasizes TEL’s commitment to leveraging digital technologies to enhance corporate value and adapt to the rapidly evolving semiconductor market, which is projected to approach $1 trillion by 2030.</p><p><img src="https://www.tel.com/news/topics/2025/ms68nt00000000dt-img/ms68nt00000000fu.png" alt="Digital Transformation"></p><hr><p>Thank you for staying with us for the latest news in the semiconductor industry. We look forward to bringing you more updates on innovations and advancements in lithography and sustainability efforts.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://spie.org/news/other-lithography-approaches-offer-alternat</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Lithography/"/>
    
    
    <category term="EUV" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/EUV/"/>
    
    <category term="Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Lithography/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor Sustainability" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor-Sustainability/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CEO Interview with Mohan Iyer, Vice President and General Manager, Semiconductor Business Unit at Thermo Fisher Scientific</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250526_CEO-Interview-with-Mohan-Iyer,-Vice-President-and-General-Manager,-Semiconductor-Business-Unit-at-Thermo-Fisher-Scientific/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250526_CEO-Interview-with-Mohan-Iyer,-Vice-President-and-General-Manager,-Semiconductor-Business-Unit-at-Thermo-Fisher-Scientific/</id>
    <published>2025-05-25T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-05-31T10:26:58.411Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/kla-invests-in-operations-in-wales-with-the-opening-of-a-138-million-rd-and-manufacturing-facility/">News</a></h2><p><strong>KLA Invests in Operations in Wales with the Opening of a $138 Million R&amp;D and Manufacturing Facility</strong><br>KLA Corporation has inaugurated a new $138 million R&amp;D and manufacturing facility in Newport, Wales, enhancing its product lines and capacity to meet the growing demand for advanced semiconductor technologies. The facility includes extensive R&amp;D clean rooms and manufacturing spaces, aiming to support innovations across sectors like AI, power devices, and photonics. This investment reaffirms KLA’s commitment to the region and the semiconductor industry’s future.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="KLA Facility"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/efficiency-upgrade-for-oled-screens-a-route-to-blue-pholed-longevity/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Efficiency Upgrade for OLED Screens: A Route to Blue PHOLED Longevity</strong><br>Researchers at the University of Michigan have developed a method to enhance the longevity of blue phosphorescent OLEDs, bringing them up to par with the more durable green counterparts. This innovation could revolutionize OLED technology, improving energy efficiency and display performance in smartphones and televisions by integrating advanced coatings that facilitate faster energy conversion.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="OLED Technology"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/canada-needs-a-multi-faceted-strategy-to-scale-chip-talent/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Faceted Strategy to Scale Chip Talent</strong><br>The Canadian semiconductor industry is facing a critical shortage of talent, with estimates indicating a need for 1.5 million engineers globally in the next few years. This landscape requires innovative workforce development strategies to attract and cultivate talent, as highlighted in discussions at the CHIPS NORTH Executive Summit. The need for an integrated approach between industry and academia is emphasized to address the skills gap.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/chipsnorthtalent-covercarousel.jpg" alt="Talent Strategy"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/rice-method-refines-ultrapure-diamond-film-fabrication-for-quantum-and-electronic-applications/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Rice Method Refines Ultrapure Diamond Film Fabrication for Quantum and Electronic Applications</strong><br>Researchers at Rice University have made significant advancements in diamond film fabrication, creating ultrapure layers suitable for quantum and electronic technologies without the need for high-temperature annealing. This streamlined method has the potential to enhance the quality and efficiency of diamond-based devices, paving the way for innovations in the semiconductor industry.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="Diamond Fabrication"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ceo-interviews/355982-executive-interview-with-mohan-iyer-vice-president-and-general-manager-semiconductor-business-unit-thermo-fisher-scientific/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Mohan Iyer, Vice President and General Manager, Semiconductor Business Unit at Thermo Fisher Scientific</strong><br>Mohan Iyer discusses Thermo Fisher’s commitment to advancing semiconductor manufacturing through innovative solutions in R&amp;D, yield management, and defect analysis. He emphasizes the importance of automated workflows and advanced metrology for enhancing manufacturing efficiency and product quality in a rapidly evolving industry.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/MohanPicWorkday_11302021-1042x1200.jpg" alt="Mohan Iyer"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates and insights from the semiconductor industry as we continue to explore the latest innovations and trends shaping the future of technology.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/kla-invests-in-operations-in</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/technology/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="investment" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/investment/"/>
    
    <category term="workforce" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/workforce/"/>
    
    <category term="quantum computing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/quantum-computing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>SEMI Reports Typical Q1 2025 Semiconductor Seasonality with Potential for Atypical Shifts Due to Tariff Uncertainty</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250521_SEMI-Reports-Typical-Q1-2025-Semiconductor-Seasonality-with-Potential-for-Atypical-Shifts-Due-to-Tariff-Uncertainty/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250521_SEMI-Reports-Typical-Q1-2025-Semiconductor-Seasonality-with-Potential-for-Atypical-Shifts-Due-to-Tariff-Uncertainty/</id>
    <published>2025-05-20T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-05-31T10:26:58.411Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-manufacturers/intel/355988-intel-foundry-is-a-low-risk-aternative-to-tsmc/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Intel Foundry is a Low Risk Alternative to TSMC</strong><br>Intel has positioned itself as a strategic alternative to TSMC in the foundry market, emphasizing a partnership approach and a focus on execution. CFO Dave Zinsner noted that while Intel’s 18A technology is not fully developed as a foundry process, the company aims to leverage its design and foundry services for competitive advantage. The foundry market is expected to be a critical growth area for Intel, with a breakeven target set for 2027.  </p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Dave-Zinsner-Foundry-Hat-SemiWIki.png" alt="Intel Foundry"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/cea-leti-reports-co-integration-of-gan-microled-and-organic-photodetectors-for-multifunctional-display-applications/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>CEA-Leti Reports Co-Integration of GaN MicroLED and Organic Photodetectors for Multifunctional Display Applications</strong><br>CEA-Leti has successfully demonstrated the co-integration of GaN microLED technology and organic photodetectors, paving the way for multifunctional display applications. This integration enables advanced functionalities such as fingerprint sensing and bio-monitoring, addressing the growing demand for interactive displays in consumer electronics.  </p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/image002.jpg" alt="GaN MicroLED"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/semi-reports-typical-q1-2025-semiconductor-seasonality-with-potential-for-atypical-shifts-due-to-tariff-uncertainty/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>SEMI Reports Typical Q1 2025 Semiconductor Seasonality with Potential for Atypical Shifts Due to Tariff Uncertainty</strong><br>SEMI’s Q1 2025 Semiconductor Manufacturing Monitor highlights typical seasonal patterns in semiconductor sales, while also noting potential disruptions caused by global trade policies. The report emphasizes a significant year-over-year increase in capital expenditures, especially in AI and high-performance computing sectors.  </p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/vcsPRAsset_3390533_117249_eb5bd3fd-0ad2-477b-9573-a0ec71ebcf78_0.png" alt="SEMI Report"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-05-positioning-microdevices-circularly-polarized-luminescence.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Self-Positioning Microdevices with Circularly Polarized Luminescence Enable Adaptable 3D Display</strong><br>Researchers have developed a novel 3D display technology utilizing circularly polarized luminescence, which allows for interactive manipulation through hand movements. This advancement could revolutionize human-computer interaction, significantly improving applications in medical and aerospace systems.  </p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2025/ustc-develops-self-pos.jpg" alt="3D Display"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-services/356050-alchips-technology-and-global-talent-strategy-deliver-record-growth/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Alchip’s Technology and Global Talent Strategy Deliver Record Growth</strong><br>Alchip Technologies is making strides in 2nm and 3nm technology advancements, with a focus on expanding its engineering resources globally. The company’s CEO Johnny Shen highlights the importance of innovative packaging solutions and the strategic shift towards locations like Taiwan and Southeast Asia to tap into local talent and enhance semiconductor capabilities.  </p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Alchip-TSMC-2nm-N2-1200x634.jpg" alt="Alchip Technology"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more insights and updates from the semiconductor industry as we continue to explore how innovation and strategic partnerships shape the future.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-manufacturers/intel/355988-int</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Lithography/"/>
    
    
    <category term="technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/technology/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="partnerships" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/partnerships/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Role of Molybdenum in Advanced Metallization</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250519_The-Role-of-Molybdenum-in-Advanced-Metallization/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250519_The-Role-of-Molybdenum-in-Advanced-Metallization/</id>
    <published>2025-05-18T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-05-31T10:26:58.411Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/ai-integration-photonics-edge-computing-and-sustainable-electronics-to-take-center-stage-at-27th-lid-world-summit/">News</a></h2><p><strong>AI Integration, Photonics, Edge Computing and Sustainable Electronics to Take Center Stage at 27th LID World Summit</strong><br>The upcoming LID World Summit 2025 will explore the foundational role of advanced semiconductors in enhancing AI capabilities, particularly in edge computing and data centers. With over 1,100 industry leaders and researchers expected, discussions will cover strategic technologies that address pressing challenges in mobility, healthcare, and low-carbon energy. The event aims to foster innovation and collaboration among stakeholders in the microelectronics sector.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="LID World Summit"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/blaize-q1-earnings-begins-transition-to-product-revenue/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Blaize Q1 Earnings: Begins Transition to Product Revenue</strong><br>Blaize has reported a significant 83% year-on-year revenue increase in Q1 2025, transitioning from consulting fees to product sales, primarily targeting smart city applications. The company’s GSP AI accelerator chip and AI Studio software platform are at the forefront of this shift, with ambitious revenue forecasts for the year indicating a strong pipeline of future opportunities in various sectors.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Blaizechip-sq_45986b.jpg" alt="Blaize AI Chip"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-05-racket-asian-semiconductor-giants-looming.html">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Asian Semiconductor Giants Fear Looming Tariffs</strong><br>Recent analyses indicate that impending tariffs on semiconductor imports could have dire consequences for South Korean and Taiwanese chipmakers. With exports to the U.S. reaching historic highs, stockpiling is now a common strategy among these companies as they brace for potential price increases and market instability.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2025/for-chipmaking-powerho.jpg" alt="Asian Semiconductor Exports"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://newsroom.lamresearch.com/molybdenum-metallization-enable-artificial-intelligence?blog=true">Research</a></h2><p><strong>The Role of Molybdenum in Advanced Metallization</strong><br>A new white paper highlights how molybdenum is becoming a critical enabler in semiconductor manufacturing. Its low resistance compared to traditional materials like tungsten supports the demands of next-generation chips, particularly in AI applications. Lam Research’s ALTUS® Halo tool is leading this innovation, showcasing the importance of advanced metallization processes in enhancing chip performance and energy efficiency.</p><p><img src="https://newsroom.lamresearch.com/image/Lam+Research+molybdenum+metallization.jpg" alt="Molybdenum Metallization"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ceo-interviews/355597-ceo-interview-with-sudhanshu-misra-of-chempower-corporation/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Sudhanshu Misra of ChEmpower Corporation</strong><br>Sudhanshu Misra discusses how ChEmpower is revolutionizing semiconductor manufacturing through its abrasive-free planarization technology. By enhancing sustainability and reducing defects, ChEmpower’s innovations are positioned to significantly impact the semiconductor market, especially as it addresses the challenges posed by the industry’s move towards advanced materials and technology nodes.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/sudhanshu.jpeg" alt="Sudhanshu Misra"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates as we continue to bring you the latest news and insights from the semiconductor industry. Your source for innovation and trends!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/ai-integration-photonics-edg</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor Manufacturing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor-Manufacturing/"/>
    
    <category term="Power Management" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Power-Management/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>NSR-S636E ArF Immersion Scanner</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250518_NSR-S636E-ArF-Immersion-Scanner/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250518_NSR-S636E-ArF-Immersion-Scanner/</id>
    <published>2025-05-17T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-05-31T10:26:58.395Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/high-na-euv">News</a></h2><p><strong>This Machine Could Keep Moore’s Law on Track</strong><br>ASML is pioneering high-numerical-aperture EUV lithography, aiming for commercial deployment in 2025. This advancement is crucial for maintaining Moore’s Law by enabling the production of increasingly smaller chip features, essential for next-generation devices.</p><p><img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-white-box-with-vertical-lines-dwarfs-two-people-in-white-coveralls.jpg?id=34683341&width=1200&height=899" alt="ASML lithography machine"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.nikonprecision.com/nikon-releases-nsr-s636e-arf-immersion-scanner/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>NSR-S636E ArF Immersion Scanner</strong><br>Nikon introduces its NSR-S636E ArF immersion scanner, the most productive lithography system in its history, designed for critical layers in semiconductor manufacturing. This system enhances overlay accuracy and throughput, catering to the needs of advanced 3D semiconductor devices.</p><p><img src="https://www.nikonprecision.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/NSR-S636E-Larger-ImageA-scaled-e1701819763953-1024x890.jpg" alt="Nikon NSR-S636E"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/transistor-density">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>The State of the Transistor in 3 Charts</strong><br>This article provides a comprehensive overview of the advancements in transistor technology over the past 75 years, emphasizing the exponential growth in transistor density and the ongoing miniaturization efforts critical for future semiconductor innovations.</p><p><img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-photo-of-3-different-transistors.png?id=32153247&width=1200&height=844" alt="Transistor advancements"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/scalable-approach-for-fabricating-sub-10nm-nanogaps/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Scalable Approach For Fabricating Sub-10nm Nanogaps</strong><br>Researchers have developed a progressive wafer-scale method for creating sub-10 nm nanogap structures, which promises significant advancements in semiconductor fabrication techniques, enhancing performance and scalability.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_416615461-01-29-25-scaled.jpeg" alt="Sub-10nm nanogaps"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://phys.org/news/2023-12/method-fabricate-optical-devices-specifications.html">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>A New Method to Fabricate Optical Devices That More Closely Match Their Design Specifications</strong><br>MIT and the Chinese University of Hong Kong researchers have developed a machine learning-based digital simulator for photolithography that significantly enhances the precision of optical device manufacturing, paving the way for improved performance in applications ranging from mobile cameras to telecommunications.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2023/method-enables-optical.jpg" alt="Optical device fabrication"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates as we continue to bring you the latest news and innovations in the semiconductor industry!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/high-na-euv&quot;&gt;News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Th</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Lithography/"/>
    
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductor/"/>
    
    <category term="lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/lithography/"/>
    
    <category term="EUV" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/EUV/"/>
    
    <category term="optics" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/optics/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Safeguard power domain compatibility by finding missing level shifters</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250518_Safeguard-power-domain-compatibility-by-finding-missing-level-shifters/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250518_Safeguard-power-domain-compatibility-by-finding-missing-level-shifters/</id>
    <published>2025-05-17T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-05-31T10:26:58.395Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/renesas-partners-with-indian-government-to-drive-innovation-through-startups-and-industry-academia-collaboration/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Renesas Partners with Indian Government to Drive Innovation Through Startups and Industry</strong><br>Renesas Electronics Corporation has announced a partnership with the Indian government aimed at supporting local startups and academic institutions in VLSI and embedded semiconductor systems. This initiative is part of Renesas’ broader strategy to deepen its market presence in India, with ambitious plans to generate over 10% of its global revenue from the region by 2030.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/unnamed.jpg" alt="Renesas Partnership"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/curvilinear-technology-a-game-changer-for-the-logic-technology-roadmap/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Curvilinear Technology: A Game Changer for the Logic Technology Roadmap</strong><br>Imec has introduced curvilinear design techniques in optical proximity correction (OPC) and mask writing, which promise to reduce errors and improve the process window for advanced semiconductor manufacturing. This innovative approach is expected to enhance chip performance while reducing costs in future semiconductor nodes.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Figure-8-Wafer-level-printing.jpg" alt="Curvilinear Technology"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/events/355791-webinar-achieving-seamless-1-6-tbps-interoperability-with-samtec-and-synopsys/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Achieving 1.6 Tbps Interoperability</strong><br>A recent webinar explored the critical role of 224G SerDes technology in achieving high-speed data transfers, essential for supporting AI workloads. The discussion highlighted the required interoperability testing and the evolving needs for system design in the semiconductor industry.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Webinar-Achieving-Seamless-1.6-Tbps-Interoperability-with-Samtec-and-Synopsys.png" alt="Webinar on Interoperability"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-05-strategy-fabricate-highly-thin-tin.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>A new strategy to fabricate highly performing thin-film tin perovskite transistors</strong><br>Researchers at Pohang University have developed a novel approach to create high-performance p-channel thin-film transistors using tin-halide perovskites. Their method utilizes vapor deposition techniques, achieving excellent mobility and stability, potentially paving the way for broader applications in semiconductor technology.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/a-new-strategy-to-fabr-1.jpg" alt="Tin Perovskite Transistors"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/eda/355809-safeguard-power-domain-compatibility-by-finding-missing-level-shifters/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Safeguard power domain compatibility by finding missing level shifters</strong><br>An insightful article discusses the critical role of level shifters in mixed signal design and their impact on signal integrity and device performance. With advanced EDA tools, designers can identify potential issues early in the design phase, ensuring reliable operation in integrated circuits.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/fig1-missing-level-shifters-1200x676.jpg" alt="Level Shifters"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates on the latest advancements and trends in the semiconductor industry!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/renesas-partners-with-indian</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/technology/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="manufacturing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/manufacturing/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Molybdenum – The Metal Enabling Next Big Leap In Chip Manufacturing for the AI Era</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250517_Molybdenum-%E2%80%93-The-Metal-Enabling-Next-Big-Leap-In-Chip-Manufacturing-for-the-AI-Era/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250517_Molybdenum-%E2%80%93-The-Metal-Enabling-Next-Big-Leap-In-Chip-Manufacturing-for-the-AI-Era/</id>
    <published>2025-05-16T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-05-31T10:26:58.395Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/uae-and-us-presidents-attend-the-unveiling-of-phase-1-of-new-5gw-ai-campus-in-abu-dhabi/">News</a></h2><p><strong>UAE and US Presidents Attend the Unveiling of Phase 1 of New 5GW AI Campus in Abu Dhabi</strong><br>A landmark 5GW AI campus has been inaugurated in Abu Dhabi, set to enhance regional computing capabilities and collaboration between UAE and US tech firms. This facility aims to provide AI data centers powered by nuclear, solar, and gas, ensuring sustainable operations while serving nearly half of the global population.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="UAE AI Campus"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/molybdenum-the-metal-enabling-next-big-leap-in-chip-manufacturing-for-the-ai-era/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Molybdenum – The Metal Enabling Next Big Leap In Chip Manufacturing for the AI Era</strong><br>The introduction of molybdenum in semiconductor manufacturing is set to revolutionize chip performance. With superior properties over tungsten, molybdenum allows for faster chips and more efficient production processes, crucial for the demands of AI applications.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/image005-1.png" alt="Molybdenum in Chip Manufacturing"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/canadas-chip-industry-charts-best-path-to-growth/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Canada’s Chip Industry Charts Best Path to Growth</strong><br>This article discusses the growth potential of Canada’s semiconductor industry, highlighting key factors such as the necessity for a unified strategy and support for both domestic and international companies. It emphasizes the importance of leveraging existing talent and resources to boost the sector.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/chipsnorth-growth_covercarousel.png" alt="Canada&#39;s Chip Industry"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-05-decades-white-key-drivers.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Study Maps Three Decades of White LED Progress and Key Innovation Drivers</strong><br>A comprehensive study by researchers at the University of Cambridge and ETH Zurich retraced three decades of advancements in white LED technology, revealing that while R&amp;D is crucial for energy efficiency improvements, cost reductions are largely driven by economies of scale and manufacturing process innovations.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/study-re-traces-the-pr.jpg" alt="LED Progress Study"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/automotive-industry-charts-new-course-with-risc-v/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Automotive Industry Charts New Course with RISC-V</strong><br>The European automotive sector is embracing RISC-V to support the shift towards software-defined vehicles and advanced autonomous systems. This open-standard architecture enhances flexibility and reduces the risk of vendor lock-in, addressing the growing demand for customized processing capabilities.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Automotive-Panel-2.jpg" alt="RISC-V in Automotive"></p><hr><p>Thank you for staying updated with the latest in the semiconductor industry. We look forward to bringing you more insights and innovations in future editions!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/uae-and-us-presidents-attend</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="RISC-V" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/RISC-V/"/>
    
    <category term="Molybdenum" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Molybdenum/"/>
    
    <category term="Chiplets" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Chiplets/"/>
    
    <category term="Innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Innovation/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>POET Appoints Ghazi Chaoui as Senior Vice President</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250516_POET-Appoints-Ghazi-Chaoui-as-Senior-Vice-President/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250516_POET-Appoints-Ghazi-Chaoui-as-Senior-Vice-President/</id>
    <published>2025-05-15T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-05-31T10:26:58.395Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/centrotherm-clean-solutions-becomes-pfeiffer-vacuumfab-solutions/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Centrotherm Clean Solutions Becomes Pfeiffer Vacuum+Fab Solutions</strong><br>The Busch Group consolidates its gas abatement systems for the semiconductor industry under the Pfeiffer brand, streamlining offerings to enhance customer service in vacuum solutions. This strategic integration aims to leverage the strengths of both brands to deliver comprehensive solutions to semiconductor manufacturers and related sectors.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="Centrotherm Clean Solutions"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/poet-appoints-ghazi-chaoui-phd-as-senior-vice-president-global-manufacturing-and-digital-transformation/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>POET Appoints Ghazi Chaoui as Senior Vice President</strong><br>POET Technologies Inc. announces the appointment of Dr. Ghazi Chaoui to lead global manufacturing and digital transformation efforts in Penang, Malaysia. His extensive experience will support the ramp-up of production for high-performance optical engines, crucial for meeting the demands of AI and hyperscale data centers.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="POET Technologies"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/355714-the-journey-of-interface-protocols-the-evolution-of-interface-protocols-part-1-of-2/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>The Evolution of Interface Protocols</strong><br>This report outlines the significant evolution of interface protocols in semiconductor design, driven by the rise of AI and increased data demands. The ongoing advancements in protocols like PCIe and Ethernet highlight the industry’s shift towards higher performance and capacity, essential for supporting modern AI workloads.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/The-journey-of-interface-protocols-part-1-table-1.png" alt="Evolution of Interface Protocols"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.imec-int.com/en/press/imec-and-feinstein-unveil-novel-concept-neuromodulation-intermittent-interferential-current">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Novel Concept for Neuromodulation</strong><br>Imec and the Feinstein Institutes have developed a new method for activating neural tissue using intermittent interferential current stimulation (i²CS). This approach enhances the precision and efficacy of vagus nerve stimulation, which could transform treatment options for various chronic diseases, showcasing the potential impact of semiconductor innovations in medicine.</p><p><img src="https://www.imec-int.com/sites/default/files/2025-04/image%20%282%29.png" alt="Neuromodulation"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/menlo-micro-within-three-months-of-delivering-millionth-device/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Menlo Micro’s Journey to Millionth Device</strong><br>CEO Russ Garcia discusses Menlo Micro’s progress towards delivering its millionth MEMS-based “Ideal” switch. This technology significantly enhances energy efficiency in various applications, positioning the company as a key player in the semiconductor industry, especially in the context of emerging AI technologies.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Russ-Garcia_CEO_Menlo-Micros_image-source_Nitin-Dahad.jpg" alt="Menlo Micro"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned with us for the latest insights and developments in the semiconductor industry!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/centrotherm-clean-solutions-</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="manufacturing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/manufacturing/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="chiplets" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/chiplets/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Simple Heating Step Boosts Pressure Sensitivity in Semiconductor Materials Eightfold</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250515_Simple-Heating-Step-Boosts-Pressure-Sensitivity-in-Semiconductor-Materials-Eightfold/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250515_Simple-Heating-Step-Boosts-Pressure-Sensitivity-in-Semiconductor-Materials-Eightfold/</id>
    <published>2025-05-14T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-05-31T10:26:58.395Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/entegris-announces-ceo-succession-plan/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Entegris Announces CEO Succession Plan</strong><br>Entegris, Inc. prepares for leadership transition as Bertrand Loy announces retirement after 13 years as President and CEO. David Reeder, currently a board member, will succeed him. Loy expresses confidence in Reeder’s capability to lead the company into a new phase of growth, highlighting significant achievements during his tenure, including revenue and market capitalization growth.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="Entegris Announcement"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/events/355772-how-arteris-is-revolutionizing-so-design-with-smart-noc-ip/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Arteris is Revolutionizing SoC Design</strong><br>At the recent IP-SoC Days, Arteris showcased its FlexGen smart NoC technology, which accelerates chip design by up to 10x and enhances engineering efficiency by threefold. This innovation aims to tackle the complexity of modern SoCs, enabling faster development and improved performance for various applications.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/How-Arteris-is-Revolutionizing-SoC-Design-with-Smart-NoC-IP-1200x639.png" alt="Arteris Presentation"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/saudi-arabia-and-nvidia-to-build-ai-factories/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>AI Factories to Transform Saudi Arabia</strong><br>NVIDIA and Saudi Arabia have partnered to build AI factories aimed at establishing the country as a global leader in AI and cloud computing. The initiative includes deploying advanced GPU systems and training developers to enhance local capabilities in AI technology.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="AI Factories"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-05-simple-boosts-pressure-sensitivity-semiconductor.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Simple Heating Step Boosts Pressure Sensitivity in Semiconductor Materials Eightfold</strong><br>Researchers at the University of Michigan have enhanced the piezoelectric properties of scandium aluminum nitride films through a straightforward annealing process. This breakthrough could significantly improve various applications, including cell phone signal processing and automotive safety systems.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/careful-heating-unlock.jpg" alt="Pressure Sensitivity"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/eda/siemens-eda/355928-eda-ai-agents-will-come-in-three-waves-and-usher-us-into-the-next-era-of-electronic-design/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>EDA AI Agents: The Next Frontier in Semiconductor Design</strong><br>Industry leaders discuss the evolution of AI in EDA, identifying three waves of AI integration that promise to transform electronic design automation. As AI capabilities expand, the semiconductor industry must adapt to increasingly complex workflows, enhancing efficiency and innovation.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Image-1-1200x752.png" alt="EDA AI Insight"></p><hr><p>Thank you for staying with us for the latest updates in the semiconductor industry. We’re committed to bringing you the most relevant and insightful information to help you navigate this dynamic field.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/entegris-announces-ceo-succe</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="chiplets" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/chiplets/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>New Technology Promises to Make Display Screens Cheaper, Brighter and More Environmentally Friendly</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250514_New-Technology-Promises-to-Make-Display-Screens-Cheaper,-Brighter-and-More-Environmentally-Friendly/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250514_New-Technology-Promises-to-Make-Display-Screens-Cheaper,-Brighter-and-More-Environmentally-Friendly/</id>
    <published>2025-05-13T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-05-31T10:26:58.395Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/354701-ceo-interview-with-roger-cummings-of-peakaio/">News</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Roger Cummings of PEAK:AIO</strong><br>In an insightful interview, Roger Cummings, CEO of PEAK:AIO, discusses how the company is transforming storage solutions for AI workloads. By addressing data bottlenecks caused by legacy systems, PEAK:AIO enhances performance and efficiency in sectors like healthcare and government. Their innovative architecture promises to provide up to six times the performance with significantly lower energy consumption, setting a new standard for AI infrastructure. </p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Roger-Cummings-of-PEAK-AIO.jpg" alt="Roger Cummings of PEAK:AIO"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/himax-to-debut-breakthrough-ultra-luminous-miniature-dual-edge-front-lit-lcos-microdisplay-at-sid-display-week-2025/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Himax to Debut Breakthrough Ultra-Luminous Miniature Dual-Edge Front-lit LCoS Microdisplay at Display Week 2025</strong><br>Himax Technologies has unveiled a state-of-the-art LCoS microdisplay designed for next-gen AR glasses and head-mounted displays. This ultra-compact display, featuring a remarkable brightness of up to 350,000 nits and power efficiency, redefines possibilities in miniature optics and is set to be showcased at Display Week 2025.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="Himax Microdisplay"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-05-technology-display-screens-cheaper-brighter.html">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>New Technology Promises to Make Display Screens Cheaper, Brighter and More Environmentally Friendly</strong><br>Researchers at the University of Surrey have introduced a multimodal transistor that simplifies display circuits, potentially halving production costs and enhancing energy efficiency. This innovation could revolutionize screen technology across various devices, from smartphones to medical devices, while significantly reducing harmful waste.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/electronic-tablet.jpg" alt="New Display Technology"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-05-unveil-rapid-electronic-skin-paving.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Researchers Unveil Rapid Self-Healing Electronic Skin</strong><br>A team at the Terasaki Institute has developed an electronic skin capable of self-healing within 10 seconds. This breakthrough technology maintains flexibility and electrical performance, paving the way for advanced health monitoring devices. With applications in sports performance and prosthetic control systems, this innovation represents a significant leap in wearable technology.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/researchers-unveil-rap.jpg" alt="Self-Healing Electronic Skin"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/security-risks-mount-for-aerospace-defense-applications/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Security Risks Mount for Aerospace and Defense Applications</strong><br>Experts discuss the increasing hardware security vulnerabilities affecting the defense sector, highlighting the risks posed by over-manufacturing and sophisticated attacks. As reliance on advanced semiconductor systems grows, the need for robust security measures in hardware design becomes paramount. Insights from industry leaders emphasize the importance of integrating security from the design stage to mitigate potential threats.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/threat1.png" alt="Security in Defense Sector"></p><hr><p>Stay informed with us for the latest updates, innovations, and insights in the semiconductor industry as we continue to explore the evolving landscape of technology and manufacturing.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/354701-ceo-interview</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Technology/"/>
    
    <category term="Manufacturing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Manufacturing/"/>
    
    <category term="Security" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Security/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
