<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>opensemi</title>
  
  <subtitle>we bring you the daily insight in semiconductor industry</subtitle>
  <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/"/>
  <updated>2025-11-28T05:17:14.704Z</updated>
  <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/</id>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>EU Commission Unveils €50 Billion &#39;European Chips Act 2.0&#39; to Bolster Domestic Production</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251128_EU-Commission-Unveils-%E2%82%AC50-Billion-&#39;European-Chips-Act-2.0&#39;-to-Bolster-Domestic-Production/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251128_EU-Commission-Unveils-%E2%82%AC50-Billion-&#39;European-Chips-Act-2.0&#39;-to-Bolster-Domestic-Production/</id>
    <published>2025-11-27T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-28T05:17:14.704Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251128_machinelearning_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/IP_25_EU_CHIPS_2_0">News</a></h2><p><strong>EU Commission Unveils €50 Billion ‘European Chips Act 2.0’ to Bolster Domestic Production</strong><br>The European Commission today announced the “European Chips Act 2.0,” a significant legislative package backed by €50 billion in public and private investment. This ambitious initiative aims to double the EU’s share in global semiconductor production to 20% by 2030, reducing reliance on external supply chains and fostering advanced chip manufacturing within the bloc. The act will focus on strengthening R&amp;D, establishing pilot lines for cutting-edge technologies, and attracting skilled talent.<br><img src="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/assets/img/EC_Building_Chips.jpg" alt="European Chips Act 2.0"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/multi-core-architecture-optimized-for-time-predictable-neural-network-inference-fzi-kit/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>MultiVic: A Time-Predictable RISC-V Multi-Core Processor Optimized for Neural Network Inference</strong><br>Researchers at FZI Research Center for Information Technology and Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT) have unveiled “MultiVic,” a new hardware architecture designed to bridge the gap between high-performance and predictable timing behavior in real-time systems, especially for neural network inference. MultiVic is a multi-core vector processor based on RISC-V, featuring predictable cores with local scratchpad memories and a central management core for orchestrated shared external memory access.</p><ul><li>Addresses the critical need for predictable timing behavior in AI hardware for real-time applications like automated driving.</li><li>Achieves better performance with more, smaller cores due to increased effective memory bandwidth and higher clock frequencies.</li><li>Maintains very low execution time fluctuation, ensuring crucial time predictability for real-time systems.<br><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/AdobeStock_621801039-10-7-25-scaled.jpeg" alt="Multi-Core Architecture"></li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/a-decade-of-architectural-rowhammer-defense-solutions-meta-snu-uiuc/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Systematizing a Decade of Architectural RowHammer Defenses</strong><br>A new paper from Meta, Seoul National University, and UIUC provides a comprehensive systematization of a decade of architectural RowHammer (RH) defenses. Despite continuous efforts, RowHammer remains a persistent threat to DRAM process technology scaling, with the cost of protection solutions increasing superlinearly. The research provides a taxonomy of 48 different defense mechanisms, mapping them to streaming algorithms and offering practitioner guides to select optimal defenses based on various parameters. This highlights the escalating challenge of maintaining DRAM reliability amidst scaling pressures.</p><ul><li>RowHammer continues to be a critical and evolving threat to DRAM reliability and process technology scaling.</li><li>The cost of RowHammer protection solutions is increasing superlinearly, posing a significant challenge for the industry.</li><li>The paper systematizes architectural defenses, offering a taxonomy and practical guides to navigate the complex landscape of RH mitigation strategies.<br><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_320501530-06-19-24-scaled.jpeg" alt="Architectural RowHammer Defense"></li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/digital-memristor-based-pim-from-a-device-and-reliability-view-northwestern-technion/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Comparative Study of Digital Memristor-Based Processing-In-Memory</strong><br>Researchers from Northwestern University and Technion – Israel Institute of Technology have published a review exploring the advancements in digital memristor-based Processing-In-Memory (PIM). This paradigm aims to overcome the memory wall by minimizing data transfer, leveraging emerging nonvolatile memory technologies like RRAM, PCM, and MRAM. The study critically examines both stateful and non-stateful logic techniques, focusing on reliability challenges and device-level optimization crucial for scalable and commercially viable PIM systems.</p><ul><li>PIM, using memristive devices, is a promising solution to the memory wall challenge in data-intensive applications.</li><li>The review analyzes various logic families and memristive device types, highlighting the trade-offs and quality indicators.</li><li>Emphasizes the critical role of device-level optimization and reliability in developing robust memristive devices for next-generation PIM applications.<br><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_164317986-AI-scaled.jpeg" alt="Digital Memristor-Based PIM"></li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/363646-agentic-bug-localization-innovation-in-verification/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Agentic Bug Localization. Innovation in Verification</strong><br>Paul Cunningham (GM, Verification at Cadence) and Raúl Camposano (Silicon Catalyst, former Synopsys CTO) discuss “LocAgent,” a graph-guided LLM agent for code localization from Yale, USC, Stanford, and All-Hands AI. This innovation addresses the persistent challenge of bug localization in verification. LocAgent builds a knowledge graph of a codebase, leveraging static analysis and LLM agents trained on bug reports to identify relevant files, classes, or functions for fixes with high accuracy and improved cost-efficiency compared to existing methods.</p><ul><li>LocAgent uses a unified graph representation and fine-tuned LLMs for efficient and accurate code localization.</li><li>A new benchmark, LocBench, addresses limitations of previous benchmarks by using modern, post-2024 GitHub repos across various issue categories.</li><li>Achieves comparable performance to leading commercial LLMs at significantly lower inference costs, indicating a promising direction for agentic AI in software engineering.<br><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Innovation-New.jpeg" alt="Agentic Bug Localization"></li></ul><hr><p>Stay tuned for the latest developments shaping the semiconductor landscape!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251128_machinelearning_newsle</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Machinelearning" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Machinelearning/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI hardware" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI-hardware/"/>
    
    <category term="Memory technologies" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Memory-technologies/"/>
    
    <category term="Neuromorphic computing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Neuromorphic-computing/"/>
    
    <category term="Chip design" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Chip-design/"/>
    
    <category term="RowHammer" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/RowHammer/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Mastiska CEO Champions Sovereign AI Silicon in the UAE with $10M Seed Funding</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251127_Mastiska-CEO-Champions-Sovereign-AI-Silicon-in-the-UAE-with-$10M-Seed-Funding/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251127_Mastiska-CEO-Champions-Sovereign-AI-Silicon-in-the-UAE-with-$10M-Seed-Funding/</id>
    <published>2025-11-26T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-27T05:13:20.812Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251127_etch_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/hipeac-vision-a-blueprint-for-european-survival/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Europe’s Chips Act 2.0: A Blueprint for Distributed AI and Sovereign Computing</strong><br><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/EU-RISC-V.png" alt="EU RISC-V"><br>The European Union is strategically pivoting its technological agenda with “Chips Act 2.0,” shifting its focus from mere factory commitments to securing the “Next Computing Paradigm” (NCP). This move, anchored in the HiPEAC Vision 2025, emphasizes distributed intelligence for AI and leveraging Europe’s strengths in edge and cyber-physical systems, aiming to counteract a significant “capital drain” to the U.S.</p><ul><li>The second phase of the Chips Act aims to support the entire supply chain, including design firms and equipment manufacturers, beyond just “First-of-a-Kind” facilities.</li><li>Despite ambitious targets, SEMI Europe members express skepticism about achieving 20% global market share by 2030, advocating for harmonized tax credits for R&amp;D and CAPEX to bolster SMEs.</li><li>The strategy underscores the importance of mastering design and toolchain ecosystems, promoting technologies like chiplets and open-source hardware (e.g., RISC-V) to reduce dependency on external manufacturers.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/q-ant-raises-series-a-debuts-second-gen-tfln-photonic-chip/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Q.ANT Debuts Second-Gen TFLN Photonic Chip for Advanced AI Acceleration</strong><br><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/QANT-second-gen-card.jpg" alt="Q.ANT second-gen card"><br>Photonic chip startup Q.ANT has announced a successful Series A funding round, totaling $80 million, alongside the unveiling of its second-generation photonic chip, the Q.ANT NPU 2. This thin-film lithium niobate (TFLN)-based chip is engineered for complex neural network architectures beyond large language models, targeting image, audio, and video processing. The NPU 2 boasts enhanced performance with 8 GOPS and a 2 GHz clock speed, operating at approximately 150W.</p><ul><li>The TFLN process harnesses non-linear optical properties for energy-efficient execution of non-linear mathematics, addressing performance and energy consumption challenges faced by CMOS technology.</li><li>A new four-year collaboration with the Jülich Supercomputing Centre will explore practical applications and integration of photonic computing with traditional computing systems.</li><li>Q.ANT’s proprietary software stack facilitates on-chip training and includes a “model zoo” featuring algorithms optimized to leverage the NPU’s core capabilities.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.tel.com/news/ir/2025/20251121_001.html">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Tokyo Electron Completes New Tohoku Production and Logistics Hub Amidst Market Expansion</strong><br><img src="https://www.tel.com/news/ir/2025/ch0hmn00000000fr-img/ch0hmn00000000hs.jpg" alt="Tokyo Electron Tohoku Production and Logistics Center"><br>Tokyo Electron (TEL) has completed its Tohoku Production and Logistics Center in Oshu City, Iwate Prefecture, marking a significant investment of approximately 24 billion yen. This new 58,000 m² hybrid facility strategically consolidates production and warehouse functions, aiming to reduce lead times, enhance operational efficiency, and improve flexibility in response to the anticipated growth in demand for deposition systems driven by global digitalization and decarbonization trends.</p><ul><li>The center will implement advanced automation, including multifunctional robots for warehousing and an integrated production line, to streamline workflows and drastically cut lead times.</li><li>Designed with sustainability in mind, the facility integrates energy-efficient equipment and consolidates logistics to minimize truck travel distances, consequently reducing CO2 emissions.</li><li>This strategic expansion underscores TEL’s commitment to ensuring timely product delivery and fostering sustainable corporate growth in line with evolving semiconductor technology demands.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/memsstar-offers-new-vacuum-vapour-phase-metal-assisted-chemical-etching-technology/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Memsstar Unveils Breakthrough Vacuum Vapour-Phase Metal-Assisted Chemical Etching (MacEtch)</strong><br><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="Memsstar Logo"><br>Memsstar Ltd., in partnership with the Paul Scherrer Institute (PSI) and Fraunhofer ENAS, has introduced a groundbreaking vacuum vapour-phase Metal-assisted Chemical Etching (MacEtch) technology. This innovative, plasma-free silicon etch process offers highly controlled, anisotropic etching for developing next-generation micro- and nanoscale architectures, demonstrating significantly reduced porosity, improved uniformity, and exceptional suitability for extremely high aspect ratio nanostructures.</p><ul><li>Implemented on memsstar’s ORBIS platform, the technology allows for precise gas-phase control and in-process endpoint detection, enabling sharply defined silicon profiles.</li><li>Early results confirm uniform etch profiles across 4-inch wafers and the creation of nanowire structures as fine as 100 nm with aspect ratios surpassing 430:1.</li><li>The vapor-phase module can be integrated with other memsstar process technologies, such as thermal pre-treatment and self-assembled monolayer (SAM) coating, offering versatile manufacturing solutions for diverse applications from MEMS to advanced semiconductor packaging.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/mastiska-raises-10m-seed-for-sovereign-ai-chip-play-in-uae/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Mastiska CEO Champions Sovereign AI Silicon in the UAE with $10M Seed Funding</strong><br><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Mastiska-4.png" alt="Mastiska Logo"><br>Suresh Sugumar, CEO of UAE-based Mastiṣka, offers key insights into the company’s strategic vision following a $10 million seed funding round from GCC sovereign wealth funds. Sugumar emphasizes that “Sovereign AI starts with sovereign silicon,” positioning Mastiṣka in a “blue ocean” market to develop data-center class inference accelerators, aiming to create a UAE-based fabless semiconductor entity leveraging open-source technologies.</p><ul><li>Mastiṣka’s initial market offerings will be custom FPGA cards, augmented with increased HBM, designed as commercially viable, lower-performance alternatives for AI inference tasks.</li><li>The company’s long-term roadmap includes taping out a RISC-V-based, neuromorphic-inspired ASIC within the next few years, integrating open-source frameworks and innovative brain-inspired models.</li><li>Sugumar highlights the commitment to providing sovereign customers with full audit access for cybersecurity and fostering local talent through establishing offices in partner GCC countries.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay connected with us for the most pivotal updates and strategic shifts shaping the semiconductor industry’s exciting future.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251127_etch_newsletter_gemini</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Etch" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Etch/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor Manufacturing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor-Manufacturing/"/>
    
    <category term="AI semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI-semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="Photonic Computing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Photonic-Computing/"/>
    
    <category term="Advanced Etching" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Advanced-Etching/"/>
    
    <category term="Sovereign AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Sovereign-AI/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>MIT Researchers Advance 3D Nanofabrication with Novel Directed Self-Assembly Method</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251126_MIT-Researchers-Advance-3D-Nanofabrication-with-Novel-Directed-Self-Assembly-Method/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251126_MIT-Researchers-Advance-3D-Nanofabrication-with-Novel-Directed-Self-Assembly-Method/</id>
    <published>2025-11-25T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-26T05:22:25.050Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251126_lithography_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-services/netapp/363837-cloud-accelerated-eda-development/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Accelerated EDA Development Addresses Plummeting First-Silicon Success Rates</strong><br>First-silicon success rates have dropped to a historic low of 14%, posing a significant challenge to the semiconductor industry, particularly as it advances towards 2nm process nodes. Traditional on-premises infrastructure struggles to meet the compute and memory demands for advanced verification workflows.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Figure-4.jpg" alt="Cloud is a natural fit for EDA"></p><ul><li>Cloud environments, through partnerships like AWS and NetApp, offer elastic scaling, advanced analytics, and robust security essential for next-generation verification.</li><li>AI-driven optimization and real-time analytics enable data-driven decisions, reducing verification cycle times and improving efficiency.</li><li>Embracing cloud transformation is critical for addressing verification complexities and enhancing silicon success rates in the 2nm era and beyond.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/a-decade-of-discovery-heidelberg-instruments-mla-150-maskless-aligner-turns-10/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Heidelberg Instruments MLA 150 Maskless Aligner Celebrates 10 Years with Enhanced Capabilities</strong><br>Heidelberg Instruments is marking a decade of innovation with its MLA 150 Maskless Aligner, a tool that has transformed high-resolution lithography in R&amp;D and industry since 2015. Known for its flexibility, mask-free operation, and ease of use, the MLA 150 has become a staple in over 250 cleanrooms worldwide.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="Heidelberg Instruments Logo"></p><ul><li>The MLA 150 uses a digital micromirror device (DMD) for direct-write lithography, offering fast turnaround times and high accuracy.</li><li>A significant upgrade in 2025 pushed the minimum feature size to 45 nm, expanding its utility for precision applications.</li><li>It supports rapid innovation in quantum devices, MEMS, micro-optics, and biosensors, enabling users to go from design to patterned substrate in minutes.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/266675/global-semiconductor-market-revenue-forecast/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Global Semiconductor Market Revenue Expected to Reach New Highs by 2030</strong><br>The semiconductor industry is poised for robust growth in the coming years, with market revenue projected to continue its upward trajectory, potentially surpassing significant milestones by the end of the decade. This expansion is driven by increasing demand across various applications, including AI, automotive, and IoT, alongside advancements in manufacturing technologies.</p><p><img src="https://www.statista.com/graphic/1/266675/global-semiconductor-market-revenue-forecast.jpg" alt="Global Semiconductor Market Revenue Forecast"></p><ul><li>Market analyses indicate a strong rebound and sustained growth following recent fluctuations, reflecting underlying demand for advanced computing.</li><li>Key drivers include the proliferation of AI accelerators, expansion of 5G infrastructure, and increasing adoption of smart technologies.</li><li>Continued investments in R&amp;D and manufacturing capacity are essential to support this projected market expansion.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-23259-6">Research</a></h2><p><strong>New Method Enhances Quantum Emitter Activation in SiC with Laser Annealing</strong><br>Researchers have developed a novel approach for efficiently forming luminescent defects, specifically silicon vacancies (VSi−), in 4H-SiC using ion irradiation followed by nanosecond-pulsed laser annealing. These “color centers” are critical for developing single photon sources (SPS) for quantum technologies, offering potential room-temperature operation.</p><p><img src="https://media.springernature.com/m685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-23259-6/MediaObjects/41598_2025_23259_Fig1_HTML.jpg" alt="Preliminary inspection of Sample #1 following ion irradiation and laser processing"></p><ul><li>The method allows for selective, localized activation of VSi− centers, significantly increasing activation yield compared to conventional thermal annealing.</li><li>Laser pre-processing enables efficient activation of VSi− centers at lower subsequent thermal annealing temperatures, from 600 °C down to 300-450 °C.</li><li>This technique is promising for scalable fabrication of robust quantum emitters in SiC for applications in quantum computing, cryptography, and sensing.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/dsa-method-of-3d-interconnected-structures-in-thin-films-mit/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>MIT Researchers Advance 3D Nanofabrication with Novel Directed Self-Assembly Method</strong><br>MIT researchers have published a new technical paper detailing a hierarchical Directed Self-Assembly (DSA) method to create 3D interconnected networks in thin films. This breakthrough expands the utility of block copolymers (BCPs) beyond traditional 2D patterning, opening new avenues for nanoscale manufacturing.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/AdobeStock_465169781-scaled.jpeg" alt="Abstract image of 3D interconnected structures"></p><ul><li>The method generates complex cross-point structures with connected in-plane and out-of-plane segments, offering controlled orientation.</li><li>By combining surface modification, BCP periodicity, and topographic templates, highly ordered 3D networks like ladder and cross-point structures can be produced.</li><li>This innovation significantly enhances BCP-derived nanofabrication capabilities, potentially impacting future device scaling and advanced material architectures.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay tuned for more essential updates as the semiconductor industry continues to innovate at an unprecedented pace.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251126_lithography_newsletter</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Lithography/"/>
    
    
    <category term="EUV" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/EUV/"/>
    
    <category term="EDA" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/EDA/"/>
    
    <category term="SiC" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/SiC/"/>
    
    <category term="Quantum" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Quantum/"/>
    
    <category term="Maskless" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Maskless/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Intelligence Per Watt- Measuring Local Inference Viability for AI</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251125_Intelligence-Per-Watt--Measuring-Local-Inference-Viability-for-AI/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251125_Intelligence-Per-Watt--Measuring-Local-Inference-Viability-for-AI/</id>
    <published>2025-11-24T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-25T05:20:45.028Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251125_device_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/a-power-reshuffle-follows-gf-tsmc-gan-tie-up/">News</a></h2><p><strong>A Power Reshuffle Follows GF, TSMC GaN Tie-up</strong><br>GlobalFoundries (GF) has licensed TSMC’s 650-V and 80-V GaN power semiconductor manufacturing technologies as TSMC plans to phase out its GaN fabrication by July 31, 2027. This strategic partnership includes a new GaN foundry agreement with Navitas Semiconductor, a major GaN chip vendor, with development starting in early 2026. This move could significantly shift GaN supply chain operations to U.S. soil, supporting high-power applications for AI data centers, EVs, and grid infrastructures.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Hero-image-3.jpg" alt="Power Reshuffle in GaN Market"></p><ul><li>GF licenses TSMC’s GaN manufacturing tech, aiming to become a U.S. GaN production hub.</li><li>Navitas Semiconductor, TSMC’s largest GaN customer, will transition production to GF.</li><li>The deal, supported by U.S. government funding, strengthens domestic GaN manufacturing for critical high-power applications.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/applied-materials-besi-push-die-to-wafer-hybrid-bonding-toward-high-volume-manufacturing/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Applied Materials, BESI Push Die-to-Wafer Hybrid Bonding Toward High-Volume Manufacturing</strong><br>Applied Materials and BE Semiconductor Industries (BESI) have unveiled the Kinex system, the industry’s first high-volume–ready die-to-wafer hybrid bonding platform. This integrated system addresses critical scaling limits by enabling ultra-fine pitch interconnects for chiplets, crucial for next-generation AI accelerators with hundreds of dies and millions of I&#x2F;Os per square millimeter. The Kinex platform boasts high precision (100-nm alignment at 3 sigma) and throughput (1,600 die placements per hour), optimizing surface preparation and reducing defects in a compact, integrated flow.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_868575540.jpeg" alt="High-Volume Die-to-Wafer Hybrid Bonding Platform"></p><ul><li>Introduces the first high-volume die-to-wafer hybrid bonding platform, Kinex, enabling advanced multi-chiplet packages.</li><li>Achieves 100-nm alignment accuracy and 1,600 die placements&#x2F;hour, with future plans for 50-nm accuracy.</li><li>Integrates the entire bonding flow on a single platform, significantly reducing queue times and contamination risks.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/intelligence-per-watt-measuring-local-inference-viability-studying-20-models-8-hw-accelerators-stanford-univ/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Intelligence Per Watt: Measuring Local Inference Viability for AI</strong><br>A Stanford University and Together AI study introduces “Intelligence per Watt (IPW)” as a metric to assess the capability and efficiency of local AI inference. Analyzing over 20 small Large Language Models (LLMs) and 8 hardware accelerators, the research reveals significant progress:</p><ul><li>Local LLMs can accurately answer 88.7% of single-turn chat and reasoning queries.</li><li>From 2023-2025, IPW improved 5.3x, and local query coverage increased from 23.2% to 71.3%.</li><li>Local accelerators achieve at least 1.4x lower IPW than cloud accelerators running identical models, indicating substantial optimization potential. These trends highlight the growing viability of local AI inference, which can redistribute demand from centralized cloud infrastructure and improve overall energy efficiency.</li></ul><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_322782977-01-29-25-scaled.jpeg" alt="Measuring Intelligence Efficiency of Local AI"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-11-artificial-neuron-mimic-brain-major.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Artificial Neuron Can Mimic Different Parts of the Brain—A Major Step Toward Human-Like Robotics</strong><br>An international research team led by Loughborough University has developed a “transneuron,” a single artificial neuron capable of mimicking the behavior of various brain cells involved in vision, planning, and movement. Unlike fixed-task artificial neurons, this device demonstrates a remarkable level of flexibility by switching between distinct pulse patterns (steady, irregular, rapid bursts) with 70–100% accuracy, matching signals recorded from macaque monkeys. The transneuron utilizes a memristor to “remember” past signals and adjust its response, paving the way for energy-efficient, adaptive neuromorphic hardware and human-like robotics.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2025/scientists-artificial.jpg" alt="Artificial Neuron Mimics Brain Activity"></p><ul><li>A single artificial “transneuron” can emulate the activity patterns of different brain regions (visual, motor, pre-motor cortex).</li><li>Uses a memristor to enable adaptive learning and respond to complex signal interactions.</li><li>Offers a path to energy-efficient, flexible neuromorphic systems for advanced AI and robotics.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/darpa-quantum-benchmarking-taps-canadian-firms/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>DARPA Quantum Benchmarking Taps Canadian Firms</strong><br>DARPA’s Quantum Benchmarking Initiative (QBI) has selected two Canadian firms, Photonic Inc. and Xanadu Quantum Technologies Inc., to advance to Stage B. The QBI aims to identify which quantum computing approaches can achieve utility-scale performance by 2033, balancing computational value with cost and real-world timelines. Photonic will focus on its Entanglement First architecture using optically linked silicon spin qubits, while Xanadu will present its fault-tolerant photonic quantum computer architecture. Stage B involves a year-long examination of their development, scaling, and cost-control strategies, with the potential for non-dilutive capital injection in Stage C to accelerate approved participants.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/CDNQuantumDARPA-covercarousel2.jpg" alt="Canadian Quantum Firms in DARPA Quantum Benchmarking Initiative"></p><ul><li>DARPA’s QBI advances Photonic and Xanadu to Stage B for utility-scale quantum computer assessment.</li><li>The initiative rigorously evaluates quantum modalities for practical application, cost-effectiveness, and real-world timelines by 2033.</li><li>Stage B focuses on development, scaling, and cost control, with potential future funding to accelerate quantum industry growth.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay connected with us for the most recent breakthroughs and strategic shifts defining the semiconductor landscape.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251125_device_newsletter_gemi</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Neuromorphic" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Neuromorphic/"/>
    
    <category term="Quantum Computing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Quantum-Computing/"/>
    
    <category term="GaN" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/GaN/"/>
    
    <category term="Hybrid Bonding" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Hybrid-Bonding/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Imec.kelis- tool for AI datacenter design and optimization</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251124_Imec.kelis--tool-for-AI-datacenter-design-and-optimization/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251124_Imec.kelis--tool-for-AI-datacenter-design-and-optimization/</id>
    <published>2025-11-23T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-24T05:19:28.861Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251124_semiconductor_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/ainekko-buys-esperanto-hardware-ip-open-sources-it/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Ainekko Buys Esperanto Hardware IP, Open-Sources It</strong><br>Ainekko, an open-source AI hardware and software startup, has acquired the IP and select assets of AI chip startup Esperanto Technologies. This includes chip designs, software tooling, and development framework, which Ainekko plans to open-source.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Esperanto-chip-sq_1e676f.jpg" alt="Esperanto chip"></p><ul><li>Ainekko will open-source Esperanto’s production-grade many-core RISC-V architecture for increased flexibility and community engagement.</li><li>The initiative targets edge AI applications where power efficiency is critical, rather than hyperscale data centers.</li><li>Ainekko plans its first silicon tapeout with eight Esperanto cores and MRAM, aiming for an intermediate 256-core design next.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.imec-int.com/en/press/imec-unveils-imeckelis-breakthrough-tool-ai-datacenter-design-and-optimization">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Imec.kelis: tool for AI datacenter design and optimization</strong><br>Imec has launched imec.kelis, an analytical performance modeling tool designed to optimize the design of AI datacenters. This cutting-edge tool provides a fast, transparent, and validated framework for evaluating system performance across compute, communication, and memory subsystems, specifically tailored for large language model (LLM) training and inference workloads.</p><p><img src="https://www.imec-int.com/sites/default/files/2025-11/2023_IMEC_3D-Stack_Visual_v07_0.png" alt="Imec 3D Stack Visual"></p><ul><li>Imec.kelis offers an end-to-end framework for AI datacenter design, enabling architects to balance performance, sustainability, and cost.</li><li>It leverages imec’s expertise in system-level modeling and hardware-software co-design, with predictions validated on industry-standard platforms.</li><li>Key features include an LLM task-graph analyzer, a hierarchical roofline model, and an interactive dashboard for design space exploration, validated within a 12% error margin.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-services/363956-semiconductors-up-over-20-in-2025/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Semiconductors Up Over 20% in 2025</strong><br>The world semiconductor market reached a record $208 billion in Q3 2025, marking the first time it surpassed $200 billion. This represents a 15.8% increase from Q2 2025 and a 25.1% rise from Q3 2024, driven significantly by AI demand. Nvidia remained the top supplier with $57.0 billion in revenue.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Semiconductors-Up-Over-20-in-2025-3.jpg" alt="Semiconductor Market Growth"></p><ul><li>The semiconductor market achieved a record $208 billion in Q3 2025, reflecting robust growth of over 20% year-over-year.</li><li>AI-driven demand, particularly for memory and AI accelerators, is identified as the primary catalyst for this strong market performance.</li><li>The market is projected to continue growing by 12% to 18% in 2026, with potential moderation in AI-dependent sectors and stronger growth in other segments like PCs and smartphones.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/quantum-sensors-2674296517">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Quantum Sensor Startup Seeks Flaws in 3D Chips</strong><br>EuQlid, a quantum technology startup, is developing a novel quantum sensor platform called QuMRI to non-destructively detect buried defects in 3D chips. This technology, based on artificial diamonds with nitrogen-vacancy (NV) centers, aims to quickly map current flows in deeply buried interconnects, potentially saving billions of dollars in manufacturing.</p><p><img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.jpg?id=62202995&width=1200&height=600&coordinates=0,15,0,15" alt="Quantum sensors"></p><ul><li>QuMRI uses quantum sensors from artificial diamonds to precisely map current flows and detect defects in 3D stacked chips without damage.</li><li>The technology is significantly faster (100x) than X-ray inspection and offers similar precision to depths required by the semiconductor industry.</li><li>This innovation addresses critical challenges in 3D chip manufacturing by providing a non-destructive method for quality control, improving yield and reducing costs.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/the-future-for-formal-verification/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>The Future For Formal Verification</strong><br>An expert panel discussed the evolving role of formal verification (FV) in the semiconductor industry, particularly with the advent of Agentic AI. The conversation highlighted FV’s potential to move beyond traditional functional verification, playing a crucial role in validating AI-generated designs, identifying unknown unknowns, and addressing challenges in security, functional safety, power, and thermal analysis.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_718179106-11-07-24-scaled.jpeg" alt="The Future For Formal Verification"></p><ul><li>Agentic AI is expected to transform EDA by generating design code and assertions, with formal verification essential for ensuring correctness and completeness.</li><li>Experts believe the industry is shifting towards natural language specifications, with LLMs assisting in translating these into machine-readable formats and SVA properties.</li><li>Beyond functional verification, FV is being applied to critical areas like security, power optimization (e.g., clock gating), functional safety (FuSa), and identifying worst-case performance scenarios.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay tuned for more essential updates as the semiconductor landscape continues to evolve with groundbreaking advancements and market shifts.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251124_semiconductor_newslett</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Market Trends" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Market-Trends/"/>
    
    <category term="Neuromorphic" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Neuromorphic/"/>
    
    <category term="EDA" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/EDA/"/>
    
    <category term="Hybrid Bonding" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Hybrid-Bonding/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>ChipAgents AI Revolutionizes RTL Design and Verification with Autonomous Root Cause Analysis</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251121_ChipAgents-AI-Revolutionizes-RTL-Design-and-Verification-with-Autonomous-Root-Cause-Analysis/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251121_ChipAgents-AI-Revolutionizes-RTL-Design-and-Verification-with-Autonomous-Root-Cause-Analysis/</id>
    <published>2025-11-20T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-21T05:18:34.757Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251121_machinelearning_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/363814-arm-fcsa-and-the-journey-to-standardizing-open-chiplet-based-design/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Arm FCSA and the Journey to Standardizing Open Chiplet-Based Design</strong><br>Arm has donated its Foundation Chiplet System Architecture (FCSA) to the Open Compute Project (OCP), marking a significant step towards standardizing open chiplet-based designs. FCSA is an ISA-neutral initiative focused on addressing inter-chiplet communication challenges, particularly for AI-driven automotive and infrastructure applications. This move aims to enable a more modular and scalable approach to building complex, multi-die systems by defining standard interfaces like AMBA CHI C2C, allowing chiplets from various vendors to seamlessly interact.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/AI-driven-car.jpg" alt="AI-driven car"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/363689-i-have-seen-the-future/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>ChipAgents AI Revolutionizes RTL Design and Verification with Autonomous Root Cause Analysis</strong><br>ChipAgents AI is pioneering an AI-native approach to Electronic Design Automation (EDA), targeting a 10x productivity improvement in RTL design and verification. A recent demonstration highlighted the system’s capability to autonomously identify and resolve design bugs in a complex PCIe Gen 3 design using natural language commands. The system completed a task that typically takes engineers dozens of hours in approximately 20 minutes, signaling a transformative shift towards AI-augmented design processes.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/I-Have-Seen-the-Future-with-ChipAgents-Autonomous-Root-Cause-Analysis-1200x555.png" alt="ChipAgents Autonomous Root Cause Analysis"></p><ul><li>AI-native EDA targets 10x productivity boost in RTL design&#x2F;verification.</li><li>Autonomous root cause analysis resolves complex bugs in minutes via natural language.</li><li>Demonstrates a significant leap towards AI-augmented design workflows.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/comparative-analysis-of-cfet-and-nsfet-architectures-tu-munich-indian-institute-of-tech/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Comparative Analysis of CFET and NSFET Architectures Reveals Performance and Area Gains</strong><br>A recent study from TU Munich and Indian Institute of Technology presents a comparative analysis of Complementary Field-Effect Transistor (CFET) and Nanosheet FET (NSFET) architectures, focusing on the impact of aging, self-heating, and parasitics on standard cell performance. The research highlights significant advantages of CFETs in advanced process nodes.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_322557739-01-29-25-scaled.jpeg" alt="Semiconductor architecture comparison"></p><ul><li>CFETs offer approximately 50% area savings at the standard cell level compared to NSFETs.</li><li>They demonstrate a 42% improvement in inverter propagation delay.</li><li>CFET SRAM cells provide area gain with faster and more stable write operations, indicating strong potential for high-performance applications.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/study-of-compute-efficiency-and-density-of-3-photonic-computing-architectures-ibm-et-al/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Study Highlights Compute Efficiency and Density of Integrated Photonic Computing Architectures</strong><br>Researchers from IBM Research – Europe, University of Heidelberg, and University of Münster have published a technical paper on the performance metrics of integrated photonic computing. The study provides a microarchitecture-level analysis of three prominent photonic computing architectures, taking into account both the optical circuits and the essential electronic peripheral circuitry required for optoelectronic and analog-to-digital conversions. It also demonstrates a heterogeneous photonic-electronic in-memory processing approach suitable for low-latency neural network inference, offering crucial insights into design aspects for enhancing compute efficiency and density.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_839148332-06-19-24-scaled.jpeg" alt="Photonic computing architecture"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-services/363818-webinar-is-agentic-ai-the-future-of-eda/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Agentic AI Set to Transform EDA, Experts to Discuss Infrastructure and Future</strong><br>SemiWiki is hosting a pivotal webinar on December 4, 2025, titled “Is Agentic AI the Future for EDA — and What Does It Mean for EDA Infrastructure?”. Industry leaders from Cadence, NetApp, and AMD will convene to discuss how Agentic AI is poised to reshape chip design and verification. The session will cover the current state and future potential of Agentic AI, as well as the necessary infrastructure changes—including compute, storage, orchestration, and data management—to support AI-driven EDA workflows. The webinar promises practical guidance for semiconductor professionals navigating the shift towards autonomous, AI-augmented design processes.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/NetApp-Cadence-Webinar-Banner.jpg" alt="NetApp Cadence Webinar Banner"></p><ul><li>Webinar on Dec 4, 2025, addresses Agentic AI’s impact on EDA.</li><li>Experts from Cadence, NetApp, and AMD will discuss current state, future, and infrastructure needs.</li><li>Aims to provide practical guidance for adopting AI-driven design automation.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay tuned for more cutting-edge developments shaping the future of the semiconductor industry!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251121_machinelearning_newsle</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Machinelearning" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Machinelearning/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Chiplets" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Chiplets/"/>
    
    <category term="DRAM" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/DRAM/"/>
    
    <category term="Photonic Computing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Photonic-Computing/"/>
    
    <category term="AI in EDA" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI-in-EDA/"/>
    
    <category term="Next-Gen FETs" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Next-Gen-FETs/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Crypto Mining ASIC Goes Deep Sub-Threshold on 3 nm</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251120_Crypto-Mining-ASIC-Goes-Deep-Sub-Threshold-on-3-nm/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251120_Crypto-Mining-ASIC-Goes-Deep-Sub-Threshold-on-3-nm/</id>
    <published>2025-11-19T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-20T05:13:43.993Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251120_etch_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/ainekko-buys-esperanto-hardware-ip-open-sources-it/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Ainekko Buys Esperanto Hardware IP, Open-Sources It</strong><br>Open-source AI hardware and software startup Ainekko has acquired the IP and selected assets of AI chip startup Esperanto Technologies, including its chip designs, software tooling, and development framework. Ainekko plans to open-source Esperanto’s production-grade many-core RISC-V architecture, including RTL, reference designs, and development tools, with the goal of fostering community innovation and focusing on power-efficient edge AI applications.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Esperanto-chip-sq_1e676f.jpg" alt="Esperanto chip"></p><ul><li>Ainekko acquires Esperanto’s RISC-V AI chip IP, making it open-source.</li><li>Aims to drive innovation for edge AI, robotics, and embedded devices.</li><li>Plans include a TSMC tapeout and future ASIC design services leveraging the open architecture.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-today.com/news_items/2013/JUL/PEKING_120713.html">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Self-terminating recess etch produces nitride transistor with +3V threshold</strong><br>Researchers from Peking and Xidian universities have developed a self-terminating gate recess etch process that enables the production of aluminium gallium nitride (AlGaN) normally-off metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect transistors (MOSFETs) with positive threshold voltages of up to +3.2V. This advancement is critical for high-frequency and high-power applications, leading to more reliable and energy-efficient devices by ensuring fail-safe operation.</p><p><img src="https://semiconductor-today.com/news_items/2013/JUL/13072pekingfigure1.jpg" alt="Log-scale transfer curve and gate leakage of fabricated device"></p><ul><li>New self-terminating gate recess etch process for AlGaN MOSFETs.</li><li>Achieves a high positive threshold voltage of +3.2V for reliable normally-off operation.</li><li>Enhances performance and power efficiency in high-frequency and high-power applications.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://newsroom.lamresearch.com/minimizing-voltage-loss-advanced-gaa-transistors?blog=true">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Minimizing Voltage Loss and Boosting Yield in Advanced GAA Transistors</strong><br>A virtual study by Lam Research’s Semiverse Solutions team analyzed Gate-All-Around (GAA) devices using Backside Power Delivery Networks (BSPDN), comparing Direct Backside Contact (DBC) and Self-Aligned Backside Contact (SABC) architectures. The study, which includes process window contour diagrams, demonstrates that SABC significantly minimizes edge placement error (EPE) and over-etch variations, providing a much larger and more stable process window than DBC, thus promising higher yield for advanced logic nodes.</p><p><img src="/opensemi/img/semiconductor_future.png" alt="Advanced GAA Transistors"><br><em>(Refer to the original article for “Figure 2. Comparison of SABC and DBC process windows”)</em></p><ul><li>Virtual study compares SABC and DBC architectures for advanced GAA transistors with BSPDN.</li><li>SABC approach offers a significantly larger and more stable process window.</li><li>Minimizes EPE and over-etch variations, leading to higher yield for future logic device scaling.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/crypto-mining-asic-goes-deep-sub-threshold-on-3-nm/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Crypto Mining ASIC Goes Deep Sub-Threshold on 3 nm</strong><br>Japanese company Triple-1 is taping out its Kamikaze III Bitcoin-mining ASIC on TSMC’s 3nm process, boasting a power efficiency of 10.45 J&#x2F;TH through proprietary sub-threshold design techniques. This groundbreaking approach, requiring custom cell design and manual routing, not only pushes the boundaries of power efficiency for crypto mining but also positions the company to develop future AI accelerator chips optimized for edge applications, leveraging its expertise in power management and distributed computing.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Kamikaze-II.jpg" alt="Kamikaze-II"></p><ul><li>Triple-1’s Kamikaze III ASIC on TSMC 3nm achieves extreme power efficiency with proprietary sub-threshold design.</li><li>Highlights innovative custom cell design and manual routing for ultra-low voltage operation.</li><li>Explores a transition to AI accelerator chips for edge computing and distributed energy solutions.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/d-wave-among-few-ramping-quantum-computer-sales/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>D-Wave Among Few Ramping Quantum Computer Sales</strong><br>D-Wave’s Chief Development Officer Trevor Lanting discussed the company’s increasing sales of quantum annealing systems, including a significant installation at the Jülich Supercomputing Center for integration with Europe’s Jupiter exascale computer. Lanting provided key insights into D-Wave’s strategic pivot towards developing more challenging gate-model quantum technology, driven by critical innovations in error correction methodologies and fundamental qubit design, emphasizing the long-term vision for quantum applications.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Advantage2-QPU.jpg" alt="Advantage2 QPU"></p><ul><li>D-Wave reports growing sales of its quantum annealing systems, including deployments for exascale supercomputer integration.</li><li>Outlines a strategic pivot to gate-model quantum technology, citing advancements in error correction and qubit design.</li><li>Leverages existing foundry partnerships for the development of both annealing and gate-based quantum processors.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay connected with us for the latest news and breakthroughs shaping the semiconductor landscape.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251120_etch_newsletter_gemini</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Etch" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Etch/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Quantum Computing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Quantum-Computing/"/>
    
    <category term="GaN MOSFETs" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/GaN-MOSFETs/"/>
    
    <category term="GAA Transistors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/GAA-Transistors/"/>
    
    <category term="AI Hardware" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI-Hardware/"/>
    
    <category term="Sub-threshold Design" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Sub-threshold-Design/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Aniah Revolutionizes Electrical Verification in IC Design with OneCheck®</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251119_Aniah-Revolutionizes-Electrical-Verification-in-IC-Design-with-OneCheck%C2%AE/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251119_Aniah-Revolutionizes-Electrical-Verification-in-IC-Design-with-OneCheck%C2%AE/</id>
    <published>2025-11-18T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-19T05:26:27.496Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251119_lithography_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.trendforce.com/news/2025/11/18/news-china-photoresist-maker-hengkun-goes-public-on-star-market-with-ymtc-tied-fund/">News</a></h2><p><strong>China Photoresist Maker Hengkun Goes Public on STAR Market with YMTC-Tied Fund</strong><br><img src="https://img.trendforce.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/06145612/China-Semiconductor-chip-624x416.jpg" alt="China Semiconductor chip"><br>Xiamen Hengkun New Material, a prominent Chinese photoresist manufacturer, has successfully debuted on the Shanghai STAR Market, securing RMB 1.01 billion. This significant funding is earmarked for expanding its IC precursor and advanced IC materials projects, underscoring China’s strategic drive to bolster domestic capabilities in critical semiconductor materials and reduce reliance on imports.</p><ul><li>Hengkun’s product portfolio, including SOC, BARC, KrF, and i-Line photoresists, are in mass production, supporting advanced 3D NAND, DRAM, and sub-14nm logic chips.</li><li>The IPO capital will substantially boost the production of KrF&#x2F;ArF photoresists and precursor materials.</li><li>The company’s impressive growth in KrF photoresists and successful validation of ArF immersion photoresists signify accelerating domestic substitution trends.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/eda/aniah/363639-webinar-electrical-verification-the-invisible-bottleneck-in-ic-design/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Aniah Revolutionizes Electrical Verification in IC Design with OneCheck®</strong><br><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Electrical-Verification-%E2%80%93-The-invisible-bottleneck-in-IC-design-2.png" alt="Electrical Verification – The invisible bottleneck in IC design"><br>Aniah has introduced OneCheck®, a pioneering static transistor-level Electrical Rule Checking (ERC) tool, poised to tackle the pervasive bottleneck in IC design verification. With industry reports indicating that 86% of IC&#x2F;ASIC designs necessitate respins due to flaws, OneCheck® aims to enable “right-on-first-silicon” by automating verification processes, drastically minimizing false positives, and providing unparalleled error coverage across increasingly complex designs.</p><ul><li>OneCheck® performs full-chip analysis across all possible power combinations, rigorously detecting errors like conditional HiZ, missing level shifters, and electrical overstress.</li><li>It integrates seamlessly with Cadence Virtuoso, allowing for early-stage implementation and processing of billion-transistor designs within minutes.</li><li>The tool significantly enhances debugging efficiency and overall productivity by identifying and grouping root causes of errors.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-22693-w">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Ultra-broadband Wide-angle Anti-reflection Scheme Utilizing Multi-layer Resonant Metasurfaces</strong><br><img src="https://media.springernature.com/m685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-22693-w/MediaObjects/41598_2025_22693_Fig1_HTML.png" alt="Figure 1: Schematic of the proposed AR scheme"><br>A novel hybrid anti-reflection (AR) scheme employing multi-layer resonant metasurfaces has been developed, showcasing ultra-broadband and wide-angle performance. Demonstrated for Silicon-Air interfaces in the telecom band, this monolithic, single-material design exhibits remarkable robustness against fabrication errors and is ideally suited for high-power applications, offering a significant improvement over conventional thin-film coatings.</p><ul><li>The scheme precisely optimizes meta-atom dimensions to tailor metasurface resonances, achieving reflection suppression beyond -30dB across the 1300-1700 nm wavelength range and for incidence angles up to ±30°.</li><li>Design robustness was confirmed through analysis showing minimal impact from typical fabrication dimension variations (e.g., ±5-10 nm for meta-atoms, ±10-20 nm for thickness).</li><li>This approach is compatible with additive manufacturing techniques, including 3D printing and Nano-Imprint Lithography, facilitating scalable production for diverse optical systems.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/blend-strategy-to-improve-edge-resistance-capability-and-thickness-of-euv-fabricated-nanopatterns-national-tsing-hua-univ/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Blend Strategy To Improve Edge Resistance Capability And Thickness Of EUV-Fabricated Nanopatterns</strong><br><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_621001046-11-7-24.jpeg" alt="EUV-Fabricated Nanopatterns"><br>Researchers at National Tsing Hua University have unveiled a groundbreaking blend strategy for tin-oxide (SnO) photoresists, significantly enhancing both the edge resistance and thickness of EUV-fabricated nanopatterns. By combining two distinct tin oxide carboxylate clusters, the resulting photoresist achieved exceptional EUV resolutions (13-16 nm half-pitch) at notably low exposure doses (50-60 mJ&#x2F;cm²), alongside marked improvements in etching resistance.</p><ul><li>This blend strategy leverages one 12-oxide cluster to specifically boost pattern resolution, etching resistance, and nanopattern thickness, while photosensitivity is primarily driven by the other cluster.</li><li>The innovation directly addresses persistent challenges of limited thickness and poor etching resistance commonly encountered in current metal carboxylate cluster EUV photoresists.</li><li>Cooperative interactions between the clusters yielded an outstanding Z-factor (2.65 × 10⁻⁸ mJ·nm³), indicative of superior overall lithographic performance.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/global-semiconductor-outlook-2025-trends-and-forecasts/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Global Semiconductor Outlook 2025: Key Trends and Forecasts by Industry Leaders</strong><br><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/semiconductor_trends.jpg" alt="Semiconductor Market Trends"><br>Leading figures in the semiconductor industry recently shared their projections for 2025, emphasizing the sustained and accelerating growth of Artificial Intelligence (AI) and High-Performance Computing (HPC) as pivotal drivers of semiconductor demand. Despite anticipated macroeconomic variability, executives highlighted the imperative of strategic investments in advanced manufacturing, comprehensive R&amp;D, and robust supply chain resilience. A key focus is the industry’s ongoing shift towards specialized architectures and heterogeneous integration to effectively meet evolving demands for performance and power efficiency.</p><ul><li>AI and HPC are forecast to be the primary engines for significant growth, necessitating continued advancements in packaging and process technologies.</li><li>Ongoing efforts in supply chain diversification and regionalization aim to mitigate geopolitical risks and enhance overall resilience.</li><li>The industry is placing a heightened focus on sustainability and energy efficiency, integrating these principles into both chip design and manufacturing processes.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay connected with us for the latest news and breakthroughs shaping the semiconductor landscape!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251119_lithography_newsletter</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Lithography/"/>
    
    
    <category term="EUV Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/EUV-Lithography/"/>
    
    <category term="Photoresists" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Photoresists/"/>
    
    <category term="IC Design Verification" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/IC-Design-Verification/"/>
    
    <category term="Quantum Emitters" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Quantum-Emitters/"/>
    
    <category term="Metasurfaces" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Metasurfaces/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hierarchically Defining Bump and Pin Regions Overcomes 3D IC Complexity</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251118_Hierarchically-Defining-Bump-and-Pin-Regions-Overcomes-3D-IC-Complexity/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251118_Hierarchically-Defining-Bump-and-Pin-Regions-Overcomes-3D-IC-Complexity/</id>
    <published>2025-11-17T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-18T05:20:44.192Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251118_device_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/arms-dreambig-acquisition-reignites-in-house-chip-prospects/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Arm’s DreamBig Acquisition Reignites In-House Chip Prospects</strong><br>Arm has acquired DreamBig Semiconductor for $265 million, signaling a strategic move to capitalize on the surging AI and data center demand. DreamBig, known for its Chiplet Hub technology and Mercury AI-SuperNIC, could help Arm expand beyond its traditional IP licensing model. This acquisition fuels speculation that Arm might begin developing and selling its own chips, especially in the AI networking and data center sectors.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_649054724_Editorial_Use_Only.jpeg" alt="Arm Acquires DreamBig"></p><ul><li>Arm’s acquisition targets DreamBig’s chiplet and AI networking solutions.</li><li>The move suggests Arm may explore selling its own chips, not just IP, for AI data centers.</li><li>This strategic shift could intensify competition with existing Arm licensees in the AI silicon market.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ip/ceva/363351-ceva-unleashes-wi-fi-7-pulse-awakening-instant-ai-brains-in-iot-and-physical-robots/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Ceva Unleashes Wi-Fi 7 Pulse Awakening Instant AI Brains in IoT</strong><br>Ceva has launched the Ceva-Waves Wi-Fi 7 1x1 client IP, designed to power AI-enabled IoT devices and physical AI systems with unprecedented responsiveness. Leveraging the IEEE 802.11be standard, this IP core delivers ultra-high performance in compact, power-constrained form factors, essential for the projected 30 billion IoT devices by 2030. It integrates seamlessly with Ceva’s NeuPro NPUs, enabling on-device intelligence and reducing reliance on cloud processing.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Ceva-WiFi-7-1x1-Client-IP.jpg" alt="Ceva-Waves Wi-Fi 7 1x1 Client IP"></p><ul><li>The Wi-Fi 7 IP enhances AI-enabled IoT with low-latency, high-throughput connectivity.</li><li>Features like Multi-Link Operation and 4096-QAM boost performance for real-time applications.</li><li>Integration with NPUs facilitates on-device AI processing, improving data privacy and battery life.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20230306005391/en/Global-AI-Chip-Market-2023-to-2030---Trend-Forecast-and-Competitive-Analysis">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>AI Chip Market Size Projected for Significant Growth Through 2030</strong><br>The global AI chip market is experiencing explosive growth, driven by increasing adoption across diverse sectors from data centers to edge devices. Industry reports indicate a substantial upward trajectory in market size, with forecasts predicting continued expansion at a robust compound annual growth rate through 2030. This growth underscores the foundational role of specialized AI silicon in advancing artificial intelligence capabilities.</p><p><img src="https://img-cdn.service.bit.ai/11545625-1650392359550-ai-chip-market-share.webp" alt="AI Chip Market Growth Forecast"></p><ul><li>The AI chip market is forecasted for rapid expansion, propelled by demand for AI processing.</li><li>Growth is evident across various applications, from cloud AI to edge intelligence.</li><li>Specialized AI hardware is critical for enabling next-generation AI models and services.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/edge-ai-safety-agentic-ai-architecture-that-leverages-3d-to-integrate-a-dedicated-safety-layer-princeton-hkust-nc-state-univ/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>3D Guard-Layer: An Integrated Agentic AI Safety System for Edge AI</strong><br>Researchers from Princeton, HKUST, and NC State University have published a technical paper introducing “3D Guard-Layer,” an integrated agentic AI safety architecture for Edge AI. This novel system leverages 3D integration to embed a dedicated safety layer directly within edge devices. It’s designed to dynamically learn and mitigate attacks against AI systems, enhancing resilience, reliability, and performance with minimal overhead for edge computing hardware.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_362074973-security-07-23-scaled.jpeg" alt="Edge AI Security"></p><ul><li>Proposes a 3D integrated safety layer for Edge AI to combat security vulnerabilities.</li><li>The system offers adaptive learning capabilities to mitigate evolving AI attacks.</li><li>Enhances resilience, reliability, and modularity for AI deployment at the edge.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/eda/siemens-eda/363678-hierarchically-defining-bump-and-pin-regions-overcomes-3d-ic-complexity/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Hierarchically Defining Bump and Pin Regions Overcomes 3D IC Complexity</strong><br>Experts from Siemens EDA emphasize the critical role of hierarchical device planning in managing the explosive complexity of modern IC packaging, especially with 3D ICs and chiplet integration. With pin counts surging into the millions, traditional “flat” design methodologies are no longer sufficient. Hierarchical planning provides an abstraction layer, enabling designers to optimize functional areas, conduct early multi-domain analyses (SI, PI, thermal), and significantly reduce costly redesigns.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/connectivity-in-a-hierarchical-IC-package-floorplan-1200x697.jpg" alt="Connectivity in a Hierarchical IC Package Floorplan"></p><ul><li>Hierarchical device planning is crucial for managing the immense complexity of 3D IC and chiplet packaging.</li><li>It allows abstraction of millions of pins into manageable regions, enhancing design efficiency.</li><li>Early multi-domain analysis is vital for informed design decisions and preventing expensive re-spins.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay connected with us for the latest breakthroughs and developments shaping the semiconductor landscape!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251118_device_newsletter_gemi</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Chiplets" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Chiplets/"/>
    
    <category term="EDA" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/EDA/"/>
    
    <category term="3D IC" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/3D-IC/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor Workforce" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor-Workforce/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>AI Chip Startup Tsavorite Emerges With $100 Million In Pre-Orders</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251117_AI-Chip-Startup-Tsavorite-Emerges-With-$100-Million-In-Pre-Orders/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251117_AI-Chip-Startup-Tsavorite-Emerges-With-$100-Million-In-Pre-Orders/</id>
    <published>2025-11-16T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-17T05:19:35.562Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251117_semiconductor_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/3d-heterogeneous-integration">News</a></h2><p><strong>3D Heterogeneous Integration Powers New DARPA Fab</strong><br>The Texas Institute for Electronics (TIE) in Austin is being transformed into the world’s only advanced packaging plant dedicated to 3D heterogeneous integration (3DHI). This initiative, part of DARPA’s Next-Generation Microelectronics Manufacturing (NGMM) program, aims to achieve a 100-fold performance boost by stacking chips made of diverse materials like gallium nitride and silicon carbide, not just silicon. This new fab will focus on prototyping and manufacturing these complex stacked chips in the U.S., mitigating the “lab-to-fab valley of death” for hardware startups.</p><p><img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.jpg?id=62098318&width=1200&height=600&coordinates=0,306,0,174" alt="3D Heterogeneous Integration Fab"></p><ul><li><strong>DARPA-backed 3DHI Fab</strong>: Texas Institute for Electronics (TIE) is establishing a unique facility for advanced chip stacking using silicon and non-silicon materials.</li><li><strong>Performance Leap</strong>: Aims for a 100-fold performance increase over 2D integration by combining diverse materials.</li><li><strong>U.S. Manufacturing &amp; Innovation</strong>: Supports domestic prototyping and manufacturing of advanced chips, assisting startups in overcoming commercialization hurdles.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/ai-chip-startup-tsavorite-emerges-with-100-million-in-pre-orders/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>AI Chip Startup Tsavorite Emerges With $100 Million In Pre-Orders</strong><br>Tsavorite Scalable Intelligence, an AI chip startup, has exited stealth mode with $100 million in pre-orders and eight design-ins totaling $350 million. The company specializes in chiplet-based AI inference accelerators, featuring two proprietary chiplets (OmniFlex and SkyFlex) connected via its “MultiPlexus” fabric. This architecture is designed for high scalability and efficiency, offering unified memory and low latency for diverse applications from robotics to data centers. Tsavorite’s software stack, Taos, is CUDA-compatible and supports fine-tuning and reinforcement learning, aiming to provide a comprehensive solution for enterprise AI. Pre-production systems are expected by mid-2026.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Robot_6d9e47.jpg" alt="AI Chip Startup Tsavorite"></p><ul><li><strong>Chiplet-Based AI Accelerators</strong>: Tsavorite’s Omni Processing Unit (OPU) chiplets use a proprietary MultiPlexus fabric for scalable, efficient AI inference.</li><li><strong>Unified Memory &amp; Low Latency</strong>: The architecture supports large-scale designs up to 8,000 OPUs with unified memory access and high-memory bandwidth.</li><li><strong>CUDA-Compatible Software</strong>: The Taos software stack is designed for seamless integration and also enables fine-tuning and reinforcement learning on the same hardware.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/new-rules-put-the-squeeze-on-semiconductor-gray-market/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>New Rules Put The Squeeze On Semiconductor Gray Market</strong><br>The semiconductor industry is facing increased pressure to combat counterfeiting and ensure the authenticity of parts, driven by the shift towards chiplets, multi-die assemblies, and stringent government regulations. Digital certificates and immutable physical IDs are being pushed as solutions, but their widespread adoption has been hampered by inconsistent regulations and a lack of economic incentives. New government policies, like the U.S. CHIPS Act and EU’s Cyber Resilience Act, are now mandating infrastructure for traceability, making it a prerequisite for doing business in critical sectors. This global effort aims to create a “federated trust fabric” across the supply chain, moving beyond traditional quality control to verifiable provenance.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Screenshot-2025-11-10-at-2.38.06-PM.png" alt="Global standards defining provenance, security, and interoperability"></p><ul><li><strong>Combating Counterfeiting</strong>: The industry is intensifying efforts against gray market semiconductors through digital certificates and physical IDs.</li><li><strong>Regulatory Driving Force</strong>: Government acts and policies are mandating traceability infrastructure, especially for HPC, defense, and critical infrastructure.</li><li><strong>Federated Trust Fabric</strong>: Aims to establish a global, verifiable, and interoperable semiconductor traceability framework to enhance supply chain security and unlock new economic intelligence.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/controlling-triple-quantum-dots-in-a-zinc-oxide-semiconductor/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Controlling Triple Quantum Dots in a Zinc Oxide Semiconductor</strong><br>Researchers at Tohoku University’s WPI-AIMR have achieved a significant breakthrough in quantum computing by successfully creating and electrically controlling triple quantum dots in zinc oxide (ZnO). This advancement is crucial for scaling up qubit numbers, a major challenge for practical quantum computers. ZnO is favored for its good spin coherence and strong electron correlations. The team observed the quantum cellular automata (QCA) effect, where charge configurations influence neighboring dots, leading to simultaneous electron movement—a key mechanism for low-power quantum logic. This research expands the material options for quantum computing, bringing closer the realization of stable, scalable, and energy-efficient quantum devices.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="Tohoku University Logo"></p><ul><li><strong>Quantum Dot Breakthrough</strong>: Successful creation and electrical control of triple quantum dots in zinc oxide (ZnO) for quantum computing.</li><li><strong>Scalability for Qubits</strong>: Addresses the critical need for a large number of controllable qubits for practical quantum computers.</li><li><strong>Quantum Cellular Automata (QCA) Effect</strong>: Observed a unique QCA effect in triple quantum dots, essential for low-power quantum logic operations.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ceo-interviews/363573-ceo-interview-with-roy-barnes-of-tpc/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Roy Barnes of TPC</strong><br>Roy Barnes, Group President of The Partner Companies (TPC), discussed the firm’s role in delivering precision manufacturing solutions, particularly through photochemical etching, to industries where failure is not an option, with a core focus on the semiconductor sector. TPC, comprising eleven specialty manufacturers, offers deep expertise in processes for ultra-precise thin metal parts and ceramic metallization. Barnes highlighted how TPC addresses complex engineering challenges, such as optimizing AlN heater assembly reliability, through collaborative problem-solving and rapid scaling. The company differentiates itself through an integrated manufacturing approach, leveraging adjacent technologies, and making significant investments in engineering and scaling capabilities to provide secure, IP-focused domestic solutions amid supply chain pressures.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Roy-Barnes-Headshot.jpg" alt="Roy Barnes Headshot"></p><ul><li><strong>Precision Manufacturing Expertise</strong>: TPC specializes in photochemical etching and ceramic metallization for mission-critical semiconductor components.</li><li><strong>Collaborative Problem-Solving</strong>: Addresses complex engineering challenges, like AlN heater reliability, through process expertise and rapid production scaling.</li><li><strong>Integrated Domestic Solutions</strong>: Offers a differentiated approach with integrated manufacturing, adjacent technologies, and a focus on secure, IP-protected domestic supply chains to alleviate customer concerns.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay tuned with us for the latest news and breakthroughs shaping the future of the semiconductor industry.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251117_semiconductor_newslett</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Advanced Packaging" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Advanced-Packaging/"/>
    
    <category term="Chiplets" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Chiplets/"/>
    
    <category term="Quantum Computing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Quantum-Computing/"/>
    
    <category term="Supply Chain Security" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Supply-Chain-Security/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Algorithm–HW Co-Design Framework for Accelerating Attention in Large-Context Scenarios</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251114_Algorithm%E2%80%93HW-Co-Design-Framework-for-Accelerating-Attention-in-Large-Context-Scenarios/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251114_Algorithm%E2%80%93HW-Co-Design-Framework-for-Accelerating-Attention-in-Large-Context-Scenarios/</id>
    <published>2025-11-13T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-14T05:17:57.376Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251114_machinelearning_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-manufacturers/tsmc/363007-tsmc-kumamoto-pioneering-japans-semiconductor-revival/">News</a></h2><p><strong>TSMC Kumamoto: Pioneering Japan’s Semiconductor Revival</strong><br>TSMC’s Kumamoto facility, operationalized through Japan Advanced Semiconductor Manufacturing (JASM), marks a strategic diversification of its global manufacturing footprint, being its first dedicated wafer fab outside Taiwan, the U.S., and Europe. The facility focuses on mature process nodes (22&#x2F;28nm and 12&#x2F;16nm) crucial for automotive semiconductors, image sensors, and microcontrollers.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/TSMC-Kumamoto-Fab-2.jpg" alt="TSMC Kumamoto Fab"></p><ul><li>TSMC’s strategic pivot with its Kumamoto fab diversifies manufacturing globally, bolstering supply chain resilience.</li><li>The facility focuses on mature nodes, leveraging renewable energy and creating 2,400 jobs, to support key sectors like automotive and image sensors.</li><li>Kumamoto significantly contributes to Japan’s “Semiconductor Revival Plan,” aiming to reclaim a share of global chip production, despite some infrastructure challenges for future expansions.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/silicon-photonic-interconnected-chiplets-with-computational-network-and-imc-for-llm-inference-acceleration-nus/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Silicon Photonic Interconnected Chiplets With Computational Network And IMC For LLM Inference Acceleration</strong><br>Researchers at the National University of Singapore have unveiled PICNIC, a 3D-stacked chiplet-based large language model (LLM) inference accelerator. PICNIC tackles critical communication bottlenecks by employing silicon photonic interconnections and non-volatile in-memory computing processing elements. This innovative architecture significantly enhances speed and efficiency for LLM inference.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_280279152-05-21-scaled.jpeg" alt="Silicon Photonic Interconnected Chiplets"></p><ul><li>PICNIC is a novel 3D-stacked chiplet accelerator leveraging silicon photonics for efficient LLM inference.</li><li>It integrates an Inter-PE Computational Network and in-memory computing to overcome communication bottlenecks in LLM processing.</li><li>Simulation results indicate a substantial 3.95x speedup and 30x efficiency improvement over the Nvidia A100, with further scalability to rival the H100.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/eda/synopsys/363578-lessons-from-the-deepchip-wars-what-a-decade-old-debate-teaches-us-about-tech-evolution/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Lessons from the DeepChip Wars: What a Decade-old Debate Teaches Us About Tech Evolution</strong><br>A review of hardware-assisted verification (HAV) trends over the last decade reveals a dramatic evolution driven by soaring design complexity, embedded software growth, and the rise of AI workloads. Key shifts include a reversal of priorities from compile time to runtime performance, a move from multi-user parallelism to single, system-critical validation runs, and a transformation in debugging from waveform visibility to system-level insights. This evolution is summarized in a table showcasing the changing attributes of HAV systems.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Lessons-from-the-DeepChip-wars-Table.png" alt="Evolution of HAV Main Attributes"></p><ul><li>HAV priorities have shifted dramatically, favoring long runtime performance for complex software workloads over rapid compile times.</li><li>The focus of capacity utilization transitioned from running many small jobs in parallel to executing single, system-critical validation runs for massive, multi-die architectures.</li><li>Debugging techniques evolved from low-level waveform visibility to high-abstraction system-level analysis, utilizing software debuggers and protocol analyzers.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/algorithm-hw-co-design-framework-for-accelerating-attention-in-large-context-scenarios-cornell/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Algorithm–HW Co-Design Framework for Accelerating Attention in Large-Context Scenarios</strong><br>Cornell University researchers have introduced LongSight, an innovative algorithm-hardware co-design framework to accelerate the attention mechanism in large-context LLMs. LongSight utilizes a compute-enabled CXL memory device to offload the Key-Value (KV) cache storage and retrieval, effectively enabling state-of-the-art Llama models to support context lengths of up to 1 million tokens. This approach elevates the value of relatively low-cost LPDDR DRAM to that of high-end HBM.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_571576869-wave-data-10-10-23.jpeg" alt="Wave Data Flow"></p><ul><li>LongSight accelerates large-context LLMs by offloading the critical KV cache to compute-enabled CXL memory.</li><li>This framework allows LLMs to efficiently support context windows of up to 1 million tokens, enhancing output accuracy and personalization.</li><li>It effectively leverages lower-cost LPDDR DRAM to function at high-end HBM capacities for LLM acceleration.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/362807-adding-expertise-to-genai-an-insightful-study-on-fine-tuning/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Adding Expertise to GenAI: An Insightful Study on Fine-tuning</strong><br>An insightful analysis of a Microsoft study explores methods for fine-tuning pre-trained Generative AI models (like GPT-4) to embed specific expertise, such as knowledge of recent sporting events. The study compares token-based and fact-based approaches to supervised fine-tuning (SFT), concluding that fact-based training, which breaks down complex sentences into atomic facts, yields more uniform coverage and significantly improved accuracy. The article emphasizes the dynamic nature of fine-tuning, the critical role of expert review, and the ongoing challenge of achieving 100% model accuracy while mitigating issues like catastrophic forgetting.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/AI-Model-Tuner.png" alt="AI Model Tuner"></p><ul><li>Fine-tuning GenAI models is crucial for embedding specific expertise and significantly enhancing response accuracy over base pre-trained models.</li><li>Fact-based fine-tuning, by breaking down complex sentences into individual labels, demonstrates superior and more uniform coverage compared to token-based methods.</li><li>Expert human review and careful label generation are vital for building confidence in enhanced models and preventing issues like “catastrophic forgetting.”</li></ul><hr><p>Stay tuned for the latest updates shaping the semiconductor landscape!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251114_machinelearning_newsle</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Machinelearning" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Machinelearning/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor Manufacturing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor-Manufacturing/"/>
    
    <category term="Chiplets" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Chiplets/"/>
    
    <category term="AI Acceleration" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI-Acceleration/"/>
    
    <category term="Photonic Computing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Photonic-Computing/"/>
    
    <category term="Advanced Verification" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Advanced-Verification/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TSMC Arizona Begins N4 Production, Boosting Domestic Chip Manufacturing</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251111_TSMC-Arizona-Begins-N4-Production,-Boosting-Domestic-Chip-Manufacturing/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251111_TSMC-Arizona-Begins-N4-Production,-Boosting-Domestic-Chip-Manufacturing/</id>
    <published>2025-11-10T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-11T05:22:40.956Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251111_device_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="TSMC-Arizona-N4-Production-Begins"><a href="#TSMC-Arizona-N4-Production-Begins" class="headerlink" title="TSMC Arizona N4 Production Begins"></a><a href="https://www.techradar.com/pro/tsmc-arizona-starts-n4-production-signaling-us-fab-success">TSMC Arizona N4 Production Begins</a></h2><p><strong>TSMC Arizona Begins N4 Production, Boosting Domestic Chip Manufacturing</strong><br>TSMC’s highly anticipated N4 process technology has officially begun volume production at its first fabrication plant in Arizona, marking a significant milestone for domestic semiconductor manufacturing in the United States. This move is expected to bolster the U.S. supply chain for advanced chips, with initial production focused on customers like Apple and Nvidia. The ramp-up of this facility underscores the strategic importance of localized, leading-edge chip production.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/4W8hWwB6jX9Z7Qp7YQ8vP-1200-80.jpg" alt="TSMC Arizona Fab"></p><ul><li>First U.S.-based fab to initiate volume production of N4 process technology.</li><li>Aims to strengthen the domestic semiconductor supply chain and reduce reliance on overseas manufacturing.</li><li>Expected to serve major customers requiring advanced chip designs.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Eta-Compute-Rebrands-as-ModelCat-Unveils-Agentic-Model-Builder"><a href="#Eta-Compute-Rebrands-as-ModelCat-Unveils-Agentic-Model-Builder" class="headerlink" title="Eta Compute Rebrands as ModelCat, Unveils Agentic Model Builder"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/eta-compute-rebrands-as-modelcat-unveils-agentic-model-builder/">Eta Compute Rebrands as ModelCat, Unveils Agentic Model Builder</a></h2><p><strong>ModelCat Launches Agentic AI Platform for Hardware-Aware Edge AI Model Building</strong><br>Eta Compute, an AI software startup, has rebranded as ModelCat and introduced an innovative agentic AI platform designed for hardware-aware model building on edge devices. This new platform uses an AI agent to automate the complex process of creating tailored models, significantly reducing manual effort and optimizing performance for specific edge hardware constraints. The tool tests hypotheses on real hardware in the cloud, delivering models optimized for metrics like latency, energy consumption, and prediction accuracy.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Evan-Petridis.jpg" alt="Evan Petridis, CEO of ModelCat"></p><ul><li>Automates edge AI model creation using an AI agent, accelerating development.</li><li>Optimizes models for specific hardware constraints, including latency and energy efficiency.</li><li>Partnership with NXP integrates a dedicated version into the eIQ software ecosystem.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Gartner-Forecasts-Global-Semiconductor-Revenue-to-Grow-18-Percent-in-2025"><a href="#Gartner-Forecasts-Global-Semiconductor-Revenue-to-Grow-18-Percent-in-2025" class="headerlink" title="Gartner Forecasts Global Semiconductor Revenue to Grow 18 Percent in 2025"></a><a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2025-01-16-gartner-forecasts-global-semiconductor-revenue-to-grow-18-percent-in-2025">Gartner Forecasts Global Semiconductor Revenue to Grow 18 Percent in 2025</a></h2><p><strong>Gartner Projects Robust 18% Growth in Global Semiconductor Revenue for 2025</strong><br>Market research firm Gartner forecasts an impressive 18% increase in global semiconductor revenue for 2025, reaching a projected $706 billion. This significant growth is primarily driven by the escalating demand for chips in AI applications, particularly for generative AI inference and training. Memory segment recovery, especially DRAM, is also a key factor contributing to this optimistic outlook, as the market rebounds from previous downturns. The forecast underscores the pivotal role of advanced computing and memory in driving overall industry expansion.</p><p><img src="https://www.gartner.com/imagesrv/newsroom/images/semiconductors_2025_chart_illustration_30240905.jpg" alt="Gartner Semiconductor Forecast"></p><ul><li>Global semiconductor revenue expected to hit $706 billion in 2025.</li><li>AI applications, including generative AI, are identified as major growth accelerators.</li><li>Memory market recovery, led by DRAM, significantly contributes to the forecasted expansion.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Silicon-Photonic-Interconnected-Chiplets-With-Computational-Network-And-IMC-For-LLM-Inference-Acceleration-NUS"><a href="#Silicon-Photonic-Interconnected-Chiplets-With-Computational-Network-And-IMC-For-LLM-Inference-Acceleration-NUS" class="headerlink" title="Silicon Photonic Interconnected Chiplets With Computational Network And IMC For LLM Inference Acceleration (NUS)"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/silicon-photonic-interconnected-chiplets-with-computational-network-and-imc-for-llm-inference-acceleration-nus/">Silicon Photonic Interconnected Chiplets With Computational Network And IMC For LLM Inference Acceleration (NUS)</a></h2><p><strong>NUS Introduces PICNIC: Photonic Interconnected Chiplets for LLM Inference</strong><br>Researchers at the National University of Singapore (NUS) have published a technical paper detailing “PICNIC,” a 3D-stacked chiplet-based accelerator designed to significantly improve Large Language Model (LLM) inference performance. PICNIC integrates non-volatile in-memory computing (IMC) processing elements and an Inter-PE Computational Network, all interconnected via silicon photonics to address critical communication bottlenecks. Simulations show impressive results, with up to 57x efficiency improvement over Nvidia H100 in accommodating larger models.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_280279152-05-21-scaled.jpeg" alt="Silicon Photonic Interconnected Chiplets"></p><ul><li>Utilizes 3D-stacked chiplets with silicon photonic interconnects to overcome communication bottlenecks.</li><li>Integrates in-memory computing (IMC) for enhanced processing efficiency.</li><li>Achieves substantial speedup and efficiency gains for large language model inference.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="CEO-Interview-with-Sanjive-Agarwala-of-EuQlid-Inc"><a href="#CEO-Interview-with-Sanjive-Agarwala-of-EuQlid-Inc" class="headerlink" title="CEO Interview with Sanjive Agarwala of EuQlid Inc."></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ceo-interviews/363568-ceo-interview-with-sanjive-agarwala-of-euqlid-inc/">CEO Interview with Sanjive Agarwala of EuQlid Inc.</a></h2><p><strong>EuQlid CEO Details Quantum 3D Imaging for Advanced Semiconductor Metrology</strong><br>Sanjive Agarwala, co-founder and CEO of EuQlid, shared insights into the company’s proprietary quantum 3D imaging platform, Qu-MRI™. This technology provides non-destructive, high-precision mapping of buried current flow, addressing a critical unmet need in metrology for advanced semiconductor (3D heterogeneous integration) and battery design and manufacturing. EuQlid aims to fill the whitespace in inspecting buried interconnects for defects that current tools cannot reach, ensuring quality and optimizing complex manufacturing workflows.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/EuQlid-Co-founders-picture.jpg" alt="EuQlid Co-founders"></p><ul><li>Qu-MRI™ platform offers non-destructive 3D imaging of sub-surface current flow.</li><li>Addresses critical metrology gaps in advanced semiconductor and battery manufacturing.</li><li>Enables precise inspection of buried device structures and interconnect integrity.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay tuned for more cutting-edge developments and insights shaping the semiconductor industry’s future.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251111_device_newsletter_gemi</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Advanced Packaging" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Advanced-Packaging/"/>
    
    <category term="Neuromorphic" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Neuromorphic/"/>
    
    <category term="Quantum Computing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Quantum-Computing/"/>
    
    <category term="Edge AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Edge-AI/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Omdia- Display Glass Revenue Reached a Record High of JPY 270 Billion in 3Q 2025</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251110_Omdia--Display-Glass-Revenue-Reached-a-Record-High-of-JPY-270-Billion-in-3Q-2025/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251110_Omdia--Display-Glass-Revenue-Reached-a-Record-High-of-JPY-270-Billion-in-3Q-2025/</id>
    <published>2025-11-09T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-10T05:19:40.452Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251110_semiconductor_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-11-crisis-chipmaker-nexperia-automakers-scrambling.html">News</a></h2><p><strong>A crisis at chipmaker Nexperia sent automakers scrambling</strong><br>A geopolitical dispute involving Chinese-owned Dutch chipmaker Nexperia has disrupted the global automotive supply chain. The Dutch government invoked a rarely used law to assert control over Nexperia due to national security concerns, leading to the ousting of its Chinese CEO. In response, China blocked exports of Nexperia chips from its Dongguan plant, severely impacting automakers like Honda, Ford, General Motors, Nissan, and Mercedes-Benz, who rely on Nexperia’s discrete chips for essential vehicle functions.</p><ul><li>Dutch government asserted control over Nexperia, citing national security and “governance shortcomings.”</li><li>China retaliated by blocking chip exports from Nexperia’s Chinese factory, causing major disruptions for global automakers.</li><li>The crisis highlights semiconductor supply chain vulnerabilities and the impact of geopolitical tensions on critical industries.</li></ul><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/a-crisis-at-chipmaker.jpg" alt="A crisis at chipmaker Nexperia"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/eta-compute-rebrands-as-modelcat-unveils-agentic-model-builder/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Eta Compute Rebrands as ModelCat, Unveils Agentic Model Builder</strong><br>AI software startup Eta Compute has rebranded as ModelCat and launched a new hardware-aware model building platform for edge devices, leveraging agentic AI. This platform uses an AI agent to automate the creation of models tailored to specific edge hardware constraints, significantly reducing the manual effort in the development cycle. ModelCat has partnered with NXP to integrate a dedicated version of the tool into NXP’s eIQ software ecosystem, and its cloud platform supports various edge hardware from NXP, STMicroelectronics, Silicon Labs, Qualcomm, and others for real-world testing.</p><ul><li>ModelCat’s platform uses agentic AI to automate hardware-aware model creation for edge devices.</li><li>The tool significantly reduces development time by testing models on real hardware in the cloud.</li><li>Partnership with NXP extends its reach into the eIQ software ecosystem for NXP hardware targets.</li></ul><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Evan-Petridis.jpg" alt="Evan Petridis, CEO of ModelCat"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/omdia-display-glass-revenue-reached-a-record-high-of-jpy-270-billion-in-3q-2025/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Omdia: Display Glass Revenue Reached a Record High of JPY 270 Billion in 3Q 2025</strong><br>According to Omdia, display glass revenue hit a record JPY 270 billion in Q3 2025, marking a 5% quarter-over-quarter and 14% year-over-year increase. This growth is driven by both increased prices and demand, reflecting a strategic shift by major glass makers towards profitability after a decade of intense competition. Since 2022, prices have risen over 25% as companies manage production capacity and avoid new tank investments, focusing instead on efficiency. Chinese glass makers, however, continue aggressive investments, particularly in G8.5 glass tanks, and are expected to gain market share long-term. Major glass makers are also exploring new business areas, including glass for the semiconductor industry (TGV, support glass).</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/quarterly-display-glass-revenue.png" alt="Quarterly Display Glass Revenue"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/lithography/363425-predicting-stochastic-euv-defect-density-with-electron-noise-and-resist-blur-models/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Predicting Stochastic EUV Defect Density with Electron Noise and Resist Blur Models</strong><br>New research explores the impact of secondary electron noise on defect probability in Extreme Ultraviolet (EUV) lithography, utilizing updated blur models for chemically amplified (CAR) and metal oxide (MOR) resists. The study highlights that resist blur significantly degrades contrast, affecting defect probability calculations. It reveals that EUV exposures are exponentially more defective than ArF immersion lithography, with edge defects being the most likely due to proximity to feature edges. As lithography pitches shrink, resist blur and electron noise are becoming more critical than optical parameters, indicating the growing necessity for advanced techniques like multipatterning to manage defectivity in future semiconductor manufacturing.</p><ul><li>Secondary electron noise and resist blur are key factors in EUV lithography defect probability.</li><li>EUV exposures exhibit exponentially higher defectivity compared to ArF immersion.</li><li>As pitches shrink, resist blur and electron noise are now more critical than optical parameters, necessitating advanced patterning.</li></ul><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Predicting-Stochastic-EUV-1.png" alt="Predicting Stochastic EUV Defect Density"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/moving-ai-workloads-to-the-edge/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Moving AI Workloads To The Edge</strong><br>Industry experts discussed the growing trend of moving AI workloads from the cloud to the edge, driven by crucial factors such as consistent performance, reduced network reliance, lower cloud computing costs, and enhanced data privacy. The panel emphasized that while AI training remains compute-intensive in the cloud, inference is increasingly shifting to edge devices like phones, wearables, and autonomous vehicles, utilizing specialized NPUs and TPUs. This shift also addresses security concerns by keeping sensitive data localized, vital for corporate IP and applications where latency is critical, such as autonomous driving and security monitoring. The discussion highlighted a hybrid model where cloud and edge solutions complement each other, with edge AI enabling new, efficient, and secure user experiences.</p><ul><li>Key drivers for edge AI include consistent performance, privacy, reduced latency, and lower cloud costs.</li><li>Edge devices are increasingly handling AI inference with specialized NPUs and TPUs.</li><li>Hybrid cloud-edge models are emerging, enabling new applications and enhancing security for sensitive data.</li></ul><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Screenshot-2025-11-05-at-2.11.35-PM.png" alt="Experts discuss Moving AI Workloads To The Edge"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more essential updates as the semiconductor industry continues to innovate and adapt to evolving technological demands.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251110_semiconductor_newslett</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Advanced Packaging" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Advanced-Packaging/"/>
    
    <category term="EUV Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/EUV-Lithography/"/>
    
    <category term="Edge AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Edge-AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Supply Chain" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Supply-Chain/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Penn State and NIWC Develop Three-Terminal Memtransistors for Edge AI</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251107_Penn-State-and-NIWC-Develop-Three-Terminal-Memtransistors-for-Edge-AI/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251107_Penn-State-and-NIWC-Develop-Three-Terminal-Memtransistors-for-Edge-AI/</id>
    <published>2025-11-06T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-07T05:20:50.414Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251107_machinelearning_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-manufacturers/intel/362972-intel-to-compete-with-broadcom-and-marvell-in-the-lucrative-asic-business/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Intel Enters Lucrative ASIC Business, Forms Central Engineering Group</strong><br>Intel is strategically entering the custom Application-Specific Integrated Circuit (ASIC) market, historically dominated by companies like Broadcom and Marvell. This move involves establishing a new Central Engineering Group to enhance engineering execution, leverage Intel’s x86 IP, and offer design services to external customers. The global ASIC market, valued at over $20 billion in 2025, is projected to double in five years due to demand from AI, edge computing, and 5G&#x2F;6G. Intel’s approach is to offer custom ASICs centered around Intel&#x2F;NVIDIA IP using Intel Foundry manufacturing and packaging.</p><ul><li>Intel forms a Central Engineering Group to spearhead a new ASIC and design services business.</li><li>Aims to leverage core x86 IP and Intel Foundry capabilities for purpose-built silicon.</li><li>Targets the rapidly growing $20B+ ASIC market, driven by AI and edge computing demand.</li></ul><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Lip-Bu-Tan-Intel-1200x675.jpg" alt="Intel&#39;s Lip-Bu Tan"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/eda/363148-synopsys-and-nvidia-forge-ai-powered-future-for-chip-design-and-multiphysics-simulation/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Synopsys and NVIDIA Deepen Partnership for AI-Powered Chip Design</strong><br>Synopsys and NVIDIA are expanding their three-decade collaboration, integrating Synopsys’ software with NVIDIA’s agentic AI, GPU-accelerated computing, and AI-driven physics simulations. This partnership aims to revolutionize semiconductor design by transforming AI into a collaborative design partner. Key initiatives include fusing Synopsys’ AgentEngineer™ with NVIDIA’s NeMo Agent Toolkit for autonomous design flows and leveraging NVIDIA GPUs for up to 500x speedup in fluid simulations and 15x gains in atomistic simulations. This targets faster iterations, reduced energy consumption, and scalable simulations for advanced nodes and complex systems.</p><ul><li>Partnership integrates Synopsys’ tools with NVIDIA’s agentic AI, GPU-accelerated computing, and AI physics.</li><li>Aims to transform AI into a collaborative partner for autonomous design flows, enhancing productivity.</li><li>Promises significant performance speedups (e.g., 500x in fluid simulations) across EDA and simulation workloads.</li></ul><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Synopsys-Nvidia-Agentic-AI-2025-1200x662.jpg" alt="Synopsys Nvidia Agentic AI"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/362941-ai-rtl-generation-versus-ai-rtl-verification/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>The High Cost of Verification: AI’s Untapped Potential</strong><br>Industry analysis consistently shows that over 50% of IC&#x2F;ASIC project time is dedicated to verification, requiring as many verification engineers as design engineers. Debugging alone accounts for a substantial 47% of this verification effort, making it a prime area for efficiency improvements. While AI-generated RTL currently sees an acceptance rate of only around 25%, indicating limitations in reliability and complexity, agentic AI approaches hold significant promise for enhancing verification processes, particularly in bug triage and root-cause analysis, where substantial ROI can be realized.</p><ul><li>Over 50% of IC&#x2F;ASIC project time is spent on verification, matching design time.</li><li>Debugging consumes 47% of all verification effort, presenting a major efficiency challenge.</li><li>Agentic AI offers significant ROI potential in bug triage and root-cause analysis for verification.</li></ul><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/RTL-generation-vs-RTL-Verification.jpg" alt="RTL Generation vs. RTL Verification"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/three-terminal-memtransistors-for-decentralized-edge-applications-penn-state-niwc/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Penn State and NIWC Develop Three-Terminal Memtransistors for Edge AI</strong><br>Researchers from Penn State University and Naval Information Warfare Center Pacific have developed large-scale crossbar arrays based on three-terminal MoS2 memtransistors. These novel devices are designed for efficient, low-power inference engines in edge AI applications. Unlike traditional memristive crossbars, these memtransistors can dynamically tune conductance via gate control, effectively resolving similar outputs and enhancing separability without retraining. The technology demonstrates high yield (&gt;92%), low write energies (~0.2 fJ), and projected retention exceeding three years, validating performance with MNIST digit classification.</p><ul><li>New MoS2 memtransistors offer dynamic conductance tuning via gate control for enhanced inference.</li><li>Achieve high yield (&gt;92%), low write energies (~0.2 fJ), and long retention (&gt;3 years).</li><li>Aims to improve separability in edge AI applications without costly retraining.</li></ul><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/Blue-AdobeStock_137033829-12-20.jpeg" alt="Decentralized Edge Applications"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/362678-a-compelling-differentiator-in-oem-product-design/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Redefining OEM Component Discovery with Interactive Digital Tools</strong><br>The semiconductor industry is seeing a shift in how component manufacturers engage with OEM hardware designers. A new approach emphasizes interactive digital tools and AI-powered chatbots to streamline component discovery, replacing cumbersome datasheet reviews. Manufacturers are offering interactive reference designs, allowing designers to experiment with parameters and view impacts on behavior directly. This “engineering outreach” provides access to schematics, PCB layouts, and BOMs, alongside supply chain and compliance information, fostering early design commitment and manufacturer stickiness before traditional sales engagement.</p><ul><li>New models use interactive tools and AI to simplify component discovery for OEMs.</li><li>Designers can experiment with virtual reference designs, schematics, and BOMs.</li><li>Aims to foster early design wins and manufacturer loyalty through enhanced digital engagement.</li></ul><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/PartQuest.png" alt="PartQuest"></p><hr><p>Stay connected with us for the latest developments shaping the future of the semiconductor industry.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251107_machinelearning_newsle</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Machinelearning" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Machinelearning/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI Chip Design" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI-Chip-Design/"/>
    
    <category term="Advanced Memory" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Advanced-Memory/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor Strategy" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor-Strategy/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TEL to Highlight Sustainability Through Digitization and AI at SEMICON Europa 2025</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251106_TEL-to-Highlight-Sustainability-Through-Digitization-and-AI-at-SEMICON-Europa-2025/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251106_TEL-to-Highlight-Sustainability-Through-Digitization-and-AI-at-SEMICON-Europa-2025/</id>
    <published>2025-11-05T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-06T05:16:26.327Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251106_etch_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/kerala-positions-design-and-ip-at-core-of-chip-strategy/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Kerala Positions Design and IP at Core of Chip Strategy</strong><br>The Indian state of Kerala has unveiled its Vision 2031 framework, charting a design-first semiconductor roadmap. Instead of investing heavily in multi-billion-dollar fabs, the state aims to focus on chip design, testing, and IP creation. This strategy leverages Kerala’s strong academic base to build design-centric clusters, expand hardware incubation centers, and retain intellectual property within India. The plan seeks to create half a million IT jobs and grow the sector’s economic output to $49.7 billion by 2031.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Feature-Image-Recode-Kerala.jpg" alt="Feature Image Recode Kerala"></p><ul><li>Kerala prioritizes chip design, testing, and IP creation over fab construction.</li><li>The strategy aims to create 500,000 IT jobs and boost economic output by 2031.</li><li>Leverages academic strengths to build design-centric clusters and retain IP in India.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.gsmarena.com/qualcomm_snapdragon_8_gen_4_unveiling_is_expected_on_october_24-news-60317.php">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Gen 4 Unveiling is Expected on October 24</strong><br>Qualcomm is set to unveil its next-generation flagship mobile platform, the Snapdragon 8 Gen 4, on October 24. This highly anticipated chip is expected to power premium Android smartphones in 2025, bringing significant advancements in performance, AI capabilities, and power efficiency. The launch event is slated to showcase Qualcomm’s latest innovations in mobile processing, aiming to set new benchmarks for the industry and enhance user experiences across various high-end devices.</p><p><img src="https://fdn.gsmarena.com/imgroot/news/23/10/snapdragon-8-gen-4-october-24/-1200x900m/gsmarena_001.jpg" alt="Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Gen 4"></p><ul><li>Qualcomm to unveil its Snapdragon 8 Gen 4 mobile platform on October 24.</li><li>The new chip is expected to deliver significant performance and AI enhancements.</li><li>Aims to power premium Android smartphones in 2025, setting new industry benchmarks.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://newsroom.lamresearch.com/overcoming-beol-patterning-challenges-at-the-3-nm-node?blog=true">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Overcoming BEOL Patterning Challenges at the 3-NM Node</strong><br>At the 3-nm node, achieving precise interconnect critical dimensions (CD) and pitch for metal dimensions below 18 nm poses significant challenges, particularly in controlling Edge Placement Error (EPE). Through virtual fabrication and Monte Carlo simulations using SEMulator3D®, Lam Research identified critical process parameters and optimal process windows needed to manage EPE variability and line CD control. The analysis showed that only a small percentage of simulated runs met minimum line CD criteria, highlighting the importance of tightly controlling process parameters for successful patterning in advanced BEOL technologies.</p><p><img src="https://assets.newsroom.lamresearch.com/m/6a793a38c92a6b29/original/blog-overcoming-beol-patterning-challenges-at-the-3-nm-node-5.jpg" alt="Minimum line CD process window to meet minimum line CD success criteria"></p><ul><li>BEOL patterning at 3nm faces critical challenges with interconnect CD and EPE.</li><li>Virtual fabrication identified key process parameters and windows for EPE control.</li><li>Only 9.75% of simulated runs met line CD success criteria, emphasizing strict process control.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-today.com/news_items/2025/oct/ucas-301025.shtml">Research</a></h2><p><strong>P-type Layer Etch for Enhanced Deep UV LEDs to Boost Efficiency</strong><br>Researchers in China have demonstrated an innovative method to enhance the performance of aluminium gallium nitride (AlGaN) deep ultraviolet (DUV) light-emitting diodes (LEDs) by carefully etching away DUV-absorbing p-type layers. This technique aims to increase light-extraction efficiency (LEE) without significantly compromising internal quantum efficiency (IQE) or carrier injection. The team found that an optimal etch depth can lead to improved light output power and wall-plug efficiency, crucial for developing more efficient DUV sources for sterilization and medical applications.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-today.com/news_items/2025/oct/25103_ucas_f2.jpg" alt="Schematics of DUV-LEDs with etched p-type layer"></p><ul><li>P-type layer etching enhances DUV-LED light extraction efficiency.</li><li>Balancing etch depth is crucial to prevent IQE reduction and increased resistance.</li><li>Optimal etching shows improved light output power and wall-plug efficiency.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.tel.com/news/event/2025/20251105_001.html">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>TEL to Highlight Sustainability Through Digitization and AI at SEMICON Europa 2025</strong><br>At SEMICON Europa 2025, Tokyo Electron (TEL) will present on “Enabling Sustainability through Digitization and AI.” Kaushik Kumar will discuss how the semiconductor market, projected to reach $1 trillion by 2030 driven by AI, faces increasing complexities in device structures. The presentation will explore how semiconductor production equipment makers like TEL can leverage AI to manage these challenges sustainably, improve operational efficiency, and support Net-Zero objectives amidst rising development costs and extended timelines.</p><p><img src="https://www.tel.com/news/event/2025/t6kdf800000000hw-img/t6kdf800000000k6.jpg" alt="SEMICON Europa 2025 Logo"></p><ul><li>TEL to present on sustainability, digitization, and AI at SEMICON Europa 2025.</li><li>Focuses on leveraging AI to manage complexities and enhance efficiency in chip manufacturing.</li><li>Aims to support Net-Zero objectives in the semiconductor industry’s growth towards $1 trillion by 2030.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay tuned for more essential updates and analysis shaping the future of the semiconductor industry!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251106_etch_newsletter_gemini</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Etch" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Etch/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Chip Design" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Chip-Design/"/>
    
    <category term="Manufacturing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Manufacturing/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    <category term="DUV-LEDs" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/DUV-LEDs/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>proteanTecs&#39; Real-Time Health Monitoring Prevents Semiconductor Failures</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251104_proteanTecs&#39;-Real-Time-Health-Monitoring-Prevents-Semiconductor-Failures/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251104_proteanTecs&#39;-Real-Time-Health-Monitoring-Prevents-Semiconductor-Failures/</id>
    <published>2025-11-03T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-04T05:18:23.422Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251104_device_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/intel-eyeing-ai-catchup-in-inference-with-sambanova-acquisition/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Intel Eyeing AI Catchup in Inference with SambaNova Acquisition</strong><br>Intel is reportedly in talks to acquire AI processor designer SambaNova as part of a strategic shift to bolster its AI roadmap, focusing heavily on inference workloads. This move comes after Intel canceled its Falcon Shores AI accelerator and announced the “Crescent Island” GPU for inference, aiming for a “system-level solution at rack scale.” SambaNova specializes in AI hardware and software stacks, particularly reconfigurable dataflow unit (RDU) chips optimized for large-scale inference by mapping neural network graphs directly into hardware, reducing memory movement overhead.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_283632950_Editorial_Use_Only.jpeg" alt="Intel SambaNova Acquisition"></p><ul><li>Intel is pivoting its AI strategy towards inference workloads and full-stack solutions.</li><li>SambaNova’s RDU chips and expertise in inference systems could significantly enhance Intel’s AI offerings.</li><li>The potential acquisition highlights Intel’s renewed focus on the rapidly growing AI inference market.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/could-ntts-low-power-chip-be-a-game-changer-for-drones/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>NTT’s Low-Power Chip Revolutionizes Drone Object Detection</strong><br>NTT Research has unveiled a groundbreaking chip capable of real-time 4K video object detection at under 20W, a critical advancement for battery-powered aerial platforms like drones. Unlike conventional systems that downscale video, NTT’s chip processes 4K frames by dividing them into blocks, running parallel YOLO detection, and then fusing results with a holistic “overview” process. This maintains high-resolution accuracy while achieving remarkable power efficiency, enabling drones to detect objects farther away and classify them more accurately.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Image-4-5.jpg" alt="NTT Drone Chip"></p><ul><li>The chip performs real-time 4K object detection under 20W, crucial for power-constrained drones.</li><li>It utilizes a unique block-processing and fusion method to maintain high resolution without downscaling.</li><li>Expected to be generally available in early 2026, it promises to enhance drone autonomy, swarming, and security by reducing reliance on external data links.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/mits-survey-on-accelerators-and-processors-for-inference-with-peak-performance-and-power-comparisons/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>MIT Lincoln Lab Releases LAICS Survey on AI Accelerators and Processors</strong><br>The MIT Lincoln Laboratory Supercomputing Center has published an updated “Lincoln AI Computing Survey (LAICS) and Trends,” providing a multi-year analysis of commercial AI accelerators and processors. This survey compiles publicly announced peak performance and power consumption numbers, plotting them on scatter graphs to highlight market segments and trends. The latest update includes a new categorization of computing architectures, offering crucial insights into the evolving landscape of hardware for generative AI training and inference.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_309524207-scaled.jpeg" alt="MIT LAICS Survey"></p><ul><li>The LAICS survey offers a comprehensive overview of commercial AI accelerators’ performance and power.</li><li>It utilizes scatter graphs to visualize trends and differentiate market segments for AI hardware.</li><li>The updated survey includes new architectural categorizations relevant to GenAI.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-10-neuromorphic-prototype-patterns-traditional-ai.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Neuromorphic Computer Prototype Learns Patterns with Fewer Computations</strong><br>Researchers at The University of Texas at Dallas, in collaboration with Everspin Technologies Inc. and Texas Instruments, have developed a small-scale neuromorphic computer prototype that significantly reduces training computations. This brain-inspired hardware integrates memory storage with processing, allowing it to perform AI tasks more efficiently and with lower power consumption than conventional AI systems. A key innovation is the use of magnetic tunnel junctions (MTJs) in networks, mimicking synaptic connections to adapt and learn patterns based on Hebb’s law.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/team-builds-computer-p.jpg" alt="Neuromorphic Prototype"></p><ul><li>The prototype achieves efficient pattern learning with substantially fewer training computations.</li><li>It integrates memory and processing, inspired by brain architecture, for greater AI efficiency.</li><li>Magnetic tunnel junctions (MTJs) are central to its design, enabling adaptive learning through varying conductivity.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/analytics/proteantecs/362580-failure-prevention-with-real-time-health-monitoring-a-proteantecs-innovation/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>proteanTecs’ Real-Time Health Monitoring Prevents Semiconductor Failures</strong><br>At the 2025 TSMC OIP Forum, Noam Brousard of proteanTecs presented on “Failure Prevention with Real-Time Health Monitoring (RTHM™),” addressing the critical challenge of silent data corruption (SDC) in advanced semiconductor devices. As devices shrink and operate under intense AI workloads, traditional reliability methods fall short. RTHM provides continuous, high-coverage on-chip monitoring of performance-limiting paths using embedded Agents. It generates a “Performance Index” score, enabling proactive intervention before failures escalate, thereby safeguarding against SDC, functional failures, and system errors.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/proteanTecs-RTHM-OIP-2025-1200x615.jpg" alt="proteanTecs RTHM"></p><ul><li>SDC is a growing threat in nanoscale semiconductors and AI systems, leading to untraceable failures.</li><li>proteanTecs’ RTHM offers proactive, continuous on-chip monitoring to predict and avert failures.</li><li>The system uses a Performance Index to indicate proximity to failure, enabling timely mitigation and enhanced system reliability.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay tuned with us for the latest news and breakthroughs shaping the semiconductor landscape!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251104_device_newsletter_gemi</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Edge AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Edge-AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Neuromorphic Computing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Neuromorphic-Computing/"/>
    
    <category term="AI Acceleration" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI-Acceleration/"/>
    
    <category term="Chiplet Systems" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Chiplet-Systems/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor Reliability" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor-Reliability/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>NVIDIA, South Korea Government and Industrial Giants Build AI Infrastructure and Ecosystem to Fuel Korea Innovation, Industries and Jobs</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251103_NVIDIA,-South-Korea-Government-and-Industrial-Giants-Build-AI-Infrastructure-and-Ecosystem-to-Fuel-Korea-Innovation,-Industries-and-Jobs/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251103_NVIDIA,-South-Korea-Government-and-Industrial-Giants-Build-AI-Infrastructure-and-Ecosystem-to-Fuel-Korea-Innovation,-Industries-and-Jobs/</id>
    <published>2025-11-02T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-03T05:20:23.711Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251103_semiconductor_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/nvidia-south-korea-government-and-industrial-giants-build-ai-infrastructure-and-ecosystem-to-fuel-korea-innovation-industries-and-jobs/">News</a></h2><p><strong>NVIDIA, South Korea Government and Industrial Giants Build AI Infrastructure and Ecosystem to Fuel Korea Innovation, Industries and Jobs</strong><br>NVIDIA is partnering with South Korea to significantly expand the nation’s AI infrastructure, deploying over a quarter-million NVIDIA GPUs across sovereign clouds and AI factories. This initiative, announced during the APEC Summit, is set to fuel AI-enabled economic growth and innovation across key Korean industries, including automotive, manufacturing, and telecommunications.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="NVIDIA South Korea Collaboration"></p><ul><li>South Korea plans to deploy over 250,000 NVIDIA GPUs to accelerate sovereign AI development and bolster national AI capabilities.</li><li>Industry leaders like Samsung, SK Group, and Hyundai Motor Group are making substantial investments to build NVIDIA AI factories for advanced manufacturing and physical AI development.</li><li>Collaborations also extend to AI-RAN, 6G infrastructure, quantum computing research, and a new startup alliance to foster the nation’s AI ecosystem.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/onsemi-unveils-vertical-gan-semiconductors-a-breakthrough-for-ai-and-electrification/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>onsemi Unveils Vertical GaN Semiconductors: A Breakthrough for AI and Electrification</strong><br>onsemi has introduced groundbreaking vertical gallium nitride (vGaN) power semiconductors, setting a new benchmark for power density, efficiency, and ruggedness in applications like AI data centers and electric vehicles. Developed and manufactured at onsemi’s Syracuse, NY, fab, this proprietary GaN-on-GaN technology enables current to flow vertically through the compound semiconductor, supporting higher operating voltages and faster switching frequencies.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="onsemi Vertical GaN"></p><ul><li>vGaN technology offers superior power density, efficiency, and ruggedness for demanding AI and electrification applications.</li><li>The GaN-on-GaN design reduces energy loss by nearly 50% and allows for smaller, lighter systems by operating at higher frequencies.</li><li>onsemi is currently sampling 700V and 1200V devices to early access customers, targeting AI data centers, EVs, and renewable energy.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-services/semiconductor-intelligence/363205-u-s-electronics-production-growing/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>U.S. Electronics Production Growing Amidst Global Shifts</strong><br>U.S. electronics production has shown an accelerating growth trend over the past ten months, with the three-month average change versus a year ago (3&#x2F;12 change) increasing from 0.4% in October 2024 to 6.2% in August 2025. This growth is partly attributed to companies shifting manufacturing to the U.S., influenced by tariff policies. Despite this, employment in the U.S. electronics manufacturing sector has seen a decline. Globally, China’s electronics production remains robust.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/U.S.-Electronics-Production-Growing-1.jpg" alt="U.S. Electronics Production Chart"></p><ul><li>U.S. electronics production significantly accelerated, with a 3&#x2F;12 change rising to 6.2% by August 2025.</li><li>Despite increased production, U.S. electronics manufacturing employment decreased from 1.04 million jobs in January 2024 to 1.001 million in August 2025.</li><li>China’s electronics production maintained steady growth between 10% to 13%, indicating resilience despite global manufacturing shifts.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.imec-int.com/en/press/imec-sets-electro-optic-performance-record-thin-film-strontium-titanate-cryogenic">Research</a></h2><p><strong>imec Sets Electro-Optic Performance Record with Thin-Film Strontium Titanate at Cryogenic Temperatures</strong><br>Imec researchers, in collaboration with KU Leuven and Ghent University, have engineered thin-film strontium titanate (SrTiO₃) to achieve a record electro-optic performance at 4 Kelvin (cryogenic temperatures). Published in Science, this breakthrough demonstrates an effective Pockels coefficient of nearly 350 pm&#x2F;V with remarkably low optical loss, surpassing any other thin-film electro-optic material at this temperature.</p><p><img src="https://www.imec-int.com/sites/default/files/2025-10/header.jpg" alt="imec Thin-Film Strontium Titanate"></p><ul><li>Imec achieved record electro-optic performance with thin-film SrTiO₃ at 4 Kelvin, critical for quantum devices.</li><li>The material demonstrates a Pockels coefficient of nearly 350 pm&#x2F;V, enabling efficient light modulation with minimal optical loss.</li><li>This advance facilitates the development of smaller, faster electro-optic components for next-generation quantum interconnects, modulators, and transducers.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/even-with-ai-inroads-human-chip-designers-still-essential/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Even With AI Inroads, Human Chip Designers Still Essential</strong><br>Despite the growing integration of AI tools in semiconductor design, human engineers remain indispensable for creative, open-ended, and context-specific tasks. Experts emphasize that AI will primarily serve to augment designers’ capabilities, streamlining mundane and repetitive tasks, and accelerating optimization. However, human intuition, complex problem-solving, and final judgment in areas like architectural design, analog circuits, and safety-critical decisions will continue to be paramount.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/AdobeStock_857968898-neural-network-scaled.jpeg" alt="Human Brains and AI"></p><ul><li>AI is expected to augment, rather than replace, human chip designers, focusing on enhancing productivity in repetitive tasks.</li><li>Human expertise remains critical for high-level architectural decisions, innovative product design, and complex analog circuit development.</li><li>Final verification sign-off, safety-critical design, and handling novel problems still require human judgment, intuition, and cross-disciplinary reasoning.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay tuned for our next update, bringing you the freshest developments in the dynamic world of semiconductors!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251103_semiconductor_newslett</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Advanced Packaging" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Advanced-Packaging/"/>
    
    <category term="Chip Design" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Chip-Design/"/>
    
    <category term="GaN" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/GaN/"/>
    
    <category term="Photonics" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Photonics/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>VSORA- Inference Acceleration from the Ground Up</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251031_VSORA--Inference-Acceleration-from-the-Ground-Up/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251031_VSORA--Inference-Acceleration-from-the-Ground-Up/</id>
    <published>2025-10-30T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-31T05:18:51.194Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251031_machinelearning_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/3dic/362862-chiplets-powering-the-next-generation-of-ai-systems/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Chiplets: Powering the Next Generation of AI Systems</strong><br>The semiconductor industry is rapidly shifting towards modular multi-die designs, with chiplets projected to become a $411 billion market by 2035. This paradigm allows for dividing large SoC functions into smaller, reusable dies, integrated into a single system-in-package (SiP) to overcome traditional SoC scaling limits. Critical to this evolution are interconnect standards like UCIe and advanced packaging techniques (2.5D and 3D). Collaboration between industry leaders like Synopsys and Arm is crucial, simplifying AI chip design by focusing on interoperability, reliability, and security within evolving chiplet ecosystems.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Arm-Synopsys-at-Chiplet-Summit.png" alt="Arm Synopsys at Chiplet Summit"></p><ul><li>Chiplets are set to be a $411 billion market by 2035, driven by AI’s compute and I&#x2F;O demands.</li><li>UCIe is emerging as the preferred die-to-die interconnect standard, alongside advanced packaging techniques.</li><li>Industry collaboration, such as between Synopsys and Arm, is vital for streamlining AI chip design and ensuring interoperability.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/363023-inference-acceleration-from-the-ground-up/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>VSORA: Inference Acceleration from the Ground Up</strong><br>VSORA has engineered a novel architecture specifically for AI inference, delivering near-theoretical performance in latency, throughput, and energy efficiency for both datacenters and the edge. This fifth-generation architecture tackles the “memory wall” by employing a unified memory stage with a massive SRAM array, ensuring single-clock access to 16 million registers per core. Each core integrates 64K multi-dimensional MAC units and DSP cores, with dynamic numerical precision. The design leverages a chiplet architecture, allowing scalable configurations like the Jotunn8 for datacenters (3,200 TFLOPS FP8) and Tyr configurations for edge AI. This approach achieves processing efficiencies exceeding 50% and double the performance-per-watt of comparable solutions, simplifying development through a CUDA-free compilation flow.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/VSORA-AI-CHip.png" alt="VSORA AI Chip"></p><ul><li>VSORA’s new architecture achieves near-theoretical AI inference performance by eliminating the “memory wall” with a unified SRAM array.</li><li>Each core features 16 million registers and high-throughput MAC units, supporting flexible tensor operations and dynamic precision.</li><li>Chiplet-based scalability enables configurations for both datacenter (Jotunn8) and edge AI, offering significant power efficiency gains.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/understanding-and-mitigating-column-based-read-disturbance-in-dram-chips-eth-zurich-cispa/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Understanding and Mitigating Column-Based Read Disturbance in DRAM Chips</strong><br>Researchers at ETH Zurich and CISPA have identified and characterized a new widespread read disturbance phenomenon called “ColumnDisturb” in commodity DRAM chips. Unlike previous disturbances, ColumnDisturb can affect cells across multiple DRAM subarrays by repeatedly opening or keeping an aggressor row open, inducing bitflips in cells sharing the same columns. Experimental results from 216 DDR4 and 4 HBM2 chips show that this issue affects all major manufacturers and worsens as DRAM technology scales down, with the minimum time to induce a bitflip reducing by up to 5.06x. This trend suggests ColumnDisturb will pose significant challenges for future DRAM chips, impacting refresh mechanisms and data reliability.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_362074973-security-07-23-scaled.jpeg" alt="Security Image"></p><ul><li>A new “ColumnDisturb” read disturbance affects DRAM cells across multiple subarrays, causing bitflips.</li><li>This phenomenon worsens with DRAM technology scaling, reducing the time to induce bitflips by up to 5.06x.</li><li>ColumnDisturb poses significant reliability challenges for future DRAM designs and refresh mechanisms.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/utilizing-chiplet-locality-for-efficient-memory-mapping-in-mcm-gpus-etri-sungkyunkwan-univ/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Utilizing Chiplet-Locality For Efficient Memory Mapping In MCM GPUs (ETRI, Sungkyunkwan Univ.)</strong><br>Researchers from ETRI and Sungkyunkwan University have introduced CLAP (Chiplet-Locality Aware Paging), a novel approach to enhance memory mapping efficiency in Multi-Chip Module (MCM) GPUs. MCM designs introduce memory system non-uniformity when threads access remote chiplet resources, which is sensitive to page size. CLAP addresses this by determining the optimal page size for each application, leveraging the observation that GPU applications exhibit “chiplet-locality”—specific groups of pages primarily accessed by the same chiplet. By pre-organizing these local page groups into contiguous physical frames within the accessing chiplet, CLAP creates regions that function like large pages with merged TLB entries, delivering up to a 19.2% performance improvement over previous paging schemes.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_278047901-05-25-scaled.jpeg" alt="Adobe Stock Image"></p><ul><li>CLAP optimizes memory mapping in MCM GPUs by identifying and exploiting “chiplet-locality.”</li><li>It dynamically determines suitable page sizes for applications, consolidating local page groups for efficient access.</li><li>This approach improves performance by up to 19.2% by delivering the benefits of large pages without compromising locality.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/362468-emulator-like-simulation-acceleration-on-gpus-innovation-in-verification/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Like Simulation Acceleration on GPUs. Innovation in Verification</strong><br>A new paper titled “GEM: GPU-Accelerated Emulator-Inspired RTL Simulation” by Peking University and NVIDIA introduces a novel method to accelerate logic simulation on GPUs, addressing previous challenges with GPU architectures. Paul Cunningham (GM, Verification at Cadence) highlights Cadence’s continued investment in this area, noting that GEM’s intelligent partitioning and bit-packed structure enable efficient execution on NVIDIA’s SIMT machines. Raúl Camposano (Silicon Catalyst, former Synopsys CTO) praises GEM’s innovations, particularly its “boomerang executor layer” for intra-block efficiency and multi-stage RepCut partitioning for scalability, achieving up to 9x speed-up over leading commercial simulators. While currently lacking features like 4-state logic and multi-GPU support, GEM’s open-source, software-only approach represents a significant step forward in verification efficiency.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Innovation-New.jpeg" alt="Innovation New"></p><ul><li>GEM utilizes a new GPU-accelerated approach for RTL simulation, inspired by FPGA emulators.</li><li>It achieves up to 9x speed-up over commercial simulators by optimizing logic execution for GPU architectures.</li><li>Industry leaders recognize its potential for verification efficiency, despite current limitations in full commercial feature parity.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay connected with us for the most pivotal advancements shaping the future of the semiconductor landscape!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251031_machinelearning_newsle</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Machinelearning" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Machinelearning/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Chiplets" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Chiplets/"/>
    
    <category term="DRAM" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/DRAM/"/>
    
    <category term="Thermal Management" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Thermal-Management/"/>
    
    <category term="AI acceleration" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI-acceleration/"/>
    
    <category term="FeRAM" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/FeRAM/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>L&amp;T Semiconductor and Hon Young Partner for High-Voltage SiC Wafer Development</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251030_L&amp;T-Semiconductor-and-Hon-Young-Partner-for-High-Voltage-SiC-Wafer-Development/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251030_L&amp;T-Semiconductor-and-Hon-Young-Partner-for-High-Voltage-SiC-Wafer-Development/</id>
    <published>2025-10-29T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-30T05:13:36.112Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251030_etch_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://newsroom.lamresearch.com/semiverse-solutions-preps-top-engineering-talent-for-whats-next?blog=true">News</a></h2><p><strong>Lam Research Tackles Engineer Shortage with Virtual Process Integration</strong><br>Lam Research is addressing the U.S. semiconductor engineer shortage by providing its SEMulator3D® modeling platform to educational institutions. This platform offers students virtual, hands-on experience in chip manufacturing, bridging the gap between theoretical knowledge and practical fab experience. It enables students to design, analyze, and optimize fabrication steps without physical wafers.</p><ul><li>SEMulator3D uses physics-based simulation to replicate fabrication processes like etch, deposition, and lithography.</li><li>It helps students understand the “why” behind process integration, fostering critical decision-making skills.</li><li>The platform runs on student laptops, ensuring accessibility for future semiconductor professionals globally.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/lt-semiconductor-hon-young-partner-for-650v-to-3300v-sic-wafer-development/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>L&amp;T Semiconductor and Hon Young Partner for High-Voltage SiC Wafer Development</strong><br>L&amp;T Semiconductor Technologies Ltd (LTSCT) has partnered with Hon Young Semiconductor (HYS) to develop high-voltage silicon carbide (SiC) wafers ranging from 650V to 3300V. This collaboration targets the growing demand for SiC devices in electric vehicles (EVs), renewable energy systems, and industrial applications, aiming to enhance energy efficiency through superior thermal performance and lower switching losses.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/power-modules-image-feature-image.jpg" alt="Power Modules"></p><ul><li>The partnership focuses on SiC wafers for power devices like SiC MOSFETs and Schottky barrier diodes.</li><li>SiC devices are critical for improving efficiency in EV chargers, solar inverters, and motor drives.</li><li>This collaboration seeks to ensure a stable supply and competitive pricing for global customers, fostering innovation and IP creation.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.yolegroup.com/news/power-sic-market-to-exceed-11-billion-by-2029-driven-by-evs-and-energy-transition/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Power SiC Market Poised for Significant Growth by 2029</strong><br>A recent analysis by Yole Group highlights the robust growth trajectory of the power SiC market, projecting it to exceed $11 billion by 2029. This substantial expansion is primarily fueled by increasing adoption in electric vehicles (EVs) and the broader energy transition. The report underscores the critical role of SiC technology in achieving higher efficiency and performance across various power electronics applications.</p><p><img src="https://www.yolegroup.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Yole_SiC_2024_Fig1-1024x576.jpg" alt="Power SiC Market Forecast"></p><ul><li>The market growth is driven by rising demand for SiC in EV main inverters and industrial applications.</li><li>SiC penetration is expanding across automotive, industrial, and energy sectors due to efficiency benefits.</li><li>Forecasts indicate continued high growth rates, solidifying SiC’s position as a key enabling technology.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/manufacturing-strategies-for-stretchable-synaptic-transistors/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Blueprint for Stretchable Synaptic Transistors Unveiled</strong><br>Researchers from Seoul National University have developed a comprehensive manufacturing “blueprint” for stretchable synaptic transistors, crucial for soft electronics. The review details how material selection, process flow (photopatterning, printing, lamination), and device architecture collectively determine the electro-mechanical stability and learning accuracy of these flexible devices, even under significant tensile strain.</p><ul><li>Key findings emphasize the importance of device architecture, with vertical organic transistors outperforming planar channels under deformation.</li><li>The insights advance soft neuromorphic hardware towards scalable, CMOS-compatible integration for on-skin wearables and bio-interactive prosthetics.</li><li>Challenges remain, including the need for ambipolar stretchable semiconductors and robust interfacial insulation for vertical stacking.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/physical-ai-needs-an-ecosystem/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Physical AI and Robotics Demand a Robust Ecosystem for Future Growth</strong><br>Industry experts, including Anders Billesø Beck from Universal Robots and Paul Williamson from Arm, highlight the critical need for a comprehensive technology ecosystem to drive the success of “physical AI” or “embodied AI” in robotics. While humanoid robots capture imagination, the immediate focus is on collaborative robots (cobots) for industrial automation, addressing complex, variable tasks that benefit immensely from AI-driven flexibility and software updates.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Universal-Robots-1-sq.jpg" alt="Universal Robots Cobot"></p><ul><li>AI enables cobots to handle high variability in tasks, accelerating automation in logistics and assembly.</li><li>Functional safety for AI-powered robotics is a significant challenge requiring innovation from silicon to ecosystem levels.</li><li>A strong partner ecosystem, including hardware peripherals and software plugins, is essential for integration and scaling AI deployments in robotics.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates as the semiconductor industry continues to push the boundaries of innovation and shapes the future of technology.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251030_etch_newsletter_gemini</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Etch" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Etch/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Neuromorphic" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Neuromorphic/"/>
    
    <category term="SiC" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/SiC/"/>
    
    <category term="Robotics" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Robotics/"/>
    
    <category term="STEM" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/STEM/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>DeepOHeat-v1- Enhancing 3D-IC Thermal Simulation with Operator Learning</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251028_DeepOHeat-v1--Enhancing-3D-IC-Thermal-Simulation-with-Operator-Learning/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251028_DeepOHeat-v1--Enhancing-3D-IC-Thermal-Simulation-with-Operator-Learning/</id>
    <published>2025-10-27T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-28T05:19:53.485Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251028_device_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/lt-semiconductor-hon-young-partner-for-650v-to-3300v-sic-wafer-development/">News</a></h2><p><strong>L&amp;T Semiconductor and Hon Young Partner on High-Voltage SiC Wafer Development</strong></p><p>L&amp;T Semiconductor Technologies (LTSCT) and Hon Young Semiconductor (HYS) have announced a long-term partnership to jointly develop high-voltage silicon carbide (SiC) wafers, ranging from 650V to 3300V. This collaboration aims to meet the escalating demand for SiC devices in critical sectors.</p><ul><li>The partnership targets automotive (EVs), renewable energy (solar inverters), and industrial applications.</li><li>SiC wafers provide a base for high-voltage power devices like MOSFETs and SBDs, offering lower switching losses and improved thermal performance over traditional silicon.</li><li>LTSCT, a fabless company, will leverage HYS’s SiC wafer fabrication expertise to ensure supply reliability, competitive pricing, and accelerate product development.</li></ul><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/power-modules-image-feature-image.jpg" alt="Power Modules"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/tekstart/362144-pioneering-edge-ai-tekstarts-newport-processor-ushers-in-a-new-era-of-efficient-intelligence/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>TekStart Unveils Newport, a High-Performance, Ultra-Low-Power Edge AI Processor</strong></p><p>TekStart Group’s ChipStart division has launched Newport, a groundbreaking Edge AI processor designed to bring advanced AI inference directly to where data is generated, with remarkable power efficiency. Newport delivers 65 TOPS peak performance while consuming under 2 watts.</p><ul><li>The processor addresses critical Edge AI challenges by enabling ultra-low-power, on-device learning and real-time inference, significantly reducing dependency on cloud computing.</li><li>Its versatile architecture allows seamless integration into diverse applications such as surveillance, agriculture, wearables, and industrial automation, supporting adaptive AI capabilities.</li><li>Newport is poised to power the future of agentic AI systems—proactive, autonomous, targeted, and collaborative—without the energy overhead of traditional interconnects.</li></ul><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/TekStart-Newport-Chip-SemiWiki-1200x554.jpg" alt="TekStart Newport Chip"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/thermal-simulation-and-optimization-in-3d-ic-design-intel-ucsb-cadence/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>DeepOHeat-v1: Enhancing 3D-IC Thermal Simulation with Operator Learning</strong></p><p>Researchers from Intel Corporation, University of California, Santa Barbara, and Cadence have published a new paper on DeepOHeat-v1, an enhanced physics-informed operator learning framework for fast and trustworthy thermal simulation and optimization in 3D-IC design.</p><ul><li>DeepOHeat-v1 achieves significant improvements:<ul><li><strong>1.25x and 6.29x reduction in error</strong> for multi-scale thermal patterns.</li><li><strong>62x training speedup and 31x GPU memory reduction</strong> using a separable training method.</li><li><strong>70.6x speedup</strong> for the entire thermal optimization process, effectively minimizing peak temperature through optimal placement of heat-generating components.</li></ul></li><li>The framework integrates Kolmogorov-Arnold Networks and provides a confidence score to evaluate result trustworthiness, ensuring high accuracy comparable to finite difference solvers.</li></ul><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/iStock-1441278907-11-29-23.jpeg" alt="3D-IC Thermal Simulation"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-10-memristor-ferroelectric-memory-energy-efficient.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Unified Memristor-Ferroelectric Memory for Energy-Efficient AI Training</strong></p><p>A research team from Université Grenoble Alpes, Université de Bordeaux, and Université Paris-Saclay has developed a novel memory device that unifies memristors and ferroelectric capacitors (FeCAPs) within a single stack. This hybrid approach promises significant advancements for energy-efficient training and implementation of AI systems.</p><ul><li>The memory combines the analog weight storage and energy efficiency during read operations of memristors, ideal for AI inference.</li><li>By integrating FeCAPs, it also offers rapid and low-energy updates, which are crucial for training machine learning algorithms and continuous learning in AI systems.</li><li>This breakthrough could enable more efficient edge AI, allowing AI algorithms to run directly on local hardware without heavy reliance on remote cloud servers.</li></ul><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/a-unified-memristor-fe.jpg" alt="Unified Memristor-Ferroelectric Memory"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/physical-ai-needs-an-ecosystem/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>The Growing Ecosystem Imperative for Physical AI (Robotics)</strong></p><p>Industry experts, including Anders Billesø Beck from Universal Robots and Paul Williamson from Arm, emphasize the critical need for a robust technology ecosystem to realize the full potential of “physical AI” or embodied AI in robotics. They highlight challenges and opportunities in this nascent field.</p><ul><li>AI is essential for “human-scale automation,” augmenting or replacing humans in variable tasks like logistics and complex assembly, which traditional engineering struggles with.</li><li>Functional safety for robotics is becoming increasingly complex with AI, requiring continuous innovation from silicon to ecosystem, with a focus on predictability and flexible safety capabilities.</li><li>A strong software ecosystem with commonality and interoperability is vital, allowing startups to focus on software innovation while leveraging established hardware infrastructure and support.</li></ul><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Universal-Robots-1-sq.jpg" alt="Universal Robots"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more cutting-edge developments shaping the future of semiconductors and intelligent systems.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251028_device_newsletter_gemi</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Edge AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Edge-AI/"/>
    
    <category term="SiC" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/SiC/"/>
    
    <category term="Photonics" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Photonics/"/>
    
    <category term="3D-IC" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/3D-IC/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
