<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>opensemi</title>
  
  <subtitle>we bring you the daily insight in semiconductor industry</subtitle>
  <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/"/>
  <updated>2025-07-16T04:18:28.156Z</updated>
  <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/</id>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Photonics Aids the March of Moore’s Law</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250716_Photonics-Aids-the-March-of-Moore%E2%80%99s-Law/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250716_Photonics-Aids-the-March-of-Moore%E2%80%99s-Law/</id>
    <published>2025-07-15T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-07-16T04:18:28.156Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/intel-says-its-manufacturing-tech-will-lead-the-world-by-2025">News</a></h2><p><strong>Intel: Back on Top by 2025?</strong><br>Intel has revealed an ambitious roadmap that aims to reclaim its leadership in semiconductor manufacturing by 2025. The company will discontinue the use of “nanometer” terminology, introducing new node names like Intel 7, Intel 4, and the groundbreaking Intel 20A, which will feature the innovative RibbonFET architecture for improved transistor performance and efficiency. The PowerVia technology will also enhance power delivery, promising significant advancements in the semiconductor landscape.</p><p><img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/3-side-by-side-blue-and-gold-illustrations-of-intel-s-powervia-backside-power-delivery-network-implementation.jpg?id=27084815&width=1200&height=831" alt="Intel Technology"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://spie.org/news/ais-impact-three-examples">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>AI’s Impact: Three Examples</strong><br>At the 2025 SPIE Advanced Lithography + Patterning conference, advancements in lithography systems and AI applications were showcased. ASML unveiled new lithography solutions that promise enhanced stability and measurement capabilities, while imec’s research on extreme ultraviolet lithography (EUVL) aims to improve chip yield through innovative assist features. These technologies are crucial for meeting the escalating demands driven by AI applications.</p><p><img src="https://spie.org/images/Graphics/Newsroom/2025articles/AL25_Lithography_artificial%20intelligence_920.jpg" alt="AI in Lithography"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://spie.org/news/photonics-focus/marchapril-2025/aiding-the-march-of-moores-law">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Photonics Aids the March of Moore’s Law</strong><br>The importance of photonics in sustaining Moore’s Law is emphasized as TSMC aims for products with over one trillion transistors by 2030. The article discusses the evolution of technology nodes from 20 µm in 1968 to 2 nm today, highlighting how photonics advancements and chiplet technology are essential for achieving higher transistor densities while maintaining performance improvements.</p><p><img src="https://spie.org/images/Graphics/Photonics%20Focus/V6_iss2/Fab14-920.jpg" alt="Moore&#39;s Law Chart"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2022-06-3d-electronics.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Research Allows for 3D Printing of ‘Organic Electronics’</strong><br>Researchers at the University of Houston have developed a process for 3D printing organic semiconductor devices using multiphoton lithography. This technology enables the fabrication of flexible electronic circuits, biosensors, and bioelectronics with enhanced conductivity, paving the way for applications in biomedical fields and next-generation electronics.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2022/research-allows-for-3d.jpg" alt="3D Printed Electronics"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ceo-interviews/353842-ceo-interview-with-jonas-sundqvist-of-alixlabs/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Jonas Sundqvist of AlixLabs</strong><br>Jonas Sundqvist discusses the innovative Atomic Layer Etch (ALE) technology developed by AlixLabs, which aims to reduce costs and improve yields in semiconductor manufacturing. He highlights how their APS (ALE Pitch Splitting) process provides a sustainable alternative to traditional multi-patterning techniques, addressing key challenges in the semiconductor industry as it scales down feature sizes.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/04_AlixLabs_portrait_211116-1200x800.jpg" alt="Jonas Sundqvist"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates as we continue to explore the latest trends and innovations in the semiconductor industry!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/intel-says-its-manufacturing-tech-will-</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Lithography/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="sustainability" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/sustainability/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/lithography/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Tenstorrent Acquires Blue Cheetah, Opens Chiplet Spec</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250715_Tenstorrent-Acquires-Blue-Cheetah,-Opens-Chiplet-Spec/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250715_Tenstorrent-Acquires-Blue-Cheetah,-Opens-Chiplet-Spec/</id>
    <published>2025-07-14T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-07-15T04:13:13.266Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/risc-v-solidifies-presence-in-china-as-global-momentum-builds/">News</a></h2><p><strong>V Solidifies Presence in China as Global Momentum Builds</strong><br>The RISC-V instruction set architecture is witnessing significant growth globally, with China emerging as a key player. The upcoming RISC-V Summit China 2025 in Shanghai highlights China’s contributions to the ecosystem, where major companies are investing heavily in RISC-V tools and development, showcasing a unified global maturity in its adoption.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/risc-v-china.jpg" alt="RISC-V Growth"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/tenstorrent-acquires-blue-cheetah-opens-chiplet-spec/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Tenstorrent Acquires Blue Cheetah, Opens Chiplet Spec</strong><br>Tenstorrent has made a strategic acquisition of Blue Cheetah to enhance its chiplet design capabilities. The newly opened Open Chiplet Architecture (OCA) aims to foster a diverse chiplet ecosystem, allowing for significant cost reductions in custom SoC designs and encouraging collaboration across the industry.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/chiplet-jigsaw-sq.jpg" alt="Chiplet Innovation"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/delivering-energy-for-abundant-ai-will-require-new-playbook/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Delivering Energy for Abundant AI Will Require New Playbook</strong><br>A new report from Applied Materials outlines the projected electricity demand increase due to AI and data centers, emphasizing the necessity for a coordinated approach to energy efficiency and grid modernization. The report highlights that AI could consume approximately 12% of global electricity by 2030, necessitating significant industry-wide collaboration.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Applied-Materials_delivering-sustainable-energy-ai-era-sq.jpg" alt="Energy Demand"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/photonic-sram-facilitating-electro-optic-data-storage-for-ultra-fast-imc-uw-madison-usc/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Photonic SRAM Facilitating Electro-Optic Data Storage For Ultra-Fast IMC</strong><br>Researchers at UW-Madison and USC have developed a differential photonic SRAM (X-pSRAM) that enables ultra-fast in-memory computing. This advancement addresses the limitations of traditional architectures by facilitating high-speed data operations entirely within the optical domain, thus significantly enhancing computational efficiency for AI applications.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_184389409-06-19-24-scaled.jpeg" alt="Photonic SRAM"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ceo-interviews/357846-ceo-interview-with-darin-davis-of-silicet/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Darin Davis of SILICET</strong><br>In an insightful interview, Darin Davis discusses SILICET’s innovative LDMOS architecture designed to revolutionize semiconductor IP licensing. He highlights how their scalable designs enhance performance while minimizing costs, and addresses industry challenges such as parasitic effects, demonstrating SILICET’s commitment to advancing semiconductor technologies.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Davis-Silicet.jpeg" alt="Darin Davis"></p><hr><p>Stay connected with us for the latest updates and innovations in the semiconductor industry!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eetimes.com/risc-v-solidifies-presence-in-china-as-gl</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="partnerships" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/partnerships/"/>
    
    <category term="energy" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/energy/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CEO Interview with Darin Davis of SILICET</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250714_CEO-Interview-with-Darin-Davis-of-SILICET/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250714_CEO-Interview-with-Darin-Davis-of-SILICET/</id>
    <published>2025-07-13T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-07-14T04:15:12.724Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/what-do-trumps-tariffs-mean-for-the-european-semiconductor-industry/">News</a></h2><p><strong>What Do Trump’s Tariffs Mean for the European Semiconductor Industry?</strong><br>The uncertainty surrounding potential tariffs on semiconductor imports continues to impact the European tech landscape, with companies grappling with strategic adjustments amid fluctuating costs and supply chain disruptions. The article underscores the need for advanced modeling technologies to navigate these challenges and mitigate risks.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/UK_BY_IMG_Puneet-Saxena_FINAL-scaled.jpg" alt="Trump Tariffs"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/asymmetric-power-biasing-for-critical-plasma-semiconductor-processes/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Asymmetric Power Biasing for Critical Plasma Semiconductor Processes</strong><br>Advanced Energy Industries has introduced a novel asymmetric waveform technology aimed at enhancing plasma etching and deposition processes. This innovation allows for precise control over ion energy distribution, supporting the manufacturing of smaller and more complex semiconductor devices.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Figure-2.jpg" alt="Plasma Technology"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/global-semiconductor-sales-increase-27-0-year-to-year-in-may/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Global Semiconductor Sales Increase 27.0% Year-to-Year</strong><br>Recent data from the Semiconductor Industry Association reveals a robust growth in global semiconductor sales, attributed to strong demand in the Americas and Asia-Pacific regions. The chart illustrates monthly sales trends, showcasing the industry’s resilience against economic fluctuations.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/vcsPRAsset_3390533_117690_83ce3657-c465-49b3-b17b-98f323c9453e_0-1.png" alt="Sales Growth Chart"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/breakthrough-in-atomically-thin-semiconductors-large-scale-controlled-doping-and-integration-achieved/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Breakthrough in Atomically Thin Semiconductors</strong><br>Researchers have developed a groundbreaking technique for fabricating wafer-scale, modulated-doped monolayer MoS2 films, promising significant advancements in semiconductor performance. This innovative approach enhances the electronic properties of 2D materials, paving the way for high-speed applications.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Low-Res_93.jpg" alt="Research Breakthrough"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ceo-interviews/357846-ceo-interview-with-darin-davis-of-silicet/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Darin Davis of SILICET</strong><br>Darin Davis discusses SILICET’s innovative LDMOS architecture and its implications for semiconductor manufacturing. He highlights the need for improved reliability and performance in power conversion devices, emphasizing the role of their new scalable source-side architecture in meeting industry demands.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Davis-Silicet.jpeg" alt="Darin Davis"></p><hr><p>Thank you for staying updated on the latest in the semiconductor industry. We encourage you to subscribe for more insights and innovations that shape the future of technology.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/what-do-trumps-tariffs-mean-</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="research" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/research/"/>
    
    <category term="advanced packaging" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/advanced-packaging/"/>
    
    <category term="tariffs" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/tariffs/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>ChipAgents on Automating Debug- Insights from DAC 2025 Panel</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250711_ChipAgents-on-Automating-Debug--Insights-from-DAC-2025-Panel/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250711_ChipAgents-on-Automating-Debug--Insights-from-DAC-2025-Panel/</id>
    <published>2025-07-10T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-07-11T19:07:51.378Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-services/alchip/356050-alchips-technology-and-global-talent-strategy-deliver-record-growth/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Alchip’s Technology and Global Talent Strategy Deliver Record Growth</strong><br>Alchip Technologies is making waves with a strategic focus on 2nm and 3nm technology advancements. The company is expanding its global engineering workforce in Taiwan, Japan, and Southeast Asia, preparing for a significant technology inflection with the introduction of 2nm design enablement. In 2024, Alchip achieved record revenues of $1.62 billion, driven by differentiated package engineering solutions, showcasing its leadership in advanced-node silicon.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Alchip-TSMC-2nm-N2-1200x634.jpg" alt="Alchip&#39;s Growth"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/eda/chipagents-ai/356581-chipagent-ai-at-62nd-dac/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>ChipAgents Tackles Debug with Innovative AI Solutions</strong><br>ChipAgents AI is revolutionizing the semiconductor design and verification landscape with its agentic AI technology. This innovative platform is designed to enhance debugging processes, allowing engineers to leverage natural language queries for root cause analysis, significantly reducing debug cycles and improving efficiency. The technology aims to transform how chip design and verification are approached, integrating seamlessly with existing workflows.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/ChipAgentsAtDAC-1200x675.png" alt="ChipAgents AI"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/detailed-study-of-performance-modeling-for-llm-implementations-at-scale-imec/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Performance Modeling for LLM Implementations at Scale</strong><br>Imec’s recent research presents a performance-cost modeling methodology for large language models (LLMs) that integrates advanced compute techniques with memory optimizations. This innovative framework highlights the current challenges of LLM scalability on distributed systems, offering valuable insights into performance-cost trade-offs and future compute system designs.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_1104488381-03-26-2025-scaled.jpeg" alt="Performance Modeling"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/emerging-nvm-review-of-emerging-memory-materials-and-device-architectures/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Emerging NVM: Review of Emerging Memory Materials and Device Architectures</strong><br>A comprehensive review published by Texas A&amp;M University and others explores the evolution of nonvolatile memory technologies (eNVMs). These advancements are pivotal for applications such as in-memory computing and AI, offering significant improvements in speed and energy efficiency compared to traditional memory technologies. The review discusses various eNVM materials and architectures, paving the way for future developments in memory technology.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_993766061-03-26-2025-scaled.jpeg?fit=2560,1435&ssl=1" alt="Emerging NVM"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/eda/chipagents-ai/357657-chipagents-tackles-debug-this-is-important/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>ChipAgents on Automating Debug: Insights from DAC 2025 Panel</strong><br>The DAC 2025 panel featuring ChipAgents discussed the transformative potential of agentic AI in the debugging process. Experts highlighted the challenges of fine-grained debugging and how AI can facilitate root cause analysis through natural language processing, aiming to make debugging more efficient and less time-consuming. This insight underscores the growing importance of AI in EDA and chip design.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/ChipAgents-concept-min.png" alt="ChipAgents Panel"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates on the latest advancements and innovations in the semiconductor industry. Your insights and feedback are always appreciated as we strive to keep you informed and engaged with the latest trends and technologies.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-services/alchip/356050-alchips</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Machinelearning" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Machinelearning/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="chip design" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/chip-design/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="memory technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/memory-technology/"/>
    
    <category term="EDA" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/EDA/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Nikon Announces Development of the NSR-S636E ArF Immersion Scanner</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250709_Nikon-Announces-Development-of-the-NSR-S636E-ArF-Immersion-Scanner/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250709_Nikon-Announces-Development-of-the-NSR-S636E-ArF-Immersion-Scanner/</id>
    <published>2025-07-08T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-07-09T04:54:50.769Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.trendforce.com/news/2024/08/01/news-hong-kong-kicked-off-construction-of-the-first-gan-epi-wafer-pilot-line/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Hong Kong Kicked-off Construction of the First GaN Epi-Wafer Pilot Line</strong><br>Hong Kong has launched its first ultra-high vacuum GaN epitaxial wafer pilot line, aiming to enhance its microelectronics industry. MassPhoton is set to invest HKD 200 million to develop GaN processes for optoelectronic and power devices, promising over 250 new jobs in the region.</p><p><img src="https://img.trendforce.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/31165005/San-Tin-Technopole_1_event-624x234.jpg" alt="Hong Kong GaN Pilot Line"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.nikonprecision.com/nikon-announces-development-of-the-nsr-s636e-arf-immersion-scanner/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Nikon Announces Development of the NSR-S636E ArF Immersion Scanner</strong><br>Nikon is developing the NSR-S636E ArF immersion scanner, designed for high-performance semiconductor manufacturing. This system promises superior overlay accuracy and ultra-high throughput, catering to the evolving demands of advanced semiconductor devices.</p><p><img src="https://www.nikonprecision.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/NSR-S636E_L.Hires_-1024x724.jpg" alt="Nikon NSR-S636E"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/ebeam-initiative-survey-of-semiconductor-luminaries-predicts-photomask-market-growth-and-increasing-investments-in-mask-inspection-and-multi-beam-mask-writing/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>eBeam Initiative Survey Results Predict Strong Growth in Photomask Market</strong><br>The eBeam Initiative’s latest survey shows that 100% of industry leaders expect an increase in mask revenues for 2024, highlighting the growing importance of photomasks in semiconductor manufacturing. Investments in multi-beam mask writers and inspection technologies are also anticipated to rise.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/eBeam-Initiative-2024-Luminaries-Survey-Graphic.jpg" alt="eBeam Survey"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-024-01882-5">Research</a></h2><p><strong>New Protocol Improves Photolithography Accuracy</strong><br>A new quantum lithography protocol enhances the accuracy of photolithography by addressing physical limitations. This advancement promises to improve the resolution of semiconductor devices, critical for meeting future manufacturing demands.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2013/newgrayscale.jpg" alt="Photolithography"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.appliedmaterials.com/us/en/blog/blog-posts/semiconductor-rd-leaders-share-vision-accelerating-advanced-packaging.html">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Semiconductor R&amp;D Leaders Share Vision for Accelerating Advanced Packaging</strong><br>Industry leaders discuss the challenges and opportunities in advanced packaging technology, emphasizing the need for tighter process control and the integration of heterogeneous technologies. Innovative strategies for attracting talent and improving curricula are also highlighted.</p><p><img src="https://www.appliedmaterials.com/content/dam/blog/img/2025/2025-02/adv-pkg-summit-blog-lead-1200x700.png" alt="Advanced Packaging"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more insights and developments in the semiconductor industry as we continue to bring you the latest news and trends.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.trendforce.com/news/2024/08/01/news-hong-kong-kicked-</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Lithography/"/>
    
    
    <category term="technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/technology/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="photomasks" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/photomasks/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>DAC 2025- Towards Multi-Agent Systems</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250708_DAC-2025--Towards-Multi-Agent-Systems/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250708_DAC-2025--Towards-Multi-Agent-Systems/</id>
    <published>2025-07-07T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-07-08T04:13:25.388Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/ai-startup-esperanto-winds-down-silicon-business/">News</a></h2><p><strong>AI Startup Esperanto Winds Down Silicon Business</strong><br>The AI chip startup Esperanto has announced the winding down of its silicon business, seeking buyers or licensing for its technology. CEO Art Swift cited fierce competition for talent and resources as a key reason for the closure. Despite a strong initial pipeline, the company struggled to sell its energy-efficient RISC-V chips amidst a market that prioritized other attributes. The company’s future roadmap included advanced chips that are now uncertain.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/ET-SoC-1-Chip-Stacked-Perspective-1.png" alt="Esperanto Chip"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-07-ai-cloud-infrastructure-faster-greener.html">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>AI Cloud Infrastructure Gets Faster and Greener: NPU Core Improves Inference Performance by Over 60%</strong><br>Researchers from KAIST have developed a new NPU core technology that enhances the performance of generative AI models while significantly reducing power consumption. This advancement allows AI cloud infrastructures to operate more efficiently, addressing the growing demands of AI applications like ChatGPT. The new design integrates quantization techniques for memory optimization, promising a transformative impact on AI cloud services.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2025/core-neural-processing.jpg" alt="NPU Core Technology"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/dac-2025-towards-multi-agent-systems-in-eda/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>DAC 2025: Towards Multi-Agent Systems</strong><br>At the recent DAC conference, advancements in multi-agent systems for EDA workflows were discussed. These systems improve the efficiency and effectiveness of chip design processes, showcasing a significant trend towards automation in the semiconductor industry. The discussions highlighted the need for integrating human oversight with advanced AI-driven design tools, which could reshape how semiconductor companies approach development.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Chappell.jpg" alt="DAC Conference"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/nvidia-gpu-confidential-computing-threat-model-and-security-insights-ibm-research-ohio-state/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>NVIDIA GPU Confidential Computing: Threat Model and Security Insights</strong><br>A new paper from IBM Research delves into NVIDIA’s GPU Confidential Computing, outlining its architecture and potential security vulnerabilities. The research emphasizes the importance of transparency in proprietary systems and explores how GPUs can securely process sensitive AI workloads. This work has significant implications for security in AI applications, crucial for the semiconductor landscape.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_488222178-feb-20-2024-scaled.jpeg" alt="NVIDIA Confidential Computing"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-services/344572-intel-high-na-adoption/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Intel High NA Adoption</strong><br>Intel’s adoption of High NA EUV technology marks a pivotal shift in semiconductor manufacturing capabilities. This move is set to enhance their process densities and simplify production workflows, with the first High NA tool already integrated into their Oregon fab. The insights from Intel’s strategy reflect broader trends in the industry as companies strive for technological advancements amid increasing competition.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/High-NA-EUV-Final-Pre-Briefing-Deck-4.15.24-embargoed-til-4.18-at-7am-PT-1_Page_07-1200x675.jpg" alt="Intel High NA"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned with us for the latest news and insights from the semiconductor industry as we continue to track these transformative developments.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eetimes.com/ai-startup-esperanto-winds-down-silicon-b</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="sustainability" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/sustainability/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="investment" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/investment/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Quantum Machine Learning Improves Semiconductor Manufacturing for First Time</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250707_Quantum-Machine-Learning-Improves-Semiconductor-Manufacturing-for-First-Time/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250707_Quantum-Machine-Learning-Improves-Semiconductor-Manufacturing-for-First-Time/</id>
    <published>2025-07-06T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-07-07T04:28:03.122Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/geopolitical-tensions-and-us-export-restrictions-slightly-temper-ai-server-shipment-growth-in-2025/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Geopolitical Tensions and US Export Restrictions Slightly Temper AI Server Shipment Growth in 2025</strong><br>TrendForce reports that while major North American cloud service providers continue to drive AI server market growth, geopolitical tensions and US export restrictions impacting China have slightly tempered projections for 2025. Global AI server shipments are now expected to grow by 24.3% year-on-year, influenced by evolving demand dynamics and strategic shifts among key players like Microsoft, Google, and Meta.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="image title"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ceo-interviews/356568-ceo-interview-with-dr-naveen-verma-of-encharge-ai/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Dr. Naveen Verma of EnCharge AI</strong><br>EnCharge AI has launched the EN100 chip, an analog in-memory computing solution designed for edge devices and AI inference applications. This innovative chip achieves over 200 TOPS while consuming minimal power, enabling advanced AI functionalities in energy-constrained environments. Dr. Naveen Verma emphasizes the chip’s capacity to enhance AI deployment across various applications, from IoT to sophisticated local AI processing.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Naveen-Verma-Headshot-1200x900.webp" alt="image title"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-07-quantum-machine-semiconductor.html">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Quantum Machine Learning Improves Semiconductor Manufacturing for First Time</strong><br>Recent research reveals how quantum machine learning (QML) can significantly enhance semiconductor fabrication. By applying QML to model Ohmic contact resistance in semiconductor materials, researchers achieved better performance than conventional methods, potentially revolutionizing chip manufacturing processes.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/quantum-tech-powers-se.jpg" alt="image title"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-07-robotic-probe-quickly-semiconductor-properties.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Robotic Probe Quickly Measures Semiconductor Properties to Accelerate Solar Panel Development</strong><br>MIT researchers have developed an autonomous robotic system capable of rapidly measuring photoconductivity in semiconductor materials. This breakthrough increases the pace of discovering new materials for solar cells, ultimately aiding in the enhancement of solar panel efficiency. The robot’s ability to perform over 125 measurements per hour showcases the potential for automation in materials science.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2021/semiconductor.jpg" alt="image title"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ceo-interviews/357498-ceo-interview-with-peter-l-levin-of-amida/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Peter L. Levin of Amida</strong><br>Peter L. Levin discusses the Achilles platform, a pre-synthesis tool developed by Amida to predict and mitigate vulnerabilities in semiconductor devices. This innovative approach addresses critical security challenges in semiconductor design, emphasizing the need for proactive measures in a landscape increasingly threatened by cyber risks. Levin’s insights highlight the importance of integrating security into the semiconductor manufacturing process from the outset.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Peter-L.-Levin-Headshot-2024-1200x800.jpg" alt="image title"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates and insights in the fast-evolving semiconductor industry, where innovation continues to shape the future.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/geopolitical-tensions-and-us</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor Manufacturing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor-Manufacturing/"/>
    
    <category term="Innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="Quantum Computing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Quantum-Computing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Gowri Kamarthy Explains Akara’s Essential Role in the Era of 3D Chipmaking</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250703_Gowri-Kamarthy-Explains-Akara%E2%80%99s-Essential-Role-in-the-Era-of-3D-Chipmaking/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250703_Gowri-Kamarthy-Explains-Akara%E2%80%99s-Essential-Role-in-the-Era-of-3D-Chipmaking/</id>
    <published>2025-07-02T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-07-02T22:29:45.365Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/3d-printing-breakthrough-paves-way-for-next-gen-medical-devices-and-stretchable-electronics/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Gen Medical Devices and Stretchable Electronics</strong><br>Researchers at The University of Texas at Austin have developed an innovative 3D printing method that allows for the seamless integration of soft and hard materials. This technique could revolutionize the creation of prosthetics and flexible medical devices, enabling them to mimic the natural movement of human joints. The new process uses a dual-light printing system to cure a custom resin into materials of varying hardness, enhancing design possibilities and production efficiency in additive manufacturing.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="3D Printing Breakthrough"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://newsroom.lamresearch.com/gowri-kamarthy-explains-akaras-essential-role-in-the-era-of-3d-chipmaking-counterpoint?blog=true">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Gowri Kamarthy Explains Akara’s Essential Role in the Era of 3D Chipmaking</strong><br>Lam Research has introduced the Akara tool, which employs advanced technologies to enhance plasma etching precision for high aspect ratio devices. This innovation is crucial for the manufacturing of next-generation memory and logic architectures as the industry approaches the 2 nm threshold. Akara promises atomic-level control over ion energy, significantly reducing defects and improving manufacturing outcomes for complex semiconductor structures.</p><p><img src="https://newsroom.lamresearch.com/image/Figure+1+-+Embracing+Semiverse%E2%84%A2+Solutions+Semiconductor+Virtual+Fabrication+and+Its+Applications.png" alt="Akara"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/dac-2025-agentic-ai-in-eda-is-just-getting-started-and-chiplets-are-all-the-rage/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>DAC 2025: Agentic AI In EDA</strong><br>At DAC 2025, discussions highlighted the increasing role of agentic AI in chip design, focusing on its potential to manage the complexities of modern semiconductor design. The conference shed light on the necessity of human oversight in AI-driven design processes and the need for a clear monetization strategy for AI services. The integration of AI into design workflows is expected to evolve significantly over the next year as the industry grapples with talent shortages and rising design volumes.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/DAC-2025-registration_source_DAC_sq.jpg" alt="DAC 2025 Conference"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/quantum-sun-rises-japan-gambit-for-leadership/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Quantum Sun Rises, Japan Gambit for Leadership</strong><br>Japan has announced a landmark investment of ¥1.05 trillion ($7.4 billion) in quantum technology, marking a strategic shift towards leading the global quantum industry. This initiative aims to transition from basic research to commercialization, fostering a robust ecosystem for quantum startups and enhancing Japan’s competitiveness in technology. The strategy highlights the importance of collaboration between government and industry to achieve significant advancements in quantum computing and applications.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/international-2693231_1280.jpg" alt="Japan&#39;s Quantum Strategy"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/dac-2025-agentic-ai-in-eda-is-just-getting-started-and-chiplets-are-all-the-rage/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>DAC 2025 Insights on AI and Chiplets</strong><br>Mile Ellow, CEO of Siemens EDA, shared insights at DAC 2025 regarding the future of AI in chip design, emphasizing the need for increased trust in AI tools among engineers. He anticipates that in the coming year, AI will play a more significant role in streamlining design processes, while discussions around chiplets highlighted their potential as new building blocks for computing. The conference showcased a growing interest in standardization and interoperability in the chiplet marketplace.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/DAC-2025-registration_source_DAC_sq.jpg" alt="DAC Insights"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates and insights from the semiconductor industry as we continue to explore innovations and trends shaping the future of technology!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/3d-printing-breakthrough-pav</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Etch" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Etch/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="chip design" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/chip-design/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="quantum technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/quantum-technology/"/>
    
    <category term="3D printing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/3D-printing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hardware Security Tech Can Hide and Reveal Encryption Keys on Demand</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250701_Hardware-Security-Tech-Can-Hide-and-Reveal-Encryption-Keys-on-Demand/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250701_Hardware-Security-Tech-Can-Hide-and-Reveal-Encryption-Keys-on-Demand/</id>
    <published>2025-06-30T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-07-01T18:52:09.245Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/ai-clusters-spur-optical-connectivity/">News</a></h2><p><strong>AI Clusters Spur Optical Connectivity</strong><br>Broadcom has announced its third-generation 200G&#x2F;lane co-packaged optics (CPO) product line, aimed at supporting the growing optical bandwidth requirements driven by AI workloads. With advancements in laser technology, Broadcom is integrating optical components into higher-density siliconized devices to enhance performance and reduce power consumption, responding to the demands of AI clusters and data centers.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/broadcomSTM-covercarousel.png" alt="AI Clusters"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/rapidus-siemens-join-2-nm-alliance-targeting-2027-production/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>nm Alliance Targeting 2027 Production</strong><br>Rapidus has formed an alliance with Siemens to achieve 2-nm wafer production by 2027. This partnership aims to leverage IBM’s technology and create a reference flow for design verification and manufacturing, enhancing Japan’s semiconductor capabilities and reducing reliance on China.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Rapidus-fab-under-construction.png" alt="Rapidus and Siemens"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/arm-chiplets-cant-deliver-on-tco-without-an-ecosystem/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Arm: Chiplets Can’t Deliver on TCO Without an Ecosystem</strong><br>Arm emphasizes the need for a robust ecosystem and standards in the chiplet marketplace to ensure economic viability. The current semi-custom chiplet designs can inflate overall costs, and a true marketplace approach is essential for maximizing total cost of ownership (TCO) and promoting chiplet reuse.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Eddie-Ramirez-presenting.jpg" alt="Chiplet Ecosystem"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-06-hardware-tech-reveal-encryption-keys.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Hardware Security Tech Can Hide and Reveal Encryption Keys on Demand</strong><br>Researchers at Seoul National University have developed a new hardware security technology using 3D NAND flash memory that can conceal security keys until needed. This innovation enhances data security without requiring changes to existing memory structures, making it applicable for various devices, including smartphones and IoT.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/snu-researchers-develo-27.jpg" alt="Hardware Security"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ceo-interviews/356423-ceo-interview-with-yannick-bedin-of-eumetrys/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Yannick Bedin of Eumetrys</strong><br>Yannick Bedin discusses EUMETRYS’s role in semiconductor manufacturing, focusing on quality control and inspection solutions that combat the $10-20 billion annual losses due to defective silicon wafers. He emphasizes the importance of a one-stop-shop approach to streamline processes and enhance manufacturing efficiency.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Yannick-Bedin-CEO-Eumetrys.jpg" alt="Yannick Bedin"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates as we continue to explore the latest advancements in the semiconductor industry!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eetimes.com/ai-clusters-spur-optical-connectivity/&quot;&gt;N</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductor/"/>
    
    <category term="chip design" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/chip-design/"/>
    
    <category term="optical interconnects" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/optical-interconnects/"/>
    
    <category term="quantum technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/quantum-technology/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>STMicro Advances PiezoMEMS Development in Singapore</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250624_STMicro-Advances-PiezoMEMS-Development-in-Singapore/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250624_STMicro-Advances-PiezoMEMS-Development-in-Singapore/</id>
    <published>2025-06-23T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-06-23T22:21:34.476Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/stmicro-advances-piezomems-development-in-singapore/">News</a></h2><p><strong>STMicro Advances PiezoMEMS Development in Singapore</strong><br>STMicroelectronics, in collaboration with A*STAR and ULVAC, has launched Lab-in-Fab 2.0 at its Ang Mo Kio campus, focusing on lead-free piezoelectric MEMS. This initiative accelerates the transition from prototyping to manufacturing, aiming to achieve a sustainable alternative to lead-based materials by 2027. The Lab-in-Fab model enables seamless integration of research and production, enhancing time to market for MEMS applications in consumer electronics and medical devices.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/7669543_AI4I0453_Engineer-preparing-wafer-for-analysis.png" alt="STMicro Lab-in-Fab"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-06-3d-chip-stacking-method-traditional.html">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>3D Chip Stacking Method Created to Overcome Traditional Semiconductor Limitations</strong><br>Researchers from the Institute of Science Tokyo have developed a novel 3D chip integration method named BBCube, which employs advanced bonding techniques to enhance memory bandwidth and reduce power consumption in high-performance computing applications. This innovative approach addresses traditional semiconductor limitations by stacking processing units directly above DRAM, significantly improving power supply integrity and efficiency.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/novel-technologies-to.jpg" alt="3D Chip Stacking"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/want-a-smart-factory-its-all-about-the-data/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Smart Factories Need Intelligent Components</strong><br>At the MES &amp; Industry 4.0 conference, industry leaders discussed the pivotal role of data in the evolution of smart factories. Key insights highlighted that achieving data integrity is critical for manufacturing efficiency. Notable advancements in AI integration into manufacturing execution systems (MES) were presented, demonstrating the trend towards intelligent factories capable of real-time data-driven decision-making.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Porto-MESI-Industry-4-0-Infineon_image_sq_Nitin-Dahad.jpg" alt="Smart Factory Data"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/machine-intelligence-on-wireless-edge-networks-with-rf-analog-architecture-mit-duke/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Machine Intelligence on Wireless Edge Networks with RF Analog Architecture</strong><br>A groundbreaking study from MIT and Duke University introduces MIWEN, an RF analog architecture that facilitates deep neural network inference on power-constrained edge devices. By eliminating local weight memory, this innovation significantly reduces energy consumption and enhances real-time inference capabilities in low-power environments, paving the way for more efficient edge computing solutions.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_184389409-06-19-24-scaled.jpeg" alt="RF Analog Architecture"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/sambanova-shifts-to-inference-but-leaves-cloud-to-customers/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>SambaNova Shifts To Inference, Courts Cloud Customers</strong><br>In an exclusive interview, SambaNova’s CEO Rodrigo Liang discussed the company’s strategic pivot towards inference workloads amidst a shifting market landscape. With a focus on open-source models and a robust cloud deployment strategy, SambaNova aims to support enterprises in leveraging AI for enhanced operational efficiency. Liang emphasized the importance of customization in AI models to deliver superior value and performance.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/SambaNova-SoftBank-1.jpg" alt="SambaNova"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates as we continue to bring you the latest in semiconductor innovations and trends!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eetimes.com/stmicro-advances-piezomems-development-in</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="MEMS" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/MEMS/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Novel Technologies to Advance Next</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250623_Novel-Technologies-to-Advance-Next/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250623_Novel-Technologies-to-Advance-Next/</id>
    <published>2025-06-22T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-06-22T22:22:49.739Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/novel-technologies-to-advance-next-generation-semiconductor-packaging/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Novel Technologies to Advance Next</strong><br>A team of researchers from the Institute of Science Tokyo has unveiled a groundbreaking power supply technology for 3D-integrated chips called BBCube™, aimed at high-performance computing applications. This innovation leverages a three-dimensionally stacked architecture, enabling high memory bandwidth and low power consumption. Their findings were shared at the recent IEEE Electronic Components and Technology Conference, showcasing advancements in chip integration through novel bonding techniques and adhesive materials.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="Novel Technologies"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-services/aion-silicon/356734-the-sondrel-transformation-to-aion-silicon/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>The Sondrel transformation to Aion Silicon!</strong><br>Sondrel has rebranded itself as Aion Silicon, signifying a strategic pivot towards high-performance AI-centric silicon solutions. The company is expanding its service offerings to include tighter program management and architectural assistance, focusing on sectors such as data-center AI and automotive ADAS. CEO Oliver Jones emphasizes a commitment to becoming a leading design partner in custom silicon, enhancing their capacity to meet the evolving demands of the semiconductor market.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/1747740149443.jpg" alt="Aion Silicon"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/techcet-predicts-semiconductor-ald-cvd-precursor-market-outlook-highlights-growth/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>TECHCET Predicts Semiconductor ALD&#x2F;CVD Precursor Market Outlook, Highlights Growth</strong><br>According to TECHCET’s report, the global semiconductor precursor market is set to grow at a CAGR of 10.4% through 2029, driven by advancements in sub-3nm logic and increasing demands in AI and high-performance computing. In 2024, the market is anticipated to rebound to $1.7 billion, showcasing a significant recovery in NAND and DRAM sectors and emphasizing the importance of sustainability in procurement practices.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/image1.png" alt="Market Outlook"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-06-3d-chip-stacking-method-traditional.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>3D chip stacking method created to overcome traditional semiconductor limitations</strong><br>Researchers from the Institute of Science Tokyo have developed an innovative 3D chip stacking method that addresses conventional semiconductor limitations. This method enhances power integrity and reduces energy requirements for data transmission, showcasing significant advancements in chip integration technologies that could transform future computing architectures.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/novel-technologies-to.jpg" alt="3D Chip Stacking"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/want-a-smart-factory-its-all-about-the-data/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Want A Smart Factory? It’s All About the Data</strong><br>At the recent MES &amp; Industry 4.0 conference, industry leaders emphasized the critical role of data in achieving smart manufacturing. Insights from executives at Infineon and other major players highlighted the importance of data integrity and real-time decision-making facilitated by AI. The conference showcased how advanced manufacturing execution systems (MES) are evolving to become more intelligent, ultimately driving efficiency across semiconductor manufacturing processes.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Porto-MESI-Industry-4-0-Infineon_image_sq_Nitin-Dahad.jpg" alt="Smart Factory"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates and insights in the world of semiconductors as we continue to explore innovations and market trends shaping the industry.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/novel-technologies-to-advanc</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/technology/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductor/"/>
    
    <category term="smart manufacturing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/smart-manufacturing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>EUV Tech Debuts Enhanced FALCON Photoresist Flood Exposure Tool</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250618_EUV-Tech-Debuts-Enhanced-FALCON-Photoresist-Flood-Exposure-Tool/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250618_EUV-Tech-Debuts-Enhanced-FALCON-Photoresist-Flood-Exposure-Tool/</id>
    <published>2025-06-17T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-06-17T22:19:48.714Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.trendforce.com/news/2024/12/16/news-chinas-photoresist-breaking-through-and-advancing/">News</a></h2><p><strong>China’s Photoresist: Breaking Through and Advancing</strong><br>The global semiconductor industry is witnessing significant advancements, particularly in China, where local enterprises are achieving milestones in photoresist production. Hubei Dinglong has secured orders for its advanced ArF and KrF photoresists, while Shenzhen Rongda has received approval for a RMB 244 million private placement to enhance its R&amp;D capabilities. The government’s support further accelerates the industry’s rapid development amid increasing domestic demand for semiconductor materials.</p><p><img src="https://img.trendforce.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/13074350/Dinglong-624x374.jpg" alt="Hubei Dinglong"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.trendforce.com/news/2024/10/21/news-chinas-domestic-photoresist-successfully-validated/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>China’s Domestic Photoresist Successfully Validated!</strong><br>Wuhan Taiziwei Optoelectronics has launched the T150 A photoresist, achieving mass production validation. This product, designed to compete with international standards, showcases extreme resolution capabilities and improved process tolerance. This breakthrough signifies a potential shift in China’s reliance on foreign photoresists, as domestic production ramps up in response to growing demand.</p><p><img src="https://img.trendforce.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/18175709/Fujifilm-Electronic-Materials-photoresist1.jpg" alt="Fujifilm Electronic Materials"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.trendforce.com/news/2024/11/28/news-samsung-cuts-photoresist-usage-in-3d-nand-production-boosting-cost-efficiency/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Samsung Cuts Photoresist Usage in 3D NAND Production, Boosting Cost Efficiency</strong><br>Samsung has halved its photoresist usage in 3D NAND production, optimizing manufacturing processes to improve cost efficiency. This change demonstrates significant advancements in semiconductor manufacturing techniques, particularly in enhancing the layering process of NAND flash chips while maintaining high efficiency.</p><p><img src="https://img.trendforce.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/20132248/samsung-logo-624x468.jpg" alt="Samsung Logo"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/euv-tech-debuts-enhanced-falcon-photoresist-flood-exposure-tool/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>EUV Tech Debuts Enhanced FALCON Photoresist Flood Exposure Tool</strong><br>EUV Tech has introduced the FALCON tool, a next-generation device for characterizing and diagnosing EUV resists. This fully automated system allows for rapid testing and provides critical insights into exposure mechanisms, facilitating advanced photoresist development. Its capabilities include high-throughput analysis and a range of diagnostic modules, enhancing research productivity in the semiconductor field.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/FalconMachinewLogo-scaled.jpg" alt="FALCON Tool"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.trendforce.com/news/2024/11/28/news-samsung-cuts-photoresist-usage-in-3d-nand-production-boosting-cost-efficiency/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Samsung’s Strategic Process Optimization</strong><br>An interview with Samsung’s production team reveals insights into their recent optimization strategies in 3D NAND manufacturing. By reducing photoresist usage and enhancing coating conditions, Samsung aims to lead in cost efficiency and production capabilities, setting a benchmark for the industry amid rising competition and demand for advanced memory solutions.</p><p><img src="https://img.trendforce.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/20132248/samsung-logo-624x468.jpg" alt="Samsung Production"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for our next edition where we will continue to bring you the latest and most relevant updates in the semiconductor industry!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.trendforce.com/news/2024/12/16/news-chinas-photoresis</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Lithography/"/>
    
    
    <category term="technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/technology/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductor/"/>
    
    <category term="EUV" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/EUV/"/>
    
    <category term="photoresist" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/photoresist/"/>
    
    <category term="China" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/China/"/>
    
    <category term="Samsung" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Samsung/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Photonic Processor Could Streamline 6G Wireless Signal Processing</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250617_Photonic-Processor-Could-Streamline-6G-Wireless-Signal-Processing/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250617_Photonic-Processor-Could-Streamline-6G-Wireless-Signal-Processing/</id>
    <published>2025-06-16T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-06-16T22:20:54.767Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/microns-200-billion-plan-to-reshore-u-s-production-faces-challenges/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Micron’s $200 Billion Plan to Reshore U.S. Production Faces Challenges</strong><br>Micron’s ambitious plan to invest $200 billion in reshoring memory chip production in the U.S. is met with skepticism from analysts. The company aims to enhance domestic manufacturing capabilities to produce 40% of its DRAM in the U.S. However, challenges such as lack of local expertise and stiff competition from other chipmakers could hinder success.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Micron-art.png" alt="Micron&#39;s investment plan"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/encharge-picks-the-pc-for-its-first-analog-ai-chip/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>EnCharge Picks The PC For Its First Analog AI Chip</strong><br>Analog AI startup EnCharge has launched its first product, the EN100 AI accelerator, designed for laptops and workstations. Utilizing innovative capacitor-based analog compute-in-memory technology, the chip achieves an impressive power efficiency of over 40 TOPS&#x2F;W, addressing the significant energy demands of AI workloads.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/EnChargeAI_PCI-E-sq.jpg" alt="EnCharge AI Accelerator"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-06-photonic-processor-6g-wireless.html">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Photonic Processor Could Streamline 6G Wireless Signal Processing</strong><br>Researchers at MIT have developed an optical hardware accelerator that classifies wireless signals with unprecedented speed. This photonic chip processes data at light speed, achieving significant improvements over traditional digital accelerators, making it pivotal for future 6G applications.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2024/cloud-computing.jpg" alt="Photonic processor"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-06-brain-chips-boosting-cybercrime.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Brain-like Chips are Boosting Computers and Battling Cybercrime</strong><br>Researchers are developing brain-inspired chips capable of performing AI calculations locally, enhancing the security of IoT devices against cyber threats. These ultra-fast, energy-efficient chips are poised to revolutionize smart device security by processing data on-device rather than relying on cloud computing.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2019/5-brain.jpg" alt="Brain-like chips"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/eda/silvaco/356779-silvaco-at-the-2025-design-automation-conference/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Silvaco at the 2025 Design Automation Conference</strong><br>Silvaco is showcasing innovative EDA tools and semiconductor IP at DAC 2025. The company emphasizes its advancements in analog custom IC design, aimed at improving AI and efficiency across various applications. Attendees can engage in technical presentations and interactive sessions to explore cutting-edge developments.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/62nd-DAC-SemiWiki-6.jpg" alt="Silvaco at DAC"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates as we continue to track the latest advancements in the semiconductor industry!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eetimes.com/microns-200-billion-plan-to-reshore-u-s-p</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Global Semiconductor Sales Increase 2.5% Month</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250616_Global-Semiconductor-Sales-Increase-2.5%-Month/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250616_Global-Semiconductor-Sales-Increase-2.5%-Month/</id>
    <published>2025-06-15T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-06-15T22:22:23.302Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/global-semiconductor-sales-increase-2-5-month-to-month-in-april/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Global Semiconductor Sales Increase 2.5% Month</strong><br>The Semiconductor Industry Association (SIA) reported that global semiconductor sales reached $57.0 billion in April 2025, marking a 2.5% increase from March and a 22.7% year-over-year growth. The rise is attributed to heightened demand across the Americas and Asia Pacific, driven by AI technologies and advanced consumer electronics. Forecasts indicate a projected annual growth rate of 11.2%, reaching $700.9 billion by year-end.</p><p>![SIA Sales Graph](<a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Screenshot-2025-06-13-at-10.44.08">https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Screenshot-2025-06-13-at-10.44.08</a> AM.png)</p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/encharge-picks-the-pc-for-its-first-analog-ai-chip/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>EnCharge Picks The PC For Its First Analog AI Chip</strong><br>EnCharge AI has launched its first product, the EN100 AI accelerator, designed for client devices such as laptops and workstations. This analog AI accelerator utilizes capacitor-based compute-in-memory technology, achieving a power efficiency of over 40 TOPS&#x2F;W, and aims to meet the increasing demand for efficient AI processing.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/EnChargeAI_PCI-E-sq.jpg" alt="EnCharge AI Accelerator"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/eda/amiq-eda/356722-amiq-eda-at-the-2025-design-automation-conference/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>AMIQ EDA Unveils New AI Assistant for Design Tools</strong><br>AMIQ EDA’s latest enhancements to their Design and Verification Tools IDE family include an AI Assistant feature aimed at simplifying code generation and modification. The IDE now incorporates over 30 new code checks and improved testbench elaboration, ensuring higher code quality. This marks a significant advancement in hardware design, showcasing the integration of AI into development tools.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/62nd-DAC-SemiWiki-6.jpg" alt="AMIQ EDA"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/creating-the-building-blocks-of-technology-multiple-rings-at-a-time/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Creating the Building Blocks of Technology, Multiple Rings at a Time</strong><br>A team from Nagoya University has developed a new technique for synthesizing complex polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) used in organic electronics. This method utilizes direct carbon-to-carbon bond formation, vastly improving efficiency and reducing costs in creating essential components for LEDs and solar cells, with implications for enhancing semiconductor device production.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="Research on PAHs"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ip/agile-analog/356586-ceo-interview-with-krishna-anne-of-agile-analog/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Krishna Anne of Agile Analog</strong><br>In a recent interview, Krishna Anne discussed Agile Analog’s innovative approach to combat the analog engineer shortage through automation in mixed-signal IP design. He emphasized the company’s focus on strategic partnerships and integrated solutions, highlighting their potential to simplify and expedite analog design processes, thus addressing a critical industry challenge.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Agile-Analog-Krishna-Anne-headshot-photo.png" alt="Krishna Anne"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates and insights from the semiconductor industry as we continue to track trends, innovations, and breakthroughs shaping the future!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/global-semiconductor-sales-i</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="Growth" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Growth/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor Design" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor-Design/"/>
    
    <category term="EDA" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/EDA/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Aware Programming in ReRAM- Evaluating and Optimizing Write Termination</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250603_Aware-Programming-in-ReRAM--Evaluating-and-Optimizing-Write-Termination/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250603_Aware-Programming-in-ReRAM--Evaluating-and-Optimizing-Write-Termination/</id>
    <published>2025-06-02T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-06-03T14:04:40.819Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/nxps-edge-llm-strategy-kinara-rag-agents/">News</a></h2><p><strong>NXP’s Edge LLM Strategy: Kinara, RAG, Agents</strong><br>NXP has unveiled its strategy for enabling large language model (LLM) inference on edge devices at the Embedded Vision Summit 2025. The company announced the acquisition of AI accelerator startup Kinara, whose Ara-2 chip enhances LLM performance. With the introduction of GenAI Flow, NXP aims to optimize edge applications by integrating RAG techniques to provide contextual awareness to LLMs, crucial for sectors like automotive and healthcare.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/industrial.jpg" alt="NXP Edge LLM Strategy"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/news-highlights-from-embedded-vision-summit-2025/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>News Highlights from Embedded Vision Summit 2025</strong><br>The Embedded Vision Summit showcased numerous advancements in edge AI technologies. MemryX was awarded for its MX3 M.2 AI accelerator module, which combines ease of use with efficient performance. Nota AI demonstrated its collaboration with Qualcomm, revealing its enhanced AI model optimization platform. SiMa.ai and Wind River introduced a powerful integrated edge AI solution, while Vision Components presented a modular MIPI bricks system for embedded vision applications.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/embedded-vision-summit-featured-image-speaker_source_embedded-vision-summit.jpg" alt="Embedded Vision Summit Highlights"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ip/weebit-nano/356372-relaxation-aware-programming-in-reram-evaluating-and-optimizing-write-termination/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Aware Programming in ReRAM: Evaluating and Optimizing Write Termination</strong><br>The research highlights the advancements in Resistive RAM (ReRAM) technology, particularly in managing conductance drift through voltage overdrive techniques. This method stabilizes memory performance while maintaining energy efficiency, showcasing potential improvements in neuromorphic computing applications. The findings illustrate the balance between energy consumption and stability, crucial for future memory technologies.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Im1_Weebit-Relaxation-Aware-Programming-in-ReRAM-Optimizing-Write-Termination-RRAM-1024x704.png" alt="ReRAM Performance Chart"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/roadmap-for-ai-hw-development-with-the-role-of-photonic-chips-in-supporting-future-llms-cuhk-nus-uiuc-berkeley/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Roadmap for AI HW Development, With The Role of Photonic Chips In Supporting Future LLMs</strong><br>A collaborative research paper explores the future of AI computing hardware, emphasizing the role of photonic chips in supporting next-generation large language models (LLMs). The paper outlines the need for innovative computing paradigms, including integrated photonic neural networks and neuromorphic devices, to meet the growing demands of AI models, which are projected to require significant power resources.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_482095378-08-06-24.jpeg?fit=1200,672&ssl=1" alt="Photonic Chips in AI Hardware"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/eda/breker-verification-systems/356315-breker-verification-systems-at-the-2025-design-automation-conference/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Breker Verification Systems at the 2025 Design Automation Conference</strong><br>Breker Verification Systems showcased its Synthesis and SystemVIP library at DAC 2025, emphasizing the need for advanced verification methodologies in semiconductor design. The solutions presented focus on enhancing verification coverage for complex applications, including AI accelerators and RISC-V cores. Breker’s AI-driven test suite synthesis aims to streamline the testing process, crucial for developing robust semiconductor solutions.</p><p><img src="/opensemi/nan" alt="DAC 2025 Demonstrations"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates and insights from the semiconductor industry as we continue to track innovations and advancements shaping the future of technology.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eetimes.com/nxps-edge-llm-strategy-kinara-rag-agents/</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="photonics" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/photonics/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="memory technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/memory-technology/"/>
    
    <category term="edge computing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/edge-computing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>VLSI Technology Symposium – Intel Describes i3 Process</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250601_VLSI-Technology-Symposium-%E2%80%93-Intel-Describes-i3-Process/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250601_VLSI-Technology-Symposium-%E2%80%93-Intel-Describes-i3-Process/</id>
    <published>2025-05-31T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-06-01T04:03:39.685Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/middle-east-expects-ai-gains-from-u-s-deals/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Middle East Expects AI Gains from U.S. Deals</strong><br>The Middle East is witnessing a surge in technological investments, particularly in AI, fueled by significant deals announced during U.S. President Biden’s recent tour. Major commitments include $600 billion from Saudi Arabia and $200 billion in new U.S.-UAE agreements, aimed primarily at establishing robust data center infrastructures to support burgeoning AI demands. Notably, the region is also cultivating a semiconductor ecosystem, with fabless design houses and initiatives like the HUMAIN project in Saudi Arabia seeking to enhance local capabilities. </p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/President-Trump-Saudi-US-investment-forum_source_-The-White-House.jpg" alt="Middle East Tech Investments"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-05-supercomputer-nobel-laureate-jennifer-doudna.html">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>U.S. Supercomputer Named After Nobel Laureate Jennifer Doudna to Power AI and Scientific Research</strong><br>A new supercomputer, named after Nobel Prize winner Jennifer Doudna, is set to enhance AI research and genomic studies at the Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory. Scheduled to go live next year, this groundbreaking system aims to bolster the capabilities of AI technologies and scientific discoveries, marking a significant investment in advanced computing resources to address critical research challenges.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/us-supercomputer-named.jpg" alt="Supercomputer Development"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-services/349292-5-expectations-for-the-memory-markets-in-2025/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>5 Expectations for the Memory Markets in 2025</strong><br>TechInsights anticipates substantial growth in the memory markets, primarily driven by AI technologies. A notable focus is on High-Bandwidth Memory (HBM), with shipments projected to grow by 70% year-over-year, significantly reshaping the DRAM landscape. The report illustrates key trends affecting memory demand, including the rise of AI workloads and capital expenditure shifts towards DRAM production, emphasizing the intertwined evolution of memory and semiconductor technologies.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Expectations-for-the-Memory-Markets-in-2025-1200x675.jpg" alt="Memory Market Trends"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/3dic/356342-synopsys-addresses-the-test-barrier-for-heterogeneous-integration/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Synopsys Addresses the Test Barrier for Heterogeneous Integration</strong><br>Synopsys has unveiled advanced methodologies to tackle the complexities of heterogeneous chip designs, essential for next-gen AI and HPC applications. Their innovative High-Speed Test GPIOs (HSGPIO) allow efficient testing of chiplets while maintaining signal integrity. This research addresses the critical need for high-bandwidth interfaces in multi-die packaging, positioning Synopsys at the forefront of enhancing heterogeneous integration in semiconductor design.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Synopsys-Addresses-the-Test-Barrier-for-Heterogeneous-Integration.jpg" alt="Heterogeneous Integration Testing"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-manufacturers/intel/346992-vlsi-technology-symposium-intel-describes-i3-process-how-does-it-measure-up/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>VLSI Technology Symposium – Intel Describes i3 Process</strong><br>At the recent VLSI Technology Symposium, Intel detailed its upcoming i3 process, which promises to achieve an impressive transistor density of 148 million transistors per millimeter squared. This advancement is set to enhance performance across various applications, including AI and high-performance computing. Intel’s proactive approach in refining its processes illustrates the company’s commitment to leading in competitive foundry technologies and adapting to evolving market demands.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Figure-1-1200x675.jpg" alt="Intel i3 Process"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates on the latest advancements in the semiconductor industry as we continue to monitor these transformative trends and technologies.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eetimes.com/middle-east-expects-ai-gains-from-u-s-dea</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="market trends" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/market-trends/"/>
    
    <category term="technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/technology/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>World&#39;s Lowest Write Power Operation for High-Speed SOT-MRAM Cell Achieved</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250531_World&#39;s-Lowest-Write-Power-Operation-for-High-Speed-SOT-MRAM-Cell-Achieved/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250531_World&#39;s-Lowest-Write-Power-Operation-for-High-Speed-SOT-MRAM-Cell-Achieved/</id>
    <published>2025-05-30T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-05-31T11:59:05.939Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/supply-chain-uncertainty-hits-canadas-chip-sector/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Supply Chain Uncertainty Hits Canada’s Chip Sector</strong><br>Canada’s semiconductor industry faces significant challenges within a complex global supply chain. Experts at the CHIPS NORTH Executive Summit discussed maintaining manufacturing capabilities and the importance of flexibility in supplier networks. Recent investments by the Canadian government aim to bolster chip packaging capacities, while industry leaders emphasize the necessity of adapting to both technological and geopolitical disruptions.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/chipsnorthsupplychain-covercarousel.jpg" alt="Supply Chain"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/indian-startup-engineers-economical-evtols/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Indian Startup Engineers Economical eVTOLs</strong><br>The Indian startup ePlane Co. is pioneering electric vertical take-off and landing (eVTOL) aircraft, focusing on efficient, compact designs for urban transport. With its unique architecture promising reduced costs and the ability to operate from rooftops, ePlane aims to address the limitations of current battery technology while preparing for certification and commercial launches by 2027.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_647367286.jpeg" alt="eVTOL"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-05-world-lowest-power-high-sot.html">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>World’s Lowest Write Power Operation for High-Speed SOT-MRAM Cell Achieved</strong><br>Researchers at Tohoku University have set a new record for the lowest write power in SOT-MRAM technology, achieving an energy efficiency of just 156 fJ. This advancement is expected to propel the use of SOT-MRAM in future high-performance electronic devices, providing a greener alternative to existing memory technologies.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2025/worlds-lowest-write-po.jpg" alt="SOT-MRAM"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-05-ai-chip-decentralized-cloud.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>AI Chip Developed for Decentralized Use Without the Cloud</strong><br>A neuromorphic AI chip from the Technical University of Munich operates without cloud connections, mimicking human brain functions for energy-efficient on-site calculations. This chip demonstrates significant advancements in processing efficiency, paving the way for customized AI solutions that enhance security and reduce reliance on cloud computing.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/ai-chip-developed-for-1.jpg" alt="AI Chip"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-05-scientists-vulnerability-intel-processors.html">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Computer Scientists Discover New Security Vulnerability in Intel Processors</strong><br>Researchers from ETH Zurich have identified a new class of vulnerabilities in Intel processors that exploit speculative execution to gain unauthorized access to data. This discovery raises concerns about data security in multi-user environments and highlights the need for robust security measures in future processor designs.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/researchers-discover-n-15.jpg" alt="Intel Vulnerability"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates and insights from the semiconductor industry as we continue to monitor these exciting developments and challenges.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eetimes.com/supply-chain-uncertainty-hits-canadas-chi</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="chip design" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/chip-design/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="supply chain" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/supply-chain/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Resist Loss Model for the EUV Stochastic Defectivity Cliffs</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250530_Resist-Loss-Model-for-the-EUV-Stochastic-Defectivity-Cliffs/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250530_Resist-Loss-Model-for-the-EUV-Stochastic-Defectivity-Cliffs/</id>
    <published>2025-05-29T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-05-31T07:17:11.042Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2023-11-photoresist-materials-pave-smaller-high.html">News</a></h2><p><strong>Innovative photoresist materials pave the way for smaller, high performance semiconductor chips</strong><br>Researchers at the Center for Functional Nanomaterials have developed a new hybrid photoresist material that enhances patterning for extreme ultraviolet (EUV) lithography. This advancement is crucial as the industry approaches the challenge of producing chips with features just a few nanometers in size. The new material combines organic and inorganic components to improve sensitivity, allowing for faster and more efficient chip manufacturing.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2023/a-bright-future-for-ex.jpg" alt="Innovative Materials"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/lam-research-establishes-28nm-pitch-in-high-resolution-patterning-through-dry-photoresist-technology/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Lam Research Unveils Dry Photoresist Technology for Advanced Logic</strong><br>Lam Research’s new dry photoresist technology has been officially qualified for direct-print 28nm pitch back end of line (BEOL) logic at 2nm and below by imec. This technology promises to enhance resolution and yield while reducing costs and raw material usage in semiconductor manufacturing.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="Lam Research"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/2024-photoresist-market-forecasted-to-rise/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>2024 Photoresist Market Forecasted to Rise</strong><br>The photoresist market is expected to rebound in 2024, with a projected growth of 7% to reach $2.57 billion. This growth is driven by the increasing demand for EUV and KrF products, essential for the latest semiconductor technologies. The report highlights significant trends in the market, including the shift towards negative tone EUV photoresists.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/image1.png" alt="Market Trends"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/lithography/352503-resist-loss-model-for-the-euv-stochastic-defectivity-cliffs/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Resist Loss Model for the EUV Stochastic Defectivity Cliffs</strong><br>A new research paper explores stochastic defectivity in EUV lithography, proposing a model to address resist loss issues that affect yield and pattern fidelity. This study aims to enhance the reliability of EUV processes in semiconductor manufacturing and is crucial for future technology nodes.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Exposing-EUV-1.png" alt="EUV Research"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ceo-interviews/353829-ceo-interview-with-dinesh-bettadapur-of-irresistible-materials/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Dinesh Bettadapur of Irresistible Materials</strong><br>In an insightful interview, Dinesh Bettadapur discusses the challenges and innovations in the semiconductor materials sector, focusing on the importance of advanced photoresist solutions in meeting industry demands. He emphasizes the role of collaboration and innovation in driving the next wave of semiconductor advancements.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/D.-Bettadapur_photo_IM-960x1200.jpg" alt="Dinesh Bettadapur"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for the latest updates and breakthroughs in the semiconductor industry as we continue to bring you valuable insights and news.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techxplore.com/news/2023-11-photoresist-materials-pave-sm</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Lithography/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor Technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor-Technology/"/>
    
    <category term="Market Trends" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Market-Trends/"/>
    
    <category term="EUV Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/EUV-Lithography/"/>
    
    <category term="Photoresists" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Photoresists/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Demonstration Of EUV Scatterometry On A 2D Periodic Interconnect</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250528_Demonstration-Of-EUV-Scatterometry-On-A-2D-Periodic-Interconnect/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250528_Demonstration-Of-EUV-Scatterometry-On-A-2D-Periodic-Interconnect/</id>
    <published>2025-05-27T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-05-31T10:26:58.411Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://spie.org/news/other-lithography-approaches-offer-alternatives">News</a></h2><p><strong>Other lithography approaches offer alternatives</strong><br>At the 2025 SPIE Advanced Lithography + Patterning conference, semiconductor manufacturers are exploring alternative lithography methods to enhance performance and reduce costs. Notable presentations included Micron Technology’s Tomohiro Iwaki discussing challenges in nanoimprint technology and Intel’s Florian Gstrein highlighting directed self-assembly techniques. These innovations aim to improve defect rates and boost yields, particularly relevant for logic and memory chips.</p><p><img src="https://spie.org/images/Graphics/Newsroom/2025articles/AL25_Nanoimprint_920.jpg" alt="Nanoimprint Technology"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://spie.org/news/getting-pfas-out-of-lithography-materials">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Getting PFAS out of lithography materials</strong><br>Central Glass Co. is pioneering PFAS-free materials for 193-nm immersion lithography, addressing long-term environmental and health concerns associated with traditional photoresist components. Their new formulations, which include a PFAS-free photo acid generator and immersion barrier polymer, have shown promising results in maintaining performance while reducing harmful substances.</p><p><img src="https://spie.org/images/Graphics/Newsroom/2025articles/AL25_PFAS_Litho_920.jpg" alt="PFAS-Free Materials"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://spie.org/news/chips-and-lithography-head-up-and-down">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Chips – and lithography – head up and down</strong><br>The latest insights from the 2025 SPIE conference emphasized the shift towards 3D semiconductor architectures to overcome scaling limitations. Presentations discussed how backside power delivery can alleviate power bottlenecks, enabling denser and more efficient chip designs. This transition is pivotal for sustaining Moore’s Law in an era of complex circuitry.</p><p><img src="https://spie.org/images/Graphics/Newsroom/2025articles/AL25_Backside%20Patterning_920.jpg" alt="3D Chip Design"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/demonstration-of-euv-scatterometry-on-a-2d-periodic-interconnect/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Demonstration Of EUV Scatterometry On A 2D Periodic Interconnect</strong><br>A research collaboration involving the University of Colorado, NIST, and Samsung has revealed advancements in EUV scatterometry, a metrology technique vital for measuring periodic nanostructured materials. The study demonstrates enhanced sensitivity and the potential for deep sub-nanometer precision, marking a significant step forward for semiconductor manufacturing.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_517438105-04-16-24.jpeg" alt="EUV Scatterometry"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.tel.com/news/topics/2025/20250526_001.html">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Tokyo Electron Receives Renewal of DX-certified Business Operator Status from the Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry</strong><br>Tokyo Electron’s recent renewal of its DX-certified Business Operator status marks a significant achievement in its digital transformation initiatives. This renewed status emphasizes TEL’s commitment to leveraging digital technologies to enhance corporate value and adapt to the rapidly evolving semiconductor market, which is projected to approach $1 trillion by 2030.</p><p><img src="https://www.tel.com/news/topics/2025/ms68nt00000000dt-img/ms68nt00000000fu.png" alt="Digital Transformation"></p><hr><p>Thank you for staying with us for the latest news in the semiconductor industry. We look forward to bringing you more updates on innovations and advancements in lithography and sustainability efforts.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://spie.org/news/other-lithography-approaches-offer-alternat</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Lithography/"/>
    
    
    <category term="EUV" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/EUV/"/>
    
    <category term="Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Lithography/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor Sustainability" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor-Sustainability/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CEO Interview with Mohan Iyer, Vice President and General Manager, Semiconductor Business Unit at Thermo Fisher Scientific</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250526_CEO-Interview-with-Mohan-Iyer,-Vice-President-and-General-Manager,-Semiconductor-Business-Unit-at-Thermo-Fisher-Scientific/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250526_CEO-Interview-with-Mohan-Iyer,-Vice-President-and-General-Manager,-Semiconductor-Business-Unit-at-Thermo-Fisher-Scientific/</id>
    <published>2025-05-25T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-05-31T10:26:58.411Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/kla-invests-in-operations-in-wales-with-the-opening-of-a-138-million-rd-and-manufacturing-facility/">News</a></h2><p><strong>KLA Invests in Operations in Wales with the Opening of a $138 Million R&amp;D and Manufacturing Facility</strong><br>KLA Corporation has inaugurated a new $138 million R&amp;D and manufacturing facility in Newport, Wales, enhancing its product lines and capacity to meet the growing demand for advanced semiconductor technologies. The facility includes extensive R&amp;D clean rooms and manufacturing spaces, aiming to support innovations across sectors like AI, power devices, and photonics. This investment reaffirms KLA’s commitment to the region and the semiconductor industry’s future.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="KLA Facility"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/efficiency-upgrade-for-oled-screens-a-route-to-blue-pholed-longevity/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Efficiency Upgrade for OLED Screens: A Route to Blue PHOLED Longevity</strong><br>Researchers at the University of Michigan have developed a method to enhance the longevity of blue phosphorescent OLEDs, bringing them up to par with the more durable green counterparts. This innovation could revolutionize OLED technology, improving energy efficiency and display performance in smartphones and televisions by integrating advanced coatings that facilitate faster energy conversion.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="OLED Technology"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/canada-needs-a-multi-faceted-strategy-to-scale-chip-talent/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Faceted Strategy to Scale Chip Talent</strong><br>The Canadian semiconductor industry is facing a critical shortage of talent, with estimates indicating a need for 1.5 million engineers globally in the next few years. This landscape requires innovative workforce development strategies to attract and cultivate talent, as highlighted in discussions at the CHIPS NORTH Executive Summit. The need for an integrated approach between industry and academia is emphasized to address the skills gap.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/chipsnorthtalent-covercarousel.jpg" alt="Talent Strategy"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/rice-method-refines-ultrapure-diamond-film-fabrication-for-quantum-and-electronic-applications/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Rice Method Refines Ultrapure Diamond Film Fabrication for Quantum and Electronic Applications</strong><br>Researchers at Rice University have made significant advancements in diamond film fabrication, creating ultrapure layers suitable for quantum and electronic technologies without the need for high-temperature annealing. This streamlined method has the potential to enhance the quality and efficiency of diamond-based devices, paving the way for innovations in the semiconductor industry.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="Diamond Fabrication"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ceo-interviews/355982-executive-interview-with-mohan-iyer-vice-president-and-general-manager-semiconductor-business-unit-thermo-fisher-scientific/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Mohan Iyer, Vice President and General Manager, Semiconductor Business Unit at Thermo Fisher Scientific</strong><br>Mohan Iyer discusses Thermo Fisher’s commitment to advancing semiconductor manufacturing through innovative solutions in R&amp;D, yield management, and defect analysis. He emphasizes the importance of automated workflows and advanced metrology for enhancing manufacturing efficiency and product quality in a rapidly evolving industry.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/MohanPicWorkday_11302021-1042x1200.jpg" alt="Mohan Iyer"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates and insights from the semiconductor industry as we continue to explore the latest innovations and trends shaping the future of technology.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#News&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/kla-invests-in-operations-in</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/technology/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="investment" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/investment/"/>
    
    <category term="workforce" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/workforce/"/>
    
    <category term="quantum computing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/quantum-computing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
