<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>opensemi</title>
  
  <subtitle>we bring you the daily insight in semiconductor industry</subtitle>
  <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/"/>
  <updated>2025-11-06T05:16:26.327Z</updated>
  <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/</id>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TEL to Highlight Sustainability Through Digitization and AI at SEMICON Europa 2025</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251106_TEL-to-Highlight-Sustainability-Through-Digitization-and-AI-at-SEMICON-Europa-2025/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251106_TEL-to-Highlight-Sustainability-Through-Digitization-and-AI-at-SEMICON-Europa-2025/</id>
    <published>2025-11-05T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-06T05:16:26.327Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251106_etch_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/kerala-positions-design-and-ip-at-core-of-chip-strategy/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Kerala Positions Design and IP at Core of Chip Strategy</strong><br>The Indian state of Kerala has unveiled its Vision 2031 framework, charting a design-first semiconductor roadmap. Instead of investing heavily in multi-billion-dollar fabs, the state aims to focus on chip design, testing, and IP creation. This strategy leverages Kerala’s strong academic base to build design-centric clusters, expand hardware incubation centers, and retain intellectual property within India. The plan seeks to create half a million IT jobs and grow the sector’s economic output to $49.7 billion by 2031.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Feature-Image-Recode-Kerala.jpg" alt="Feature Image Recode Kerala"></p><ul><li>Kerala prioritizes chip design, testing, and IP creation over fab construction.</li><li>The strategy aims to create 500,000 IT jobs and boost economic output by 2031.</li><li>Leverages academic strengths to build design-centric clusters and retain IP in India.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.gsmarena.com/qualcomm_snapdragon_8_gen_4_unveiling_is_expected_on_october_24-news-60317.php">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Gen 4 Unveiling is Expected on October 24</strong><br>Qualcomm is set to unveil its next-generation flagship mobile platform, the Snapdragon 8 Gen 4, on October 24. This highly anticipated chip is expected to power premium Android smartphones in 2025, bringing significant advancements in performance, AI capabilities, and power efficiency. The launch event is slated to showcase Qualcomm’s latest innovations in mobile processing, aiming to set new benchmarks for the industry and enhance user experiences across various high-end devices.</p><p><img src="https://fdn.gsmarena.com/imgroot/news/23/10/snapdragon-8-gen-4-october-24/-1200x900m/gsmarena_001.jpg" alt="Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Gen 4"></p><ul><li>Qualcomm to unveil its Snapdragon 8 Gen 4 mobile platform on October 24.</li><li>The new chip is expected to deliver significant performance and AI enhancements.</li><li>Aims to power premium Android smartphones in 2025, setting new industry benchmarks.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://newsroom.lamresearch.com/overcoming-beol-patterning-challenges-at-the-3-nm-node?blog=true">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Overcoming BEOL Patterning Challenges at the 3-NM Node</strong><br>At the 3-nm node, achieving precise interconnect critical dimensions (CD) and pitch for metal dimensions below 18 nm poses significant challenges, particularly in controlling Edge Placement Error (EPE). Through virtual fabrication and Monte Carlo simulations using SEMulator3D®, Lam Research identified critical process parameters and optimal process windows needed to manage EPE variability and line CD control. The analysis showed that only a small percentage of simulated runs met minimum line CD criteria, highlighting the importance of tightly controlling process parameters for successful patterning in advanced BEOL technologies.</p><p><img src="https://assets.newsroom.lamresearch.com/m/6a793a38c92a6b29/original/blog-overcoming-beol-patterning-challenges-at-the-3-nm-node-5.jpg" alt="Minimum line CD process window to meet minimum line CD success criteria"></p><ul><li>BEOL patterning at 3nm faces critical challenges with interconnect CD and EPE.</li><li>Virtual fabrication identified key process parameters and windows for EPE control.</li><li>Only 9.75% of simulated runs met line CD success criteria, emphasizing strict process control.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-today.com/news_items/2025/oct/ucas-301025.shtml">Research</a></h2><p><strong>P-type Layer Etch for Enhanced Deep UV LEDs to Boost Efficiency</strong><br>Researchers in China have demonstrated an innovative method to enhance the performance of aluminium gallium nitride (AlGaN) deep ultraviolet (DUV) light-emitting diodes (LEDs) by carefully etching away DUV-absorbing p-type layers. This technique aims to increase light-extraction efficiency (LEE) without significantly compromising internal quantum efficiency (IQE) or carrier injection. The team found that an optimal etch depth can lead to improved light output power and wall-plug efficiency, crucial for developing more efficient DUV sources for sterilization and medical applications.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-today.com/news_items/2025/oct/25103_ucas_f2.jpg" alt="Schematics of DUV-LEDs with etched p-type layer"></p><ul><li>P-type layer etching enhances DUV-LED light extraction efficiency.</li><li>Balancing etch depth is crucial to prevent IQE reduction and increased resistance.</li><li>Optimal etching shows improved light output power and wall-plug efficiency.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.tel.com/news/event/2025/20251105_001.html">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>TEL to Highlight Sustainability Through Digitization and AI at SEMICON Europa 2025</strong><br>At SEMICON Europa 2025, Tokyo Electron (TEL) will present on “Enabling Sustainability through Digitization and AI.” Kaushik Kumar will discuss how the semiconductor market, projected to reach $1 trillion by 2030 driven by AI, faces increasing complexities in device structures. The presentation will explore how semiconductor production equipment makers like TEL can leverage AI to manage these challenges sustainably, improve operational efficiency, and support Net-Zero objectives amidst rising development costs and extended timelines.</p><p><img src="https://www.tel.com/news/event/2025/t6kdf800000000hw-img/t6kdf800000000k6.jpg" alt="SEMICON Europa 2025 Logo"></p><ul><li>TEL to present on sustainability, digitization, and AI at SEMICON Europa 2025.</li><li>Focuses on leveraging AI to manage complexities and enhance efficiency in chip manufacturing.</li><li>Aims to support Net-Zero objectives in the semiconductor industry’s growth towards $1 trillion by 2030.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay tuned for more essential updates and analysis shaping the future of the semiconductor industry!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251106_etch_newsletter_gemini</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Etch" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Etch/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Chip Design" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Chip-Design/"/>
    
    <category term="Manufacturing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Manufacturing/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    <category term="DUV-LEDs" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/DUV-LEDs/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>proteanTecs&#39; Real-Time Health Monitoring Prevents Semiconductor Failures</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251104_proteanTecs&#39;-Real-Time-Health-Monitoring-Prevents-Semiconductor-Failures/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251104_proteanTecs&#39;-Real-Time-Health-Monitoring-Prevents-Semiconductor-Failures/</id>
    <published>2025-11-03T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-04T05:18:23.422Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251104_device_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/intel-eyeing-ai-catchup-in-inference-with-sambanova-acquisition/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Intel Eyeing AI Catchup in Inference with SambaNova Acquisition</strong><br>Intel is reportedly in talks to acquire AI processor designer SambaNova as part of a strategic shift to bolster its AI roadmap, focusing heavily on inference workloads. This move comes after Intel canceled its Falcon Shores AI accelerator and announced the “Crescent Island” GPU for inference, aiming for a “system-level solution at rack scale.” SambaNova specializes in AI hardware and software stacks, particularly reconfigurable dataflow unit (RDU) chips optimized for large-scale inference by mapping neural network graphs directly into hardware, reducing memory movement overhead.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_283632950_Editorial_Use_Only.jpeg" alt="Intel SambaNova Acquisition"></p><ul><li>Intel is pivoting its AI strategy towards inference workloads and full-stack solutions.</li><li>SambaNova’s RDU chips and expertise in inference systems could significantly enhance Intel’s AI offerings.</li><li>The potential acquisition highlights Intel’s renewed focus on the rapidly growing AI inference market.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/could-ntts-low-power-chip-be-a-game-changer-for-drones/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>NTT’s Low-Power Chip Revolutionizes Drone Object Detection</strong><br>NTT Research has unveiled a groundbreaking chip capable of real-time 4K video object detection at under 20W, a critical advancement for battery-powered aerial platforms like drones. Unlike conventional systems that downscale video, NTT’s chip processes 4K frames by dividing them into blocks, running parallel YOLO detection, and then fusing results with a holistic “overview” process. This maintains high-resolution accuracy while achieving remarkable power efficiency, enabling drones to detect objects farther away and classify them more accurately.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Image-4-5.jpg" alt="NTT Drone Chip"></p><ul><li>The chip performs real-time 4K object detection under 20W, crucial for power-constrained drones.</li><li>It utilizes a unique block-processing and fusion method to maintain high resolution without downscaling.</li><li>Expected to be generally available in early 2026, it promises to enhance drone autonomy, swarming, and security by reducing reliance on external data links.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/mits-survey-on-accelerators-and-processors-for-inference-with-peak-performance-and-power-comparisons/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>MIT Lincoln Lab Releases LAICS Survey on AI Accelerators and Processors</strong><br>The MIT Lincoln Laboratory Supercomputing Center has published an updated “Lincoln AI Computing Survey (LAICS) and Trends,” providing a multi-year analysis of commercial AI accelerators and processors. This survey compiles publicly announced peak performance and power consumption numbers, plotting them on scatter graphs to highlight market segments and trends. The latest update includes a new categorization of computing architectures, offering crucial insights into the evolving landscape of hardware for generative AI training and inference.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_309524207-scaled.jpeg" alt="MIT LAICS Survey"></p><ul><li>The LAICS survey offers a comprehensive overview of commercial AI accelerators’ performance and power.</li><li>It utilizes scatter graphs to visualize trends and differentiate market segments for AI hardware.</li><li>The updated survey includes new architectural categorizations relevant to GenAI.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-10-neuromorphic-prototype-patterns-traditional-ai.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Neuromorphic Computer Prototype Learns Patterns with Fewer Computations</strong><br>Researchers at The University of Texas at Dallas, in collaboration with Everspin Technologies Inc. and Texas Instruments, have developed a small-scale neuromorphic computer prototype that significantly reduces training computations. This brain-inspired hardware integrates memory storage with processing, allowing it to perform AI tasks more efficiently and with lower power consumption than conventional AI systems. A key innovation is the use of magnetic tunnel junctions (MTJs) in networks, mimicking synaptic connections to adapt and learn patterns based on Hebb’s law.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/team-builds-computer-p.jpg" alt="Neuromorphic Prototype"></p><ul><li>The prototype achieves efficient pattern learning with substantially fewer training computations.</li><li>It integrates memory and processing, inspired by brain architecture, for greater AI efficiency.</li><li>Magnetic tunnel junctions (MTJs) are central to its design, enabling adaptive learning through varying conductivity.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/analytics/proteantecs/362580-failure-prevention-with-real-time-health-monitoring-a-proteantecs-innovation/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>proteanTecs’ Real-Time Health Monitoring Prevents Semiconductor Failures</strong><br>At the 2025 TSMC OIP Forum, Noam Brousard of proteanTecs presented on “Failure Prevention with Real-Time Health Monitoring (RTHM™),” addressing the critical challenge of silent data corruption (SDC) in advanced semiconductor devices. As devices shrink and operate under intense AI workloads, traditional reliability methods fall short. RTHM provides continuous, high-coverage on-chip monitoring of performance-limiting paths using embedded Agents. It generates a “Performance Index” score, enabling proactive intervention before failures escalate, thereby safeguarding against SDC, functional failures, and system errors.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/proteanTecs-RTHM-OIP-2025-1200x615.jpg" alt="proteanTecs RTHM"></p><ul><li>SDC is a growing threat in nanoscale semiconductors and AI systems, leading to untraceable failures.</li><li>proteanTecs’ RTHM offers proactive, continuous on-chip monitoring to predict and avert failures.</li><li>The system uses a Performance Index to indicate proximity to failure, enabling timely mitigation and enhanced system reliability.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay tuned with us for the latest news and breakthroughs shaping the semiconductor landscape!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251104_device_newsletter_gemi</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Edge AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Edge-AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Neuromorphic Computing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Neuromorphic-Computing/"/>
    
    <category term="AI Acceleration" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI-Acceleration/"/>
    
    <category term="Chiplet Systems" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Chiplet-Systems/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor Reliability" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor-Reliability/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>NVIDIA, South Korea Government and Industrial Giants Build AI Infrastructure and Ecosystem to Fuel Korea Innovation, Industries and Jobs</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251103_NVIDIA,-South-Korea-Government-and-Industrial-Giants-Build-AI-Infrastructure-and-Ecosystem-to-Fuel-Korea-Innovation,-Industries-and-Jobs/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251103_NVIDIA,-South-Korea-Government-and-Industrial-Giants-Build-AI-Infrastructure-and-Ecosystem-to-Fuel-Korea-Innovation,-Industries-and-Jobs/</id>
    <published>2025-11-02T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-11-03T05:20:23.711Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251103_semiconductor_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/nvidia-south-korea-government-and-industrial-giants-build-ai-infrastructure-and-ecosystem-to-fuel-korea-innovation-industries-and-jobs/">News</a></h2><p><strong>NVIDIA, South Korea Government and Industrial Giants Build AI Infrastructure and Ecosystem to Fuel Korea Innovation, Industries and Jobs</strong><br>NVIDIA is partnering with South Korea to significantly expand the nation’s AI infrastructure, deploying over a quarter-million NVIDIA GPUs across sovereign clouds and AI factories. This initiative, announced during the APEC Summit, is set to fuel AI-enabled economic growth and innovation across key Korean industries, including automotive, manufacturing, and telecommunications.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="NVIDIA South Korea Collaboration"></p><ul><li>South Korea plans to deploy over 250,000 NVIDIA GPUs to accelerate sovereign AI development and bolster national AI capabilities.</li><li>Industry leaders like Samsung, SK Group, and Hyundai Motor Group are making substantial investments to build NVIDIA AI factories for advanced manufacturing and physical AI development.</li><li>Collaborations also extend to AI-RAN, 6G infrastructure, quantum computing research, and a new startup alliance to foster the nation’s AI ecosystem.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/onsemi-unveils-vertical-gan-semiconductors-a-breakthrough-for-ai-and-electrification/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>onsemi Unveils Vertical GaN Semiconductors: A Breakthrough for AI and Electrification</strong><br>onsemi has introduced groundbreaking vertical gallium nitride (vGaN) power semiconductors, setting a new benchmark for power density, efficiency, and ruggedness in applications like AI data centers and electric vehicles. Developed and manufactured at onsemi’s Syracuse, NY, fab, this proprietary GaN-on-GaN technology enables current to flow vertically through the compound semiconductor, supporting higher operating voltages and faster switching frequencies.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="onsemi Vertical GaN"></p><ul><li>vGaN technology offers superior power density, efficiency, and ruggedness for demanding AI and electrification applications.</li><li>The GaN-on-GaN design reduces energy loss by nearly 50% and allows for smaller, lighter systems by operating at higher frequencies.</li><li>onsemi is currently sampling 700V and 1200V devices to early access customers, targeting AI data centers, EVs, and renewable energy.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/semiconductor-services/semiconductor-intelligence/363205-u-s-electronics-production-growing/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>U.S. Electronics Production Growing Amidst Global Shifts</strong><br>U.S. electronics production has shown an accelerating growth trend over the past ten months, with the three-month average change versus a year ago (3&#x2F;12 change) increasing from 0.4% in October 2024 to 6.2% in August 2025. This growth is partly attributed to companies shifting manufacturing to the U.S., influenced by tariff policies. Despite this, employment in the U.S. electronics manufacturing sector has seen a decline. Globally, China’s electronics production remains robust.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/U.S.-Electronics-Production-Growing-1.jpg" alt="U.S. Electronics Production Chart"></p><ul><li>U.S. electronics production significantly accelerated, with a 3&#x2F;12 change rising to 6.2% by August 2025.</li><li>Despite increased production, U.S. electronics manufacturing employment decreased from 1.04 million jobs in January 2024 to 1.001 million in August 2025.</li><li>China’s electronics production maintained steady growth between 10% to 13%, indicating resilience despite global manufacturing shifts.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.imec-int.com/en/press/imec-sets-electro-optic-performance-record-thin-film-strontium-titanate-cryogenic">Research</a></h2><p><strong>imec Sets Electro-Optic Performance Record with Thin-Film Strontium Titanate at Cryogenic Temperatures</strong><br>Imec researchers, in collaboration with KU Leuven and Ghent University, have engineered thin-film strontium titanate (SrTiO₃) to achieve a record electro-optic performance at 4 Kelvin (cryogenic temperatures). Published in Science, this breakthrough demonstrates an effective Pockels coefficient of nearly 350 pm&#x2F;V with remarkably low optical loss, surpassing any other thin-film electro-optic material at this temperature.</p><p><img src="https://www.imec-int.com/sites/default/files/2025-10/header.jpg" alt="imec Thin-Film Strontium Titanate"></p><ul><li>Imec achieved record electro-optic performance with thin-film SrTiO₃ at 4 Kelvin, critical for quantum devices.</li><li>The material demonstrates a Pockels coefficient of nearly 350 pm&#x2F;V, enabling efficient light modulation with minimal optical loss.</li><li>This advance facilitates the development of smaller, faster electro-optic components for next-generation quantum interconnects, modulators, and transducers.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/even-with-ai-inroads-human-chip-designers-still-essential/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Even With AI Inroads, Human Chip Designers Still Essential</strong><br>Despite the growing integration of AI tools in semiconductor design, human engineers remain indispensable for creative, open-ended, and context-specific tasks. Experts emphasize that AI will primarily serve to augment designers’ capabilities, streamlining mundane and repetitive tasks, and accelerating optimization. However, human intuition, complex problem-solving, and final judgment in areas like architectural design, analog circuits, and safety-critical decisions will continue to be paramount.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/AdobeStock_857968898-neural-network-scaled.jpeg" alt="Human Brains and AI"></p><ul><li>AI is expected to augment, rather than replace, human chip designers, focusing on enhancing productivity in repetitive tasks.</li><li>Human expertise remains critical for high-level architectural decisions, innovative product design, and complex analog circuit development.</li><li>Final verification sign-off, safety-critical design, and handling novel problems still require human judgment, intuition, and cross-disciplinary reasoning.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay tuned for our next update, bringing you the freshest developments in the dynamic world of semiconductors!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251103_semiconductor_newslett</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Advanced Packaging" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Advanced-Packaging/"/>
    
    <category term="Chip Design" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Chip-Design/"/>
    
    <category term="GaN" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/GaN/"/>
    
    <category term="Photonics" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Photonics/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>VSORA- Inference Acceleration from the Ground Up</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251031_VSORA--Inference-Acceleration-from-the-Ground-Up/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251031_VSORA--Inference-Acceleration-from-the-Ground-Up/</id>
    <published>2025-10-30T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-31T05:18:51.194Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251031_machinelearning_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/3dic/362862-chiplets-powering-the-next-generation-of-ai-systems/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Chiplets: Powering the Next Generation of AI Systems</strong><br>The semiconductor industry is rapidly shifting towards modular multi-die designs, with chiplets projected to become a $411 billion market by 2035. This paradigm allows for dividing large SoC functions into smaller, reusable dies, integrated into a single system-in-package (SiP) to overcome traditional SoC scaling limits. Critical to this evolution are interconnect standards like UCIe and advanced packaging techniques (2.5D and 3D). Collaboration between industry leaders like Synopsys and Arm is crucial, simplifying AI chip design by focusing on interoperability, reliability, and security within evolving chiplet ecosystems.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Arm-Synopsys-at-Chiplet-Summit.png" alt="Arm Synopsys at Chiplet Summit"></p><ul><li>Chiplets are set to be a $411 billion market by 2035, driven by AI’s compute and I&#x2F;O demands.</li><li>UCIe is emerging as the preferred die-to-die interconnect standard, alongside advanced packaging techniques.</li><li>Industry collaboration, such as between Synopsys and Arm, is vital for streamlining AI chip design and ensuring interoperability.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/363023-inference-acceleration-from-the-ground-up/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>VSORA: Inference Acceleration from the Ground Up</strong><br>VSORA has engineered a novel architecture specifically for AI inference, delivering near-theoretical performance in latency, throughput, and energy efficiency for both datacenters and the edge. This fifth-generation architecture tackles the “memory wall” by employing a unified memory stage with a massive SRAM array, ensuring single-clock access to 16 million registers per core. Each core integrates 64K multi-dimensional MAC units and DSP cores, with dynamic numerical precision. The design leverages a chiplet architecture, allowing scalable configurations like the Jotunn8 for datacenters (3,200 TFLOPS FP8) and Tyr configurations for edge AI. This approach achieves processing efficiencies exceeding 50% and double the performance-per-watt of comparable solutions, simplifying development through a CUDA-free compilation flow.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/VSORA-AI-CHip.png" alt="VSORA AI Chip"></p><ul><li>VSORA’s new architecture achieves near-theoretical AI inference performance by eliminating the “memory wall” with a unified SRAM array.</li><li>Each core features 16 million registers and high-throughput MAC units, supporting flexible tensor operations and dynamic precision.</li><li>Chiplet-based scalability enables configurations for both datacenter (Jotunn8) and edge AI, offering significant power efficiency gains.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/understanding-and-mitigating-column-based-read-disturbance-in-dram-chips-eth-zurich-cispa/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Understanding and Mitigating Column-Based Read Disturbance in DRAM Chips</strong><br>Researchers at ETH Zurich and CISPA have identified and characterized a new widespread read disturbance phenomenon called “ColumnDisturb” in commodity DRAM chips. Unlike previous disturbances, ColumnDisturb can affect cells across multiple DRAM subarrays by repeatedly opening or keeping an aggressor row open, inducing bitflips in cells sharing the same columns. Experimental results from 216 DDR4 and 4 HBM2 chips show that this issue affects all major manufacturers and worsens as DRAM technology scales down, with the minimum time to induce a bitflip reducing by up to 5.06x. This trend suggests ColumnDisturb will pose significant challenges for future DRAM chips, impacting refresh mechanisms and data reliability.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_362074973-security-07-23-scaled.jpeg" alt="Security Image"></p><ul><li>A new “ColumnDisturb” read disturbance affects DRAM cells across multiple subarrays, causing bitflips.</li><li>This phenomenon worsens with DRAM technology scaling, reducing the time to induce bitflips by up to 5.06x.</li><li>ColumnDisturb poses significant reliability challenges for future DRAM designs and refresh mechanisms.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/utilizing-chiplet-locality-for-efficient-memory-mapping-in-mcm-gpus-etri-sungkyunkwan-univ/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Utilizing Chiplet-Locality For Efficient Memory Mapping In MCM GPUs (ETRI, Sungkyunkwan Univ.)</strong><br>Researchers from ETRI and Sungkyunkwan University have introduced CLAP (Chiplet-Locality Aware Paging), a novel approach to enhance memory mapping efficiency in Multi-Chip Module (MCM) GPUs. MCM designs introduce memory system non-uniformity when threads access remote chiplet resources, which is sensitive to page size. CLAP addresses this by determining the optimal page size for each application, leveraging the observation that GPU applications exhibit “chiplet-locality”—specific groups of pages primarily accessed by the same chiplet. By pre-organizing these local page groups into contiguous physical frames within the accessing chiplet, CLAP creates regions that function like large pages with merged TLB entries, delivering up to a 19.2% performance improvement over previous paging schemes.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_278047901-05-25-scaled.jpeg" alt="Adobe Stock Image"></p><ul><li>CLAP optimizes memory mapping in MCM GPUs by identifying and exploiting “chiplet-locality.”</li><li>It dynamically determines suitable page sizes for applications, consolidating local page groups for efficient access.</li><li>This approach improves performance by up to 19.2% by delivering the benefits of large pages without compromising locality.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/362468-emulator-like-simulation-acceleration-on-gpus-innovation-in-verification/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Like Simulation Acceleration on GPUs. Innovation in Verification</strong><br>A new paper titled “GEM: GPU-Accelerated Emulator-Inspired RTL Simulation” by Peking University and NVIDIA introduces a novel method to accelerate logic simulation on GPUs, addressing previous challenges with GPU architectures. Paul Cunningham (GM, Verification at Cadence) highlights Cadence’s continued investment in this area, noting that GEM’s intelligent partitioning and bit-packed structure enable efficient execution on NVIDIA’s SIMT machines. Raúl Camposano (Silicon Catalyst, former Synopsys CTO) praises GEM’s innovations, particularly its “boomerang executor layer” for intra-block efficiency and multi-stage RepCut partitioning for scalability, achieving up to 9x speed-up over leading commercial simulators. While currently lacking features like 4-state logic and multi-GPU support, GEM’s open-source, software-only approach represents a significant step forward in verification efficiency.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Innovation-New.jpeg" alt="Innovation New"></p><ul><li>GEM utilizes a new GPU-accelerated approach for RTL simulation, inspired by FPGA emulators.</li><li>It achieves up to 9x speed-up over commercial simulators by optimizing logic execution for GPU architectures.</li><li>Industry leaders recognize its potential for verification efficiency, despite current limitations in full commercial feature parity.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay connected with us for the most pivotal advancements shaping the future of the semiconductor landscape!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251031_machinelearning_newsle</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Machinelearning" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Machinelearning/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Chiplets" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Chiplets/"/>
    
    <category term="DRAM" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/DRAM/"/>
    
    <category term="Thermal Management" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Thermal-Management/"/>
    
    <category term="AI acceleration" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI-acceleration/"/>
    
    <category term="FeRAM" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/FeRAM/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>L&amp;T Semiconductor and Hon Young Partner for High-Voltage SiC Wafer Development</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251030_L&amp;T-Semiconductor-and-Hon-Young-Partner-for-High-Voltage-SiC-Wafer-Development/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251030_L&amp;T-Semiconductor-and-Hon-Young-Partner-for-High-Voltage-SiC-Wafer-Development/</id>
    <published>2025-10-29T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-30T05:13:36.112Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251030_etch_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://newsroom.lamresearch.com/semiverse-solutions-preps-top-engineering-talent-for-whats-next?blog=true">News</a></h2><p><strong>Lam Research Tackles Engineer Shortage with Virtual Process Integration</strong><br>Lam Research is addressing the U.S. semiconductor engineer shortage by providing its SEMulator3D® modeling platform to educational institutions. This platform offers students virtual, hands-on experience in chip manufacturing, bridging the gap between theoretical knowledge and practical fab experience. It enables students to design, analyze, and optimize fabrication steps without physical wafers.</p><ul><li>SEMulator3D uses physics-based simulation to replicate fabrication processes like etch, deposition, and lithography.</li><li>It helps students understand the “why” behind process integration, fostering critical decision-making skills.</li><li>The platform runs on student laptops, ensuring accessibility for future semiconductor professionals globally.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/lt-semiconductor-hon-young-partner-for-650v-to-3300v-sic-wafer-development/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>L&amp;T Semiconductor and Hon Young Partner for High-Voltage SiC Wafer Development</strong><br>L&amp;T Semiconductor Technologies Ltd (LTSCT) has partnered with Hon Young Semiconductor (HYS) to develop high-voltage silicon carbide (SiC) wafers ranging from 650V to 3300V. This collaboration targets the growing demand for SiC devices in electric vehicles (EVs), renewable energy systems, and industrial applications, aiming to enhance energy efficiency through superior thermal performance and lower switching losses.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/power-modules-image-feature-image.jpg" alt="Power Modules"></p><ul><li>The partnership focuses on SiC wafers for power devices like SiC MOSFETs and Schottky barrier diodes.</li><li>SiC devices are critical for improving efficiency in EV chargers, solar inverters, and motor drives.</li><li>This collaboration seeks to ensure a stable supply and competitive pricing for global customers, fostering innovation and IP creation.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.yolegroup.com/news/power-sic-market-to-exceed-11-billion-by-2029-driven-by-evs-and-energy-transition/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Power SiC Market Poised for Significant Growth by 2029</strong><br>A recent analysis by Yole Group highlights the robust growth trajectory of the power SiC market, projecting it to exceed $11 billion by 2029. This substantial expansion is primarily fueled by increasing adoption in electric vehicles (EVs) and the broader energy transition. The report underscores the critical role of SiC technology in achieving higher efficiency and performance across various power electronics applications.</p><p><img src="https://www.yolegroup.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Yole_SiC_2024_Fig1-1024x576.jpg" alt="Power SiC Market Forecast"></p><ul><li>The market growth is driven by rising demand for SiC in EV main inverters and industrial applications.</li><li>SiC penetration is expanding across automotive, industrial, and energy sectors due to efficiency benefits.</li><li>Forecasts indicate continued high growth rates, solidifying SiC’s position as a key enabling technology.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/manufacturing-strategies-for-stretchable-synaptic-transistors/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Blueprint for Stretchable Synaptic Transistors Unveiled</strong><br>Researchers from Seoul National University have developed a comprehensive manufacturing “blueprint” for stretchable synaptic transistors, crucial for soft electronics. The review details how material selection, process flow (photopatterning, printing, lamination), and device architecture collectively determine the electro-mechanical stability and learning accuracy of these flexible devices, even under significant tensile strain.</p><ul><li>Key findings emphasize the importance of device architecture, with vertical organic transistors outperforming planar channels under deformation.</li><li>The insights advance soft neuromorphic hardware towards scalable, CMOS-compatible integration for on-skin wearables and bio-interactive prosthetics.</li><li>Challenges remain, including the need for ambipolar stretchable semiconductors and robust interfacial insulation for vertical stacking.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/physical-ai-needs-an-ecosystem/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Physical AI and Robotics Demand a Robust Ecosystem for Future Growth</strong><br>Industry experts, including Anders Billesø Beck from Universal Robots and Paul Williamson from Arm, highlight the critical need for a comprehensive technology ecosystem to drive the success of “physical AI” or “embodied AI” in robotics. While humanoid robots capture imagination, the immediate focus is on collaborative robots (cobots) for industrial automation, addressing complex, variable tasks that benefit immensely from AI-driven flexibility and software updates.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Universal-Robots-1-sq.jpg" alt="Universal Robots Cobot"></p><ul><li>AI enables cobots to handle high variability in tasks, accelerating automation in logistics and assembly.</li><li>Functional safety for AI-powered robotics is a significant challenge requiring innovation from silicon to ecosystem levels.</li><li>A strong partner ecosystem, including hardware peripherals and software plugins, is essential for integration and scaling AI deployments in robotics.</li></ul><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates as the semiconductor industry continues to push the boundaries of innovation and shapes the future of technology.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251030_etch_newsletter_gemini</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Etch" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Etch/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Neuromorphic" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Neuromorphic/"/>
    
    <category term="SiC" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/SiC/"/>
    
    <category term="Robotics" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Robotics/"/>
    
    <category term="STEM" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/STEM/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>DeepOHeat-v1- Enhancing 3D-IC Thermal Simulation with Operator Learning</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251028_DeepOHeat-v1--Enhancing-3D-IC-Thermal-Simulation-with-Operator-Learning/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251028_DeepOHeat-v1--Enhancing-3D-IC-Thermal-Simulation-with-Operator-Learning/</id>
    <published>2025-10-27T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-28T05:19:53.485Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251028_device_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/lt-semiconductor-hon-young-partner-for-650v-to-3300v-sic-wafer-development/">News</a></h2><p><strong>L&amp;T Semiconductor and Hon Young Partner on High-Voltage SiC Wafer Development</strong></p><p>L&amp;T Semiconductor Technologies (LTSCT) and Hon Young Semiconductor (HYS) have announced a long-term partnership to jointly develop high-voltage silicon carbide (SiC) wafers, ranging from 650V to 3300V. This collaboration aims to meet the escalating demand for SiC devices in critical sectors.</p><ul><li>The partnership targets automotive (EVs), renewable energy (solar inverters), and industrial applications.</li><li>SiC wafers provide a base for high-voltage power devices like MOSFETs and SBDs, offering lower switching losses and improved thermal performance over traditional silicon.</li><li>LTSCT, a fabless company, will leverage HYS’s SiC wafer fabrication expertise to ensure supply reliability, competitive pricing, and accelerate product development.</li></ul><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/power-modules-image-feature-image.jpg" alt="Power Modules"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/tekstart/362144-pioneering-edge-ai-tekstarts-newport-processor-ushers-in-a-new-era-of-efficient-intelligence/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>TekStart Unveils Newport, a High-Performance, Ultra-Low-Power Edge AI Processor</strong></p><p>TekStart Group’s ChipStart division has launched Newport, a groundbreaking Edge AI processor designed to bring advanced AI inference directly to where data is generated, with remarkable power efficiency. Newport delivers 65 TOPS peak performance while consuming under 2 watts.</p><ul><li>The processor addresses critical Edge AI challenges by enabling ultra-low-power, on-device learning and real-time inference, significantly reducing dependency on cloud computing.</li><li>Its versatile architecture allows seamless integration into diverse applications such as surveillance, agriculture, wearables, and industrial automation, supporting adaptive AI capabilities.</li><li>Newport is poised to power the future of agentic AI systems—proactive, autonomous, targeted, and collaborative—without the energy overhead of traditional interconnects.</li></ul><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/TekStart-Newport-Chip-SemiWiki-1200x554.jpg" alt="TekStart Newport Chip"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/thermal-simulation-and-optimization-in-3d-ic-design-intel-ucsb-cadence/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>DeepOHeat-v1: Enhancing 3D-IC Thermal Simulation with Operator Learning</strong></p><p>Researchers from Intel Corporation, University of California, Santa Barbara, and Cadence have published a new paper on DeepOHeat-v1, an enhanced physics-informed operator learning framework for fast and trustworthy thermal simulation and optimization in 3D-IC design.</p><ul><li>DeepOHeat-v1 achieves significant improvements:<ul><li><strong>1.25x and 6.29x reduction in error</strong> for multi-scale thermal patterns.</li><li><strong>62x training speedup and 31x GPU memory reduction</strong> using a separable training method.</li><li><strong>70.6x speedup</strong> for the entire thermal optimization process, effectively minimizing peak temperature through optimal placement of heat-generating components.</li></ul></li><li>The framework integrates Kolmogorov-Arnold Networks and provides a confidence score to evaluate result trustworthiness, ensuring high accuracy comparable to finite difference solvers.</li></ul><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/iStock-1441278907-11-29-23.jpeg" alt="3D-IC Thermal Simulation"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-10-memristor-ferroelectric-memory-energy-efficient.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Unified Memristor-Ferroelectric Memory for Energy-Efficient AI Training</strong></p><p>A research team from Université Grenoble Alpes, Université de Bordeaux, and Université Paris-Saclay has developed a novel memory device that unifies memristors and ferroelectric capacitors (FeCAPs) within a single stack. This hybrid approach promises significant advancements for energy-efficient training and implementation of AI systems.</p><ul><li>The memory combines the analog weight storage and energy efficiency during read operations of memristors, ideal for AI inference.</li><li>By integrating FeCAPs, it also offers rapid and low-energy updates, which are crucial for training machine learning algorithms and continuous learning in AI systems.</li><li>This breakthrough could enable more efficient edge AI, allowing AI algorithms to run directly on local hardware without heavy reliance on remote cloud servers.</li></ul><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/a-unified-memristor-fe.jpg" alt="Unified Memristor-Ferroelectric Memory"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/physical-ai-needs-an-ecosystem/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>The Growing Ecosystem Imperative for Physical AI (Robotics)</strong></p><p>Industry experts, including Anders Billesø Beck from Universal Robots and Paul Williamson from Arm, emphasize the critical need for a robust technology ecosystem to realize the full potential of “physical AI” or embodied AI in robotics. They highlight challenges and opportunities in this nascent field.</p><ul><li>AI is essential for “human-scale automation,” augmenting or replacing humans in variable tasks like logistics and complex assembly, which traditional engineering struggles with.</li><li>Functional safety for robotics is becoming increasingly complex with AI, requiring continuous innovation from silicon to ecosystem, with a focus on predictability and flexible safety capabilities.</li><li>A strong software ecosystem with commonality and interoperability is vital, allowing startups to focus on software innovation while leveraging established hardware infrastructure and support.</li></ul><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Universal-Robots-1-sq.jpg" alt="Universal Robots"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more cutting-edge developments shaping the future of semiconductors and intelligent systems.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251028_device_newsletter_gemi</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Edge AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Edge-AI/"/>
    
    <category term="SiC" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/SiC/"/>
    
    <category term="Photonics" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Photonics/"/>
    
    <category term="3D-IC" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/3D-IC/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>NextSilicon Unveils Runtime-Reconfigurable Architecture for HPC</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251027_NextSilicon-Unveils-Runtime-Reconfigurable-Architecture-for-HPC/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251027_NextSilicon-Unveils-Runtime-Reconfigurable-Architecture-for-HPC/</id>
    <published>2025-10-26T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-27T04:21:07.350Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251027_semiconductor_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.imec-int.com/en/articles/look-back-automotive-chiplet-forum-2025">News</a></h2><p><strong>Automotive Chiplet Forum 2025 Drives Collaboration for Next-Gen Vehicles</strong><br>The fall 2025 Automotive Chiplet Forum (ACF) in Heilbronn, Germany, highlighted a significant expansion of imec’s Automotive Chiplet Program (ACP). Key developments include:</p><ul><li>GlobalFoundries (GF) joined as a foundry partner, bringing advanced manufacturing capabilities and a global footprint.</li><li>Infineon, Silicon Box, STATS ChipPAC, and TIER IV (leader in autonomous driving) committed to participate, strengthening the ecosystem.</li><li>Discussions centered on the vision of building the “Airbus” of automotive high-performance computing (HPC) through chiplet-based platforms, reinforcing Europe’s leadership.</li><li>The event coincided with the inauguration of imec’s new Baden-Württemberg office, dedicated to automotive chiplet innovation.</li></ul><p>The forum emphasized that achieving digital sovereignty in automotive compute requires industry and government alignment on interoperable chiplets built on open standards.</p><p><img src="https://www.imec-int.com/sites/default/files/2025-10/ACF%20Fall%202025_0.jpg" alt="ACF Fall 2025"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/nextsilicon-details-runtime-reconfigurable-architecture/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>NextSilicon Unveils Runtime-Reconfigurable Architecture for HPC</strong><br>NextSilicon, an HPC silicon startup, has detailed its runtime-reconfigurable hardware architecture and showcased impressive benchmark results for its Maverick2 chip, built on TSMC 5nm.</p><ul><li>The Maverick2 dataflow chip is designed to replace traditional CPUs and GPUs in supercomputers by reconfiguring during runtime to accelerate code bottlenecks.</li><li>Its smart software algorithm continuously monitors applications, identifies critical “hot paths,” and reconfigures the chip in nanoseconds.</li><li>The architecture leverages dataflow processing, dedicating most silicon area to compute blocks (ALUs), enabling more computation per clock cycle.</li><li>NextSilicon’s stack can run any existing code (C++, Fortran, Python, CUDA, etc.) out of the box, offering flexibility for AI models and novel mathematical operations.</li><li>Benchmarks show superior performance: 5.2 TB&#x2F;s bandwidth in Stream, 32.6 GUPS at 460W, 600 GFLOPS at 600W for HPCG (outperforming CPUs&#x2F;GPUs), and 40 gigapages&#x2F;s for PageRank (10x better than GPUs).</li><li>The company also unveiled test silicon for Arbel, a 10-wide RISC-V CPU aimed at enterprise-grade performance, comparable to Intel’s Lion Cove or AMD Zen 5.</li></ul><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Maverick2-X-board-sq.jpg" alt="Maverick2 X-board"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/3dic/362862-chiplets-powering-the-next-generation-of-ai-systems/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Chiplets Poised for Explosive Growth, Fueling Next-Gen AI Systems</strong><br>Chiplets are rapidly becoming the cornerstone of advanced AI systems, projected to reach a substantial market value by 2035.</p><ul><li>The multi-die designs, which break down large SoC functions into smaller, reusable dies, are forecasted to become a <strong>$411 billion market by 2035</strong>.</li><li>This growth is driven by the fact that traditional SoC scaling can no longer meet the demanding compute and I&#x2F;O needs of modern AI workloads, making modular chiplets a crucial solution.</li><li>Interconnect performance, with UCIe (Universal Chiplet Interconnect Express) emerging as the preferred die-to-die standard, is critical for chiplet success.</li><li>Advanced packaging techniques, including 2.5D and 3D approaches, are central to integrating these chiplets, requiring early co-design to manage thermal, mechanical, and power integrity challenges.</li><li>Collaborations, such as that between Synopsys and Arm, are essential to streamline AI chip design, focusing on interoperability, reliability, and security within the evolving chiplet ecosystem.</li></ul><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Arm-Synopsys-at-Chiplet-Summit.png" alt="Arm Synopsys at Chiplet Summit"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/diamond-thermal-conductivity">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Stanford Researchers Pioneer Low-Temperature Diamond for Advanced Chip Cooling</strong><br>Groundbreaking research from Stanford University has unveiled a method to grow polycrystalline diamond at low temperatures, offering a revolutionary solution for chip cooling.</p><ul><li>As transistors miniaturize and power densities soar, heat management becomes critical, with hot spots causing performance throttling and device degradation.</li><li>Diamond, a highly thermally conductive yet electrically insulating material, has been challenging to integrate due to high growth temperatures (over 1,000 °C).</li><li>Researchers achieved low-temperature growth (below 400 °C) by adding oxygen, which selectively etched away non-diamond carbon deposits, allowing large-grained polycrystalline diamond to form around devices.</li><li>A key discovery was the formation of a silicon carbide interlayer at the diamond-semiconductor boundary, acting as a “bridge” for phonons and significantly reducing thermal boundary resistance.</li><li>Initial tests on gallium-nitride (GaN) high-electron-mobility transistors (HEMTs) showed channel temperatures dropped by a remarkable 70 °C, boosting RF signal amplification fivefold.</li><li>This innovation holds immense potential for high-power CMOS chips and 3D-stacked architectures, where “thermal scaffolding” with diamond layers and pillars could extract heat efficiently from multiple layers.</li></ul><p><img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=61766396&width=1200&height=600&coordinates=0,1048,0,1048" alt="Diamond Thermal Conductivity"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/powering-efficiency-ai-transforms-ic-manufacturing-as-ics-fuel-ai/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>AI Transforms IC Manufacturing While ICs Fuel AI: Key Takeaways from SEMICON West</strong><br>SEMICON West 2025 highlighted a virtuous cycle where AI is reshaping semiconductor manufacturing and design, while advanced ICs power the AI revolution. Industry leaders discussed the massive opportunities and challenges.</p><ul><li><strong>AI Factories &amp; Physical AI:</strong> Nvidia’s Timothy Costa emphasized $2 trillion opportunities in AI factories and physical AI, requiring innovation across semiconductor design, manufacturing, and AI. This includes accelerated design workloads, agentic AI for engineers, digital twins for fabs, and vision AI for defect detection.</li><li><strong>Digital Twins for Yield Optimization:</strong> Joseph Ervin of Lam Research showcased how fab-centric digital twins, leveraging virtual process modeling and machine learning, are crucial for rapidly boosting yield and shortening yield ramps in high-volume manufacturing, especially as process windows shrink.</li><li><strong>Sustainability &amp; Energy Efficiency:</strong> Executives from ASM, IBM Research, Merck KGaA, and TEL America stressed the urgent need to combine technology development with sustainability, addressing the immense power consumption of AI data centers. Materials innovation and integrated development processes are key to energy-efficient scaling.</li><li><strong>Democratizing Design with AI:</strong> Mukesh Khare from IBM Research highlighted the role of agentic AI and open ecosystems in democratizing chip design, aiming for a 50% improvement in productivity for complex chip design activities.</li><li><strong>Continuous Innovation:</strong> The discussions underscored a newfound drive to accelerate the development of materials, equipment, processes, and servers, while simultaneously improving operating efficiencies across the entire supply chain.</li></ul><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Screenshot-2025-10-22-at-3.20.21-PM.png" alt="SEMICON West 2025 Panel"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more cutting-edge developments and expert analysis shaping the semiconductor landscape!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251027_semiconductor_newslett</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Chiplets" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Chiplets/"/>
    
    <category term="Edge AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Edge-AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Advanced Materials" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Advanced-Materials/"/>
    
    <category term="Thermal Management" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Thermal-Management/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>NextSilicon Details Runtime Reconfigurable Architecture</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251023_NextSilicon-Details-Runtime-Reconfigurable-Architecture/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251023_NextSilicon-Details-Runtime-Reconfigurable-Architecture/</id>
    <published>2025-10-22T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-24T18:38:51.535Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251023_etch_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.tel.com/news/ir/2025/20251015_001.html">News</a></h2><p><strong>Tokyo Electron Completes Construction of New Development Building in Kyushu</strong><br>Tokyo Electron (TEL) has announced the completion of its new Process Development Building in Koshi-shi, Kumamoto, for its manufacturing and development subsidiary, Tokyo Electron Kyushu. This 47 billion yen investment underscores TEL’s commitment to innovation in semiconductor manufacturing equipment, including:</p><ul><li><strong>Next-Generation Development Hub</strong>: The new facility will focus on developing coater&#x2F;developers, cleaning systems, and advanced 3D packaging equipment like wafer bonders.</li><li><strong>Driving Innovation</strong>: These products are crucial for enabling ultra-high speeds, large capacities, high reliability, and power efficiency in semiconductor devices, supporting trends in finer scaling and higher integration.</li><li><strong>Sustainable Growth</strong>: The building is designed for advanced, efficient operations leveraging digital technologies, prioritizing safety, quality, and environmental considerations to deliver high-value products to customers.</li></ul><p><img src="https://www.tel.com/news/ir/2025/s0s3re00000000hi-img/s0s3re00000000jj.jpg" alt="Tokyo Electron Kyushu New Development Building"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://newsroom.lamresearch.com/virtualization-AI-from-fabtex-yield-optimizer-ramps-up-yield-in-semiconductor-manufacturing?blog=true">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Lam CVP David Fried Shares with EE Times How Fabtex™ Yield Optimizer Is Transforming Semiconductor Manufacturing with Virtual Twins and AI</strong><br>Lam Research has introduced Fabtex™ Yield Optimizer, a new tool under its Semiverse® Solutions platform, aimed at tackling yield variability in high-volume semiconductor manufacturing. This innovative solution leverages advanced computational techniques to:</p><ul><li><strong>Reduce Process Variability</strong>: Combines virtual silicon digital twins with inline fab data and optimization algorithms.</li><li><strong>Accelerate Issue Resolution</strong>: Helps manufacturers quickly identify and fix defects, leading to faster cycle times and reduced wafer waste.</li><li><strong>Cost Savings</strong>: Significant operational benefits for fabs by making virtual silicon more representative of real-world fab variations and targeting systematic yield-limiting mechanisms simultaneously.</li></ul><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.semi.org/en/news-media-press/semi-press/semi-reports-record-semiconductor-equipment-sales-in-2023-forecasts-growth">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>SEMI Reports Record Semiconductor Equipment Sales in 2023, Forecasts Growth</strong><br>The global semiconductor equipment market continues its robust growth trajectory, driven by increasing demand for advanced chips. According to SEMI, equipment sales are expected to rebound strongly, indicating sustained investment in manufacturing capacity and technology upgrades.</p><ul><li><strong>Market Resilience</strong>: Despite recent fluctuations, the semiconductor equipment market demonstrated strong performance, with record sales indicating healthy industry fundamentals.</li><li><strong>Regional Investment</strong>: Specific regions show significant investment, reflecting strategic moves in manufacturing and supply chain localization.</li><li><strong>Future Outlook</strong>: Industry forecasts predict continued growth, driven by expansion in AI, HPC, and IoT sectors, necessitating advanced fab equipment.</li></ul><p><img src="https://www.semi.org/sites/semi.org/files/2024-05/WW%20Total%20Fab%20Equipment%20Forecast%20-%20May%202024.jpg" alt="Semiconductor Equipment Market Size by Region"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/nextsilicon-details-runtime-reconfigurable-architecture/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>NextSilicon Details Runtime Reconfigurable Architecture</strong><br>HPC silicon startup NextSilicon has unveiled its innovative runtime-reconfigurable hardware architecture, demonstrating potential to outperform traditional CPUs and GPUs for scientific computing and HPC benchmarks. Key aspects of their Maverick2 chip include:</p><ul><li><strong>Runtime Reconfigurability</strong>: The dataflow chip dynamically reconfigures its hardware during runtime to accelerate “hot paths” (1% of code running 99% of the time), mitigating code bottlenecks in nanoseconds.</li><li><strong>Dataflow Processing</strong>: Unlike traditional architectures, NextSilicon’s chip dedicates most silicon area to compute blocks (ALUs), optimized for computation-heavy workloads and avoiding memory bottlenecks.</li><li><strong>Software Compatibility</strong>: The architecture supports any existing code (C++, Fortran, Python, CUDA, AI frameworks) without requiring rewrites, compiling it for both host CPU and reconfigurable hardware.</li><li><strong>Impressive Benchmarks</strong>: Test results on TSMC 5nm Maverick2 silicon show significant performance gains in Stream (5.2 TB&#x2F;s), GUPS (32.6 GUPS at 460W), HPCG (600 GFLOPS at 600W), and PageRank (10x better than GPUs at half the power).</li><li><strong>Future Vision</strong>: NextSilicon is also developing a 10-wide RISC-V CPU, Arbel, as a host for its next-gen accelerator, Maverick3, aiming for vertical integration and enhanced performance.</li></ul><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Maverick2-X-board-sq.jpg" alt="Maverick2 X board"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/silicon-valley-events-highlight-rapid-innovation-from-power-to-edge-ai/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Silicon Valley Events Highlight Innovation from Power to Edge AI</strong><br>Recent Silicon Valley events, including OCP Summit, Synaptics Tech Day, and Infineon’s OktoberTech, showcased a rapid pace of innovation driven by the explosive growth of AI. Industry leaders emphasized key trends and challenges:</p><ul><li><strong>AI Power Demands</strong>: A predominant concern is the massive power consumption of AI data centers, spurring innovation in cooling methods, 800V DC power solutions, and advanced packaging for efficiency.</li><li><strong>Ecosystem Collaboration</strong>: The necessity for industry-wide collaboration and open standards was a recurring theme, with a realization that no single company can tackle the immense challenges, such as co-packaged optics, alone.</li><li><strong>Edge AI Evolution</strong>: Discussions at Synaptics Tech Day highlighted the maturation of edge AI, moving beyond fragmentation towards “intelligence of things” through open edge AI initiatives and partnerships with major tech players.</li><li><strong>Quantum Computing on the Horizon</strong>: Infineon’s event underscored the growing relevance of quantum computing, with leaders asserting that it is “already happening now” and engineers should not be complacent.</li><li><strong>Silicon Valley’s Resurgence</strong>: Attendees noted an unprecedented energy and collaborative spirit in Silicon Valley, indicating a thriving environment for invention and problem-solving across hardware and software.</li></ul><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/OCP-Summit-2025_image-source_nitin-dahad_sq.jpg" alt="OCP Summit 2025"></p><hr><p>Stay connected with us for the latest news and in-depth analysis shaping the future of the semiconductor industry.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251023_etch_newsletter_gemini</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Etch" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Etch/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor Manufacturing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor-Manufacturing/"/>
    
    <category term="HPC" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/HPC/"/>
    
    <category term="Runtime Reconfiguration" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Runtime-Reconfiguration/"/>
    
    <category term="Yield Optimization" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Yield-Optimization/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>3D Printable Photochromic Materials Enable All-Optical Processors</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251022_3D-Printable-Photochromic-Materials-Enable-All-Optical-Processors/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251022_3D-Printable-Photochromic-Materials-Enable-All-Optical-Processors/</id>
    <published>2025-10-21T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-22T22:15:11.624Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251022_lithography_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.asml.com/en/news/press-releases/2025/asml-mistral-ai-enter-strategic-partnership">News</a></h2><p><strong>ASML and Mistral AI Forge Strategic Partnership to Advance Lithography with AI</strong><br>ASML Holding NV has announced a strategic partnership with France-based AI leader Mistral AI, backed by a significant €1.3 billion investment in Mistral AI’s Series C funding round, resulting in ASML holding an approximately 11% share. This long-term collaboration aims to integrate advanced AI models across ASML’s entire product portfolio, including research, development, and operations. The partnership seeks to:</p><ul><li>Deliver innovative products and solutions to ASML customers.</li><li>Accelerate time to market and enhance the performance of holistic lithography systems.</li><li>Explore potential for joint research to address future opportunities in the semiconductor and AI value chain.</li></ul><p>As part of the investment, ASML Chief Financial Officer Roger Dassen will join Mistral AI’s Strategic Committee, providing an advisory role in the AI company’s future strategy and technology decisions.</p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-025-01974-z">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>3D Printable Photochromic Materials Enable All-Optical Processors</strong><br>Researchers have developed novel 3D-printable photochromic materials that enable all-optical processors capable of performing arithmetic operations using light. These materials, based on an oligomer and photoinitiator doped with photochromic molecules (SP or BTF6), dynamically switch between colorless and colored states upon exposure to UV and green light.</p><ul><li><strong>Key Functionality</strong>: The photochromic properties allow for dynamic control of light signals, enabling multi-step photoswitching.</li><li><strong>Arithmetic Operations</strong>: Demonstrated arithmetic operations like addition and division, and logic gates (NOT, NOR), by precisely controlling light transmission through the material.</li><li><strong>Architectural Innovation</strong>: The technology supports new architectures, including 3D spiral-shaped components for parallel processing, where each element can be individually addressed.</li><li><strong>Enhanced Stability</strong>: BTF6-doped samples exhibit exceptional thermal stability, retaining their encoded configurations for over twelve months, making them highly suitable for long-term data storage applications.</li></ul><p><img src="https://media.springernature.com/m685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41377-025-01974-z/MediaObjects/41377_2025_1974_Figa_HTML.png" alt="3D printable photochromic materials"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.trendforce.com/news/2025/09/18/news-samsung-reportedly-outsources-photomasks-for-the-first-time-eyes-new-masks-tech-for-euv/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Samsung Ventures into Photomask Outsourcing While Eyeing New EUV Mask Technologies</strong><br>Samsung is reportedly initiating its first-time outsourcing of lower-end photomasks, specifically i-line and KrF masks for memory chip production, to external suppliers such as PKL and potentially Tekscend Photomask. This strategic shift is driven by several factors:</p><ul><li><strong>Resource Reallocation</strong>: Allows Samsung to dedicate internal resources and R&amp;D efforts towards advanced ArF and <strong>EUV photomask</strong> production for cutting-edge logic chips.</li><li><strong>Market Dynamics</strong>: The South Korean photomask market, valued around the mid-700 billion won range last year, is experiencing high demand with domestic manufacturers operating above 90% capacity, indicating potential supply chain impacts for rival foundries.</li><li><strong>Technological Push</strong>: Samsung is accelerating the adoption of Phase Shift Masks (PSM) in logic semiconductor manufacturing, developing methods to apply PSM to <strong>EUV lithography</strong> processes to achieve enhanced precision for sub-3nm patterning.</li><li><strong>Increasing Demand</strong>: The number of photomasks required for advanced DRAMs has surged from 30-40 to over 60, primarily due to the increasing complexity of multi-patterning techniques.</li></ul><p><img src="https://img.trendforce.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/17162846/Tekscend-photomask-japan-20250917-624x447.jpg" alt="Photomask image"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/first-stage-of-nanoscale-imaging-in-positive-tone-euv-photoresists-the-impact-of-polymer-sequence-berkeley-lab-columbia-hill/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Unraveling Nanoscale Imaging in Positive-Tone EUV Photoresists</strong><br>A new technical paper by researchers at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory and Columbia Hill Technical Consulting investigates the initial stages of nanoscale imaging in positive-tone Extreme Ultraviolet (<strong>EUV</strong>) photoresists. The study focuses on understanding how polymer chain structure influences the radiolytic process that defines image resolution.</p><ul><li><strong>Process Overview</strong>: EUV exposure in photoresists is a radiolytic process that generates electrons, radicals, and ions, which are critical for defining the printed image.</li><li><strong>Research Focus</strong>: The study simulated the sub-picosecond stages of imaging, specifically evaluating the influence of defined sequence and random copolymer structures on radiolytic spur formation—clusters of species formed by electron-polymer interactions.</li><li><strong>Key Finding</strong>: Computational results, validated against literature on electron thermalization, revealed that the polymer sequence has no significant effect on spur composition. This implies that potential imaging improvements from polymer sequence control would likely arise from subsequent lithographic process steps rather than the initial EUV exposure itself.</li></ul><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_560372105-04-15-24.jpeg" alt="EUV Photoresist Image"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/lithography/362824-how-secondary-electrons-worsen-euv-stochastics/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Understanding How Secondary Electrons Worsen EUV Stochastics and Limit Dose Returns</strong><br>In <strong>EUV lithography</strong>, increasing dose leads to diminishing returns in reducing stochastic effects, as electron noise increasingly dominates over photon noise. A recent analysis highlights the direct contribution of electrons to these stochastic variations:</p><ul><li><strong>Electron Variability</strong>: Each absorbed EUV photon releases a random number of photoelectrons and subsequent secondary electrons, creating significant statistical fluctuations in energy deposition.</li><li><strong>Dose Limitations</strong>: Unlike classical photon shot noise, which decreases with increasing dose, electron noise exhibits an asymptotic limit. This means that at higher doses, electron noise becomes the dominant factor, severely limiting further improvements in stochastic behavior.</li><li><strong>Blurring and Defects</strong>: Electron scattering causes a blurring effect that reduces image contrast. Local fluctuations in electron density are more likely to cross printing thresholds, potentially leading to critical defects such as microbridging, especially along feature edges.</li><li><strong>Scaling Challenges</strong>: As feature sizes shrink to 10 nm half-pitch and below, pixel sizes decrease, resulting in fewer absorbed photons per pixel even with increased dose. This exacerbates both photon and electron noise, leading to higher probabilities of defect formation.</li></ul><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/How-Secondary-Electrons-Worsen-EUV-Stochastics-1.jpg" alt="EUV Stochastic Image"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more cutting-edge developments and insights shaping the semiconductor landscape!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251022_lithography_newsletter</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Lithography/"/>
    
    
    <category term="photomask" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/photomask/"/>
    
    <category term="EUV lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/EUV-lithography/"/>
    
    <category term="AI integration" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI-integration/"/>
    
    <category term="optical computing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/optical-computing/"/>
    
    <category term="perovskite" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/perovskite/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The AI PC- A New Category Poised to Reignite the PC Market</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251021_The-AI-PC--A-New-Category-Poised-to-Reignite-the-PC-Market/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251021_The-AI-PC--A-New-Category-Poised-to-Reignite-the-PC-Market/</id>
    <published>2025-10-20T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-21T04:19:59.169Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251021_device_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">    Your browser does not support the audio element.  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/texas-instruments-on-its-path-to-95-in-house-manufacturing-by-2030/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Texas Instruments On Its Path to 95% In-House Manufacturing by 2030</strong><br>Texas Instruments (TI) is aggressively pursuing a strategy to increase its self-reliance in semiconductor production, aiming to grow its internal manufacturing capacity to over 95% by 2030. Stefan Bruder, President of TI EMEA and India, highlighted the company’s commitment to investing more than $60 billion in seven fabs across three U.S. mega-sites in Texas and Utah since 2021, including a significant $40 billion at its new 300mm site in Sherman, Texas. This initiative is designed to ensure geopolitically dependable capacity and supply chain resilience by enabling dual-flow capabilities across different global manufacturing locations. TI is also focusing on local raw material procurement to further enhance supply chain stability. The company’s AI strategy encompasses both power-efficient gallium nitride (GaN) products for data centers and embedded AI capabilities in edge devices, such as their C2000 microcontrollers for solar inverters, many of which are being developed in collaboration with its large R&amp;D hub in India.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Low-cost-MCU-F28E120SC-and-F28E120SB-1.jpg" alt="Texas Instruments Low-cost MCU"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/broadcom-expands-ai-ethernet-offerings/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Broadcom Expands AI Ethernet Offerings with Tomahawk 6 CPO Switch and Thor Ultra NIC</strong><br>Broadcom Inc. is significantly enhancing its AI networking portfolio with the launch of its Tomahawk 6 – Davisson (TH6-Davisson) Co-Packaged Optics (CPO) Ethernet switch and the Thor Ultra 800G AI Ethernet Network Interface Card (NIC). The TH6-Davisson, Broadcom’s third-generation CPO Ethernet switch, doubles the bandwidth of existing CPO switches, delivering 102.4 Terabits per second of optically enabled switching capacity while improving power efficiency and traffic stability critical for large-scale AI clusters. This advancement addresses the exploding demand for optical interconnects in AI networks, driven by GPUs requiring substantially more optical bandwidth than traditional CPUs. Concurrently, the Thor Ultra 800G AI Ethernet NIC, now sampling, is the industry’s first to support a single 800G flow and adopts the Ultra Ethernet Consortium (UEC) specification. This enables advanced RDMA capabilities, including packet-level multipathing, out-of-order packet delivery, selective retransmit, and scalable congestion control, providing an open and efficient solution for interconnecting hundreds of thousands of XPUs in AI workloads.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Broadcom-AInetworking-covercarousel.png" alt="Broadcom AI Networking"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/362815-the-ai-pc-a-new-category-poised-to-reignite-the-pc-market/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>The AI PC: A New Category Poised to Reignite the PC Market</strong><br>The personal computing industry is experiencing its most significant transformation since the 1980s with the emergence of the AI PC, a category poised to reignite growth in a previously plateaued market. Defined by the integration of a dedicated Neural Processing Unit (NPU) or equivalent accelerator, AI PCs enable on-device machine learning, running large language models, generative tools, and real-time personalization locally. Apple has established an early lead by incorporating its Neural Engine into all M-series Macs since 2020, achieving seamless vertical integration across silicon, OS, and frameworks. While Intel and AMD are rapidly catching up with their NPU-equipped platforms, only about 30% of x86 PCs shipped in 2025 qualify as AI PCs. Gartner projects a substantial market surge, with AI PC shipments expected to reach approximately 114 million units in 2025, a 165% increase over 2024, representing over 40% of the total PC market. This shift reflects both corporate demand for efficiency tools and individual users’ desire for local AI capabilities, promising to redefine productivity and creativity in the digital era.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Fig-1.jpg" alt="AI PC Shipments Chart"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-10-team-high-ultra-power-superconductive.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Team Develops High-Speed, Ultra-Low-Power Superconductive Neuron Device for Neuromorphic Computing</strong><br>Researchers have developed a novel superconductive neuron device that promises to advance large-scale, high-speed, and ultra-low-power neuromorphic network circuits. Published in <em>Neuromorphic Computing and Engineering</em>, this groundbreaking device employs digital processing using superconducting circuits that utilize magnetic flux quanta as signal carriers. This approach significantly eliminates variations in the characteristics of elemental circuits, a common challenge in hardware implementation of neuromorphic systems. The team’s compact design implements the Rectified Linear Unit (ReLU) activation function through frequency conversion, leveraging single flux quantum logic. A key advantage is its remarkable robustness against device variability, maintaining ideal input-output characteristics even with up to 20% parameter variations. This marks a substantial improvement over conventional analog-based neuron devices, which are highly sensitive to non-uniformity and often suffer from high power consumption and limited capacity. This innovation paves the way for scalable superconducting neural networks, offering a path to ultra-high-speed and energy-efficient AI applications.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2025/team-develops-high-spe.jpg" alt="Superconductive Neuron Device"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/events/362577-webinar-ip-design-considerations-for-real-time-edge-ai-systems/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Synopsys Webinar: IP Design Considerations for Real-Time Edge AI Systems</strong><br>A recent webinar presented by Synopsys, featuring Hezi Saar, Executive Director of Product Line Management for Mobile, Automotive, and Consumer IP, delved into the critical IP design considerations for real-time AI systems at the edge. Saar, drawing from over two decades of experience in the semiconductor industry, provided a comprehensive overview of how AI is driving semiconductor growth and the motivations behind shifting AI workloads from the cloud to edge devices. He highlighted that power efficiency is a crucial factor, with on-device (edge) AI demonstrating up to 200 times more efficiency compared to cloud-based solutions. The presentation explored the unique requirements for cost, performance, area, and power across a broad range of smart and connected edge devices. Saar also discussed the increasing quality of small models for edge AI, the role of AI companion chips, and the impact of multi-die approaches in addressing consumer demands for cost-effective products, emphasizing that this shift is driving the next innovation cycle in the industry.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Webinar-%E2%80%93-IP-Design-Considerations-for-Real-Time-Edge-AI-Systems-1200x570.png" alt="Synopsys Webinar on Edge AI Systems"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more essential insights and updates as the semiconductor industry continues to innovate and redefine the future of technology!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251021_device_newsletter_gemi</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Advanced Packaging" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Advanced-Packaging/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor Manufacturing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor-Manufacturing/"/>
    
    <category term="Chiplets" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Chiplets/"/>
    
    <category term="Machine Learning" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Machine-Learning/"/>
    
    <category term="Edge AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Edge-AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Neuromorphic Computing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Neuromorphic-Computing/"/>
    
    <category term="Ethernet" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Ethernet/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Rise, Fall, and Rebirth of In-Circuit Emulation</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251021_The-Rise,-Fall,-and-Rebirth-of-In-Circuit-Emulation/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251021_The-Rise,-Fall,-and-Rebirth-of-In-Circuit-Emulation/</id>
    <published>2025-10-20T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-21T19:03:02.635Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251021_device_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">    Your browser does not support the audio element.  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-10-group-nvidia-blackrock-buying-aligned.html">News</a></h2><p><strong>Group including Nvidia, BlackRock buying Aligned Data Centers in deal worth about $40 billion</strong><br>A consortium featuring BlackRock, Nvidia, and Microsoft is set to acquire Aligned Data Centers in a substantial $40 billion deal. This strategic investment aims to bolster and expand critical next-generation cloud and artificial intelligence (AI) infrastructure. The acquisition addresses the burgeoning demand for robust computing resources and data center capacity fueled by the rapid growth of the AI sector. Aligned Data Centers brings a formidable portfolio of 50 campuses and over 5 gigawatts of operational and planned capacity across the U.S. and Latin America. As the inaugural transaction for the Artificial Intelligence Infrastructure Partnership (AIP), this initiative plans to mobilize $30 billion in initial equity capital, with potential to scale to $100 billion including debt, highlighting the immense capital flowing into AI infrastructure development.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/group-including-nvidia.jpg" alt="Group including Nvidia, BlackRock buying Aligned Data Centers in deal worth about $40 billion"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/athos-spins-out-of-mercedes-with-chiplet-concept-for-avs/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Athos Spins Out Of Mercedes With Chiplet Concept for AVs</strong><br>Athos Silicon has officially spun out of Mercedes-Benz, emerging from a five-year research project focused on creating functionally safe compute solutions for autonomous vehicles (AVs). Mercedes-Benz has provided a strategic investment, including substantial intellectual property, and will continue to collaborate on Athos’s mSoC reference design, Polaris. The Polaris architecture is designed with functional safety as a primary consideration, leveraging a chiplet-based approach that integrates three compute dies, a central cache, and an NPU, all sourced from third-party suppliers. A core innovation is Athos’s unique voting mechanism, which uses an odd number of chiplets (starting with three) to ensure continuous safety by monitoring for both software and hardware issues. This design promises enhanced performance and reliability at a lower cost, extending its applications beyond automotive to other autonomous systems like drones and robots.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Mercedes-sq.jpg" alt="Athos Spins Out Of Mercedes With Chiplet Concept for AVs"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/new-release-microelectronics-and-advanced-packaging-technologies-roadmap-2-0-src/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Microelectronics and Advanced Packaging Technologies Roadmap 2.0 (SRC)</strong><br>The Semiconductor Research Corporation (SRC) has unveiled its comprehensive Microelectronics and Advanced Packaging Technologies (MAPT) Roadmap 2.0. This updated industry-wide framework, which represents the first 3D semiconductor roadmap, incorporates contributions from over 370 experts across 132 organizations. Funded by the U.S. Department of Commerce’s NIST and developed to support the CHIPS Act, the roadmap provides a crucial strategic guide for the entire semiconductor supply chain. Notably, it includes a new chapter dedicated to digital twins and their applications, reflecting the evolving landscape of semiconductor design and manufacturing. The MAPT Roadmap 2.0 is an essential resource for guiding R&amp;D, investment, and collaborative efforts within the global semiconductor ecosystem.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Screenshot-2025-10-14-at-12.56.47-PM.png" alt="Microelectronics and Advanced Packaging Technologies Roadmap 2.0. Source: Semiconductor Research Corporation"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/3dic/362188-cmos-2-0-is-advancing-semiconductor-scaling/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>CMOS 2.0 is Advancing Semiconductor Scaling</strong><br>Imec’s recent breakthroughs in wafer-to-wafer hybrid bonding and backside connectivity are pioneering the development of “CMOS 2.0,” a significant paradigm shift in chip design. CMOS 2.0 addresses the traditional limitations of CMOS scaling by segmenting System-on-Chip (SoC) designs into specialized functional tiers. Each tier is meticulously optimized for specific requirements, such as high-performance logic, dense memory, or superior power efficiency, through advanced system-technology co-optimization (STCO). This innovative approach leverages 3D interconnects and backside power delivery networks (BSPDNs) to enable ultra-dense connections and power distribution on both sides of the wafer. At VLSI 2025, Imec showcased impressive advancements, including 250nm pitch wafer-to-wafer hybrid bonding and 120nm pitch through-dielectric vias (TDVs). These technologies facilitate sophisticated heterogeneous stacking and enhance power efficiency by drastically reducing IR drops and decongesting frontside interconnects, which is critical for future mobile SoCs and AI accelerators.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/CMOS-2.0.jpg" alt="CMOS 2.0 is Advancing Semiconductor Scaling"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/eda/synopsys/362661-the-rise-fall-and-rebirth-of-in-circuit-emulation-real-world-case-studies-part-2-of-2/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>The Rise, Fall, and Rebirth of In-Circuit Emulation</strong><br>This in-depth article, featuring insights from Synopsys’s distinguished experts, chronicles the remarkable resurgence of in-circuit emulation (ICE) in system-level validation, largely driven by the evolution of third-generation speed adapters. Defying previous predictions of its obsolescence, modern ICE platforms, particularly those integrating Synopsys Speed Adapters and the System Validation Server (SVS), are proving indispensable for critical pre-silicon bug detection. Through compelling real-world case studies, the article demonstrates how high-fidelity ICE environments can uncover elusive RTL flaws, timing mismatches, and complex interoperability issues tied to low-level system behavior and physical layers (e.g., PCIe Gen5, UFS, Ethernet, MIPI sensors) that often escape virtual verification methods. By accurately simulating real-world operating conditions and rigorously enforcing design specifications, ICE significantly mitigates the risk of costly re-spins and accelerates time-to-tapeout, solidifying its role as an essential tool in the development of today’s increasingly complex semiconductor designs.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/The-Rise-Fall-and-Rebirth-of-In-Circuit-Emulation-real-world-case-studies-figure-1.png" alt="The Rise, Fall, and Rebirth of In-Circuit Emulation real world case studies figure 1"></p><hr><p>Stay connected for the latest innovations and breakthroughs shaping the future of the semiconductor industry!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251021_device_newsletter_gemi</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Advanced Packaging" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Advanced-Packaging/"/>
    
    <category term="Security" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Security/"/>
    
    <category term="Chiplets" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Chiplets/"/>
    
    <category term="EDA" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/EDA/"/>
    
    <category term="LLMs" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/LLMs/"/>
    
    <category term="Verification" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Verification/"/>
    
    <category term="Automotive" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Automotive/"/>
    
    <category term="Data Centers" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Data-Centers/"/>
    
    <category term="DRAM" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/DRAM/"/>
    
    <category term="GaN" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/GaN/"/>
    
    <category term="Sub-3nm" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Sub-3nm/"/>
    
    <category term="CMOS 2.0" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/CMOS-2-0/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>GlobalFoundries, Infineon, Silicon Box, STATS ChipPAC, and TIER IV Join imec Automotive Chiplet Program</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251020_GlobalFoundries,-Infineon,-Silicon-Box,-STATS-ChipPAC,-and-TIER-IV-Join-imec-Automotive-Chiplet-Program/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251020_GlobalFoundries,-Infineon,-Silicon-Box,-STATS-ChipPAC,-and-TIER-IV-Join-imec-Automotive-Chiplet-Program/</id>
    <published>2025-10-19T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-20T04:23:23.873Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251020_semiconductor_newsletter_gemini-2.5-flash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">    Your browser does not support the audio element.  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.imec-int.com/en/press/GlobalFoundries-Infineon-silicon-box-STATS-ChipPAC-TIER-IV-Join-imec-Automotive-Chiplet-Program">News</a></h2><p><strong>GlobalFoundries, Infineon, Silicon Box, STATS ChipPAC, and TIER IV Join imec Automotive Chiplet Program</strong><br>Imec has announced that leading industry players, including GlobalFoundries (GF), Infineon, Silicon Box, STATS ChipPAC, and Japanese autonomous driving technology developer TIER IV, have joined its Automotive Chiplet Program (ACP). This collaborative research initiative aims to accelerate the development and adoption of advanced chiplet architectures and packaging technologies specifically tailored for the stringent safety and reliability demands of the automotive sector. As vehicles increasingly evolve into high-performance, software-defined platforms, traditional monolithic chip designs face growing challenges. Chiplets offer a scalable, flexible, and cost-effective alternative. As a foundry partner, GF will contribute its advanced manufacturing capabilities and global fab footprint to support the development of automotive-ready, chiplet-based platforms and the qualification of critical interconnect technologies. This move highlights a significant industry collaboration to drive innovation in automotive semiconductors.</p><p><img src="https://www.imec-int.com/sites/default/files/2025-10/Header_AdobeStock_1557709119.jpg" alt="imec Automotive Chiplet Program"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/google-open-sources-npu-ip-synaptics-implements-it/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Google Open-Sources Coral NPU IP, Synaptics Implements It in Astra IoT SoCs</strong><br>Google Research has open-sourced its Coral NPU IP (previously codenamed Kelvin), a 4-way superscalar 32-bit RISC-V CPU, to foster growth in the edge AI ecosystem by mitigating fragmentation and bolstering security. Synaptics is the first company to implement this NPU in silicon, integrating it into its Astra SL2610 series of AI-enabled IoT device SoCs. Google’s initiative aims to provide an open-standards-based platform, offering flexibility and extensibility without requiring licensing fees. Synaptics’ Torq solution combines the Coral NPU with its proprietary T1 AI accelerator, supported by an open-source toolchain based on MLIR&#x2F;IREE. This development is set to simplify and accelerate the deployment of AI workloads across various IoT applications, from smart appliances to drones.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Earbud.jpg" alt="Google Coral NPU Synaptics IoT Earbud"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-10-taiwanese-chipmaker-tsmc-net-profit.html">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Taiwanese chipmaker TSMC sees nearly 40% jump in its net profit thanks to the AI boom</strong><br>Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Corp. (TSMC), the world’s leading semiconductor foundry, reported a remarkable financial performance for the July-September quarter. The company announced a record net profit of NT$452.3 billion ($15 billion), marking a nearly 40% year-on-year increase. This substantial surge in profitability is largely attributed to the unprecedented demand driven by the artificial intelligence (AI) boom. TSMC’s revenue also saw a significant 30% jump compared to the previous year, surpassing market expectations. The company continues to make substantial investments, including over $100 billion in the U.S. (with up to $40 billion at its new 300mm site in Sherman, Texas) and additional fabs in Japan, to ensure a geopolitically dependable and robust manufacturing capacity capable of meeting the “unyielding” global demand for its advanced semiconductor products, particularly those fueling the AI revolution.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/taiwanese-chipmaker-ts.jpg" alt="TSMC Net Profit"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/kaist-develops-an-ai-semiconductor-brain-combining-transformers-intelligence-and-mambas-efficiency/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>KAIST Develops an AI Semiconductor Brain Combining Transformer’s Intelligence and Mamba’s Efficiency</strong><br>A joint research team, spearheaded by Professor Jongse Park from KAIST School of Computing, in collaboration with Georgia Institute of Technology and Uppsala University, has achieved a significant breakthrough in AI semiconductor technology. They developed “PIMBA,” a core AI semiconductor “brain” based on a novel hybrid Transformer and Mamba structure. This innovative design is implemented as a Processing-in-Memory (PIM) system, enabling direct computation within the memory itself. PIMBA addresses the critical challenges of escalating computational loads and memory demands in Large Language Models (LLMs) like GPT-4 and Llama. By minimizing data movement, PIMBA demonstrated a remarkable 4.1-fold increase in LLM inference speed and an average 2.2-fold reduction in power consumption compared to existing GPU systems, promising a new era for energy-efficient, high-performance AI processing. This research is scheduled for presentation at the 58th International Symposium on Microarchitecture (MICRO 2025).</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/semiconductor-brain-co.jpg" alt="KAIST PIMBA AI Semiconductor"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ceo-interviews/362391-ceo-interview-with-dr-bernie-malouin-founder-of-jetcool-and-vp-of-flex-liquid-cooling/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Dr. Bernie Malouin Founder of JetCool and VP of Flex Liquid Cooling</strong><br>In a recent interview, Dr. Bernie Malouin, Founder of JetCool and VP of Flex Liquid Cooling, provided key insights into the escalating challenges of thermal management for AI and High-Performance Computing (HPC) workloads. Malouin emphasized that traditional air cooling systems are increasingly struggling to keep pace with the unprecedented heat generated by modern CPUs and GPUs, leading to significant power and thermal constraints in data centers. JetCool, now a part of Flex, specializes in advanced direct-to-chip SmartPlate™ liquid cooling technology, which boasts over 20% better performance than conventional solutions by precisely targeting hot spots on silicon. The company offers vertically integrated, rack-level solutions that combine power distribution, liquid cooling, and system design, aiming to lower overall power consumption, drastically reduce water usage, and future-proof data center infrastructure against the rapid advancements in AI hardware.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Bernie-Malouin_Headshot_JetCool.png" alt="Bernie Malouin JetCool Flex"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates as the semiconductor industry continues to push the boundaries of innovation and efficiency!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251020_semiconductor_newslett</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="market trends" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/market-trends/"/>
    
    <category term="RISC-V" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/RISC-V/"/>
    
    <category term="chiplets" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/chiplets/"/>
    
    <category term="advanced packaging" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/advanced-packaging/"/>
    
    <category term="TSMC" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/TSMC/"/>
    
    <category term="AI semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI-semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="processing-in-memory" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/processing-in-memory/"/>
    
    <category term="LLMs" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/LLMs/"/>
    
    <category term="data center cooling" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/data-center-cooling/"/>
    
    <category term="liquid cooling" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/liquid-cooling/"/>
    
    <category term="IoT" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/IoT/"/>
    
    <category term="automotive electronics" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/automotive-electronics/"/>
    
    <category term="GlobalFoundries" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/GlobalFoundries/"/>
    
    <category term="imec" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/imec/"/>
    
    <category term="Google" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Google/"/>
    
    <category term="Synaptics" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Synaptics/"/>
    
    <category term="KAIST" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/KAIST/"/>
    
    <category term="Flex" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Flex/"/>
    
    <category term="JetCool" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/JetCool/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>System-HW Co-Design Approach Combines Mono3D DRAM, NMP, and GPU Acceleration</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251017_System-HW-Co-Design-Approach-Combines-Mono3D-DRAM,-NMP,-and-GPU-Acceleration/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251017_System-HW-Co-Design-Approach-Combines-Mono3D-DRAM,-NMP,-and-GPU-Acceleration/</id>
    <published>2025-10-16T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-17T04:15:00.992Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251017_machinelearning_newsletter_gpt-4o-mini.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">    Your browser does not support the audio element.  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/security/362587-secure-ic-and-silicon-labs-raise-the-bar-for-hardware-security/">News</a></h2><p><strong>IC and Silicon Labs Raise the Bar for Hardware Security</strong><br>Cybersecurity is becoming increasingly critical as AI-driven attacks escalate, necessitating enhanced hardware security measures. Secure-IC’s Securyzr™ neo Core Platform has been integrated into Silicon Labs’ SiXG301 SoC, establishing a Root of Trust that offers advanced protection against sophisticated threats. This collaboration has achieved the first-ever PSA Level 4 certification, providing robust assurance against physical and cyber attacks in connected devices.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Secure-IC-and-Silicon-Labs-Raise-the-Bar-for-Hardware-Security.png" alt="Secure-IC and Silicon Labs"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/on-package-memory-with-ucie-to-improve-bandwidth-density-and-power-efficiency-amd-intel-corp/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>On-Package Memory With UCIe To Improve Bandwidth Density And Power Efficiency</strong><br>Researchers at AMD and Intel have introduced a novel approach to on-package memory that leverages Universal Chiplet Interconnect Express (UCIe) technology. This development aims to enhance bandwidth density by up to 10x and reduce power consumption by up to 3x, addressing the growing demand for efficient memory solutions in AI and high-performance computing applications.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_993766061-03-26-2025-scaled.jpeg" alt="On-Package Memory"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/automotive/362517-why-choose-pcie-5-0-for-power-performance-and-bandwidth-at-the-edge/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Why Choose PCIe 5.0 for Power, Performance and Bandwidth at the Edge</strong><br>The latest webinar by Synopsys highlights the continued relevance of PCIe 5.0 in the era of Edge AI and high-performance applications. The chart showcases how PCIe 5.0 delivers high bandwidth and low latency, making it an ideal choice for a variety of sectors including automotive and data centers, while supporting the exponential growth of AI workloads.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/PCIe-5.0-Impact-Across-Markets-1200x677.jpg" alt="PCIe 5.0 Impact"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/system-hw-co-design-approach-combines-mono3d-dram-nmp-and-gpu-acceleration-ucsd-georgia-tech-uiuc-illinois-tech/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>System-HW Co-Design Approach Combines Mono3D DRAM, NMP, and GPU Acceleration</strong><br>A groundbreaking paper from researchers at UCSD and other institutions introduces “Stratum,” a co-design framework that integrates Mono3D DRAM with near-memory processing and GPU acceleration. This novel approach significantly improves decoding throughput by 8.29x and energy efficiency by 7.66x, offering a promising solution for deploying large-scale language models effectively.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_322557739-01-29-25-scaled.jpeg" alt="System-HW Co-Design"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/heterogeneous-system-with-specialized-hw-for-disaggregated-llm-inference-princeton-univ-univ-of-washington/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Heterogeneous System With Specialized HW For Disaggregated LLM Inference</strong><br>A panel discussion featuring experts from Princeton University and University of Washington unveiled insights into their latest research on specialized hardware for disaggregated LLM inference. The proposed SPAD architecture optimizes performance and cost, achieving significant hardware savings while meeting the demands of modern AI applications. This approach emphasizes the importance of tailored hardware solutions in the evolving landscape of machine learning.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_876124851-March-26-2025-scaled.jpeg" alt="Specialized HW"></p><hr><p>Stay connected with us for the latest updates in the semiconductor industry as we continue to explore innovations and trends shaping the future.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251017_machinelearning_newsle</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Machinelearning" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Machinelearning/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="hardware security" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/hardware-security/"/>
    
    <category term="design innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/design-innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="chip technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/chip-technology/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Cinch Details CIN-APSE Interconnect Evolution for Harsh Environments</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251014_Cinch-Details-CIN-APSE-Interconnect-Evolution-for-Harsh-Environments/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251014_Cinch-Details-CIN-APSE-Interconnect-Evolution-for-Harsh-Environments/</id>
    <published>2025-10-13T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-14T04:19:26.202Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251014_device_newsletter_gpt-4o-mini.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">    Your browser does not support the audio element.  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/arizona-benefits-from-tsmc-intel-as-semicon-west-debuts-in-phoenix/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Arizona Benefits from TSMC, Intel, SEMICON West Debuts In Area</strong><br>Arizona is seeing a significant surge in investment with over $210 billion dedicated to chip manufacturing since 2020, highlighted by the successful SEMICON West 2025 event. This year’s attendance doubled compared to last year, showcasing the growing semiconductor ecosystem in the state. Key players like TSMC and Intel are establishing strong local bases, emphasizing the importance of talent and supply chain resilience in driving future growth.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Semicon-west-2025-in-Phoenix-source_SEMI.jpg" alt="SEMICON West 2025"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/cinch-details-cinapse-interconnect-evolution-for-harsh-environments/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Cinch Details CIN:APSE Interconnect Evolution for Harsh Environments</strong><br>Cinch Connectivity Solutions unveiled its innovative CIN:APSE interconnect technology at Plublitek Connect 2025. This solderless, compression-based connector is designed for high-reliability applications, capable of withstanding extreme conditions. With its unique design, it offers significant flexibility in configurations and applications, making it suitable for critical environments such as space and defense.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Screenshot-2025-10-09-at-20.50.14-e1760037372904.png" alt="Cinch Technology"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/optics-shine-light-on-brain-functions/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>The Future of Optoelectronic Devices for Medical Applications</strong><br>Recent advancements showcased at the SPRC Symposium highlight the transformative potential of optogenetics in neuroscience, with significant implications for medical devices. Key presentations revealed how light-sensitive proteins can manipulate neuronal behavior, paving the way for innovative treatments and technologies in the healthcare sector.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/deisseroth-brain-activity.jpeg" alt="Optoelectronic Devices"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-10-ai-powered-method-global-chip.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>AI-powered Method Helps Protect Global Chip Supply Chains from Cyber Threats</strong><br>Researchers at the University of Missouri have developed a novel AI-driven method that detects hardware trojans with an impressive 97% accuracy. This innovative approach leverages large language models to scan chip designs for hidden vulnerabilities, offering a more efficient and transparent solution to enhance cybersecurity in semiconductor manufacturing.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2025/new-ai-powered-method.jpg" alt="AI Trojan Detection"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ceo-interviews/362398-ceo-interview-with-dr-gary-spittle-of-sonical/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Gary Spittle of Sonical</strong><br>In an engaging conversation, Gary Spittle, founder of Sonical, shares insights on the evolution of hearables into intelligent, upgradeable devices through their operating system, CosmOS. He discusses the potential for hearables to become a new platform for personal computing, emphasizing sustainability and customization while opening avenues for innovative applications in health monitoring and immersive audio experiences.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/GarySpittle-Sonical-1077x1200.jpeg" alt="Gary Spittle"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for further updates and insights in the semiconductor sector as we continue to track the latest trends and innovations shaping the future of technology!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251014_device_newsletter_gpt-</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/technology/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="cybersecurity" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/cybersecurity/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Global 300mm Fab Equipment Spending Expected to Total $374 Billion Over Next Three Years</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251013_Global-300mm-Fab-Equipment-Spending-Expected-to-Total-$374-Billion-Over-Next-Three-Years/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251013_Global-300mm-Fab-Equipment-Spending-Expected-to-Total-$374-Billion-Over-Next-Three-Years/</id>
    <published>2025-10-12T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-13T04:23:53.395Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251013_semiconductor_newsletter_gpt-4o-mini.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">    Your browser does not support the audio element.  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/lam-research-receives-2025-semi-award-for-north-america/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Lam Research Receives 2025 SEMI Award for North America</strong><br>Lam Research Corp. has been awarded the 2025 SEMI Award for North America for its innovative cryogenic etch technology, pivotal in advancing 3D NAND device manufacturing essential for AI applications. The award was presented during SEMICON® West, highlighting the company’s contributions to high-capacity memory solutions amidst soaring demand driven by generative AI.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="Lam Research Award"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/advanced-packaging-fuels-growth-in-the-semiconductor-back-end-equipment-market/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Advanced Packaging Fuels Growth in the Semiconductor Back-End</strong><br>The semiconductor back-end equipment market is forecasted to grow significantly, driven by advancements in packaging technologies. Innovative solutions like Thermo Compression Bonding (TCB) and hybrid bonding are transforming the landscape, catering to the demands of AI, HPC, and automotive applications, with the market expected to reach $9.8 billion by 2030.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Screenshot-2025-10-12-at-4.03.24-PM.png" alt="Advanced Packaging"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/semi-reports-global-300mm-fab-equipment-spending-expected-to-total-374-billion-over-next-three-years/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Global 300mm Fab Equipment Spending Expected to Total $374 Billion Over Next Three Years</strong><br>SEMI’s latest report indicates that global spending on 300mm fab equipment will exceed $374 billion between 2026 and 2028, with significant investments driven by AI chip demand and regional self-sufficiency initiatives. The report highlights a projected increase in spending, particularly in memory and logic segments.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Screenshot-2025-10-08-at-2.50.54-PM.png" alt="300mm Fab Equipment Spending"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://techxplore.com/news/2025-10-global-efficiency-large-triple-junction.html">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Global Efficiency Record Set for Large, Triple-Junction Perovskite Solar Cell</strong><br>A research team led by the University of Sydney has achieved a record 23.3% efficiency for a large-area triple-junction perovskite solar cell. This advancement is pivotal for the development of efficient solar technologies, moving closer to practical applications in energy generation and sustainability.</p><p><img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2025/global-efficiency-reco-1.jpg" alt="Triple-Junction Solar Cell"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/how-3d-ic-will-change-chip-design/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>How 3D-IC Will Change Chip Design</strong><br>Experts discuss the significant challenges and opportunities presented by 3D-IC design. The transition from traditional 2D designs to 3D stacking introduces complexities in verification, integration, and performance, necessitating new methodologies and collaborative approaches among chip designers.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/dac_2025_ed_-_rt_state_of_design_complexity_720.jpg" alt="3D-IC Design"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates as we continue to bring you the latest news and insights from the semiconductor industry.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251013_semiconductor_newslett</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Advanced Packaging" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Advanced-Packaging/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor Manufacturing" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor-Manufacturing/"/>
    
    <category term="Innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Innovation/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CEO Interview with Howard Pakosh of TekStart</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251010_CEO-Interview-with-Howard-Pakosh-of-TekStart/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251010_CEO-Interview-with-Howard-Pakosh-of-TekStart/</id>
    <published>2025-10-09T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-10T04:14:47.857Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251010_machinelearning_newsletter_gpt-4o-mini.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">    Your browser does not support the audio element.  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/double-duty-logic-block-architecture-enabling-concurrent-lut-and-adder-chain-usage-nanyang-technological-univ-et-al/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Double Duty Logic Block Architecture Enabling Concurrent LUT and Adder Chain Usage</strong><br>A new technical paper from researchers at Nanyang Technological University and other institutions presents the “Double Duty” FPGA architecture, which allows for concurrent use of LUTs and adder chains. This innovation enhances arithmetic density in FPGAs, achieving significant area reductions without affecting critical path delay. The proposed architecture promises a 9.7% improvement in area-delay product, making it a significant advancement for FPGA applications. </p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_1104488381-03-26-2025-scaled.jpeg" alt="Double Duty FPGA Architecture"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/events/362123-webinar-the-path-to-smaller-denser-and-faster-with-cpx-samtecs-co-packaged-copper-and-optics/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>The path to smaller denser and faster</strong><br>Samtec is set to host a webinar discussing its new co-packaged copper (CPC) and co-packaged optics (CPO) solutions, termed CPX, which enable advanced speeds of 224 Gbps. This integration aims to enhance performance in data centers and AI systems, addressing the common narrative that “copper is dead.” The event will showcase how combining copper and optical technologies can optimize interconnect strategies.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Webinar-%E2%80%93-The-Path-to-Smaller-Denser-and-Faster-with-CPX-Samtecs-Co-Packaged-Copper-and-Optics-1200x398.png" alt="Webinar on CPX Technology"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/3dic/361970-ai-everywhere-in-the-chip-lifecycle-synopsys-at-ai-infra-summit-2025/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>AI Everywhere in the Chip Lifecycle: Synopsys at AI Infra Summit</strong><br>Synopsys showcased an AI-driven ecosystem that integrates energy efficiency and accelerated design processes at the AI Infra Summit 2025. Key charts from the presentation illustrated how AI is now an end-to-end engine driving chip development, with the potential to reduce design times by up to 40% and improve energy efficiency amidst soaring AI workloads.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Godwin-Talk-Summary-AI-Infra-Summit-2025-1200x750.png" alt="AI in Chip Lifecycle"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/in-sram-computing-architecture-tailored-for-cryptographic-acceleration-within-mcus-uc-riverside/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>In-SRAM Computing Architecture Tailored For Cryptographic Acceleration Within MCUs</strong><br>Researchers from UC Riverside have introduced CryptoSRAM, an innovative in-SRAM computing architecture that enhances cryptographic operations directly within microcontroller units (MCUs). This architecture reportedly achieves throughput improvements of up to 74× for AES encryption compared to traditional software implementations, addressing performance and energy costs in IoT devices.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/Security-AdobeStock_328668955-01-29-25-scaled.jpeg" alt="CryptoSRAM Architecture"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/tekstart/361951-ceo-interview-with-howard-prakash-of-tekstart/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Howard Pakosh of TekStart</strong><br>In this insightful interview, Howard Pakosh discusses how TekStart has transitioned into a venture builder focused on semiconductors and AI. He highlights the innovative solutions being developed, particularly through their ChipStart business unit, which addresses critical industry challenges like energy efficiency and supply chain fragility, particularly in Edge AI applications.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/HP_biopic_2-740x1200.jpg" alt="Howard Pakosh, CEO of TekStart"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates as we continue to bring you the latest innovations and trends in the semiconductor industry!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251010_machinelearning_newsle</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Machinelearning" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Machinelearning/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="chip design" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/chip-design/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="architecture" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/architecture/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Emerson Leverages AI to Address Complexity in Test and Measurement</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251009_Emerson-Leverages-AI-to-Address-Complexity-in-Test-and-Measurement/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251009_Emerson-Leverages-AI-to-Address-Complexity-in-Test-and-Measurement/</id>
    <published>2025-10-08T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-09T04:11:32.751Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251009_etch_newsletter_gpt-4o-mini.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">    Your browser does not support the audio element.  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/qualcomm-to-acquire-arduino/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Qualcomm To Acquire Arduino</strong><br>Qualcomm Technologies announced its acquisition of Arduino, aiming to democratize access to edge computing and AI for developers worldwide. This acquisition follows Qualcomm’s earlier purchases of Edge Impulse and Foundries.io, expanding its reach to over 33 million active Arduino users. Arduino will maintain its independent brand and community spirit while enhancing its development tools, including the new Arduino UNO Q, designed for AI-powered solutions.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/Qualcomm-Arduino-Uno.jpeg" alt="Qualcomm Arduino"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/acm-research-unveils-ultra-ecdp-electrochemical-deplating-tool-for-compound-semiconductor-gold-etch-processes/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>ACM Research Unveils Ultra ECDP Electrochemical Deplating Tool for Compound Semiconductor Gold Etch Processes</strong><br>ACM Research has launched the Ultra ECDP tool for electrochemical gold etching, specifically designed for compound semiconductor manufacturing. This innovative tool improves uniformity and surface finish while addressing challenges in gold etching. It is engineered for various substrates and is compatible with both 6-inch and 8-inch wafer platforms, supporting multiple manufacturing environments.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="ACM Ultra ECDP Tool"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://newsroom.lamresearch.com/fabtex-yield-optimizer-improves-processes-for-high-volume-manufacturing?blog=true">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Volume Semiconductor Manufacturing Yield Improvement</strong><br>Lam Research has introduced the Fabtex™ Yield Optimizer, a groundbreaking software solution designed to enhance yield in high volume manufacturing (HVM) at fabs. Leveraging AI, machine learning, and virtual silicon digital twins, Fabtex significantly reduces process variability and time-to-market by identifying issues early in the manufacturing process. This innovative approach promises to enhance yield while minimizing wafer testing and waste.</p><p><img src="https://newsroom.lamresearch.com/image/Fabtex-Value-Proposition-REV-10-1C.jpg" alt="Yield Improvement Chart"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/imec-achieves-new-milestones-in-single-patterning-high-na-euv-lithography-for-both-damascene-and-direct-metal-etch-metallization-processes/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Imec Achieves New Milestones in Single Patterning High NA EUV Lithography</strong><br>At the 2025 SPIE Photomask Technology + EUV Lithography Conference, imec presented significant advancements in single print High NA EUV lithography. They achieved 20nm pitch line structures with a critical dimension of 13nm, essential for damascene metallization processes. These breakthroughs are poised to drive the semiconductor industry toward high volume manufacturing of sub-2nm logic technology, crucial for future innovations.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Final-Logo-1.png" alt="Imec Milestones"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/emerson-leverages-ai-to-address-complexity-in-test-and-measurement/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Emerson Leverages AI to Address Complexity in Test and Measurement</strong><br>At Publitek Connect 2025, Emerson unveiled its AI platform, Nigel, designed to simplify complex test and measurement workflows. This tool aids engineers in analyzing code and identifying hardware needs, improving efficiency in semiconductor testing. With a focus on integrating AI across its product lines, Emerson aims to enhance customer experience and adapt to the increasing complexity of modern semiconductor devices.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/emerson-expands-ai-capabilities-into-test-measurement-software-portfolio-en-us-11902676.jpg" alt="Emerson AI"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates as we continue to bring you the latest in the semiconductor industry!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251009_etch_newsletter_gpt-4o</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Etch" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Etch/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductor/"/>
    
    <category term="advanced packaging" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/advanced-packaging/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Via Multipatterning Regardless of Wavelength</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251008_Via-Multipatterning-Regardless-of-Wavelength/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251008_Via-Multipatterning-Regardless-of-Wavelength/</id>
    <published>2025-10-07T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-08T04:25:03.173Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251008_lithography_newsletter_gpt-4o-mini.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">    Your browser does not support the audio element.  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.asml.com/en/news/press-releases/2025/asml-mistral-ai-enter-strategic-partnership">News</a></h2><p><strong>ASML, Mistral AI enter strategic partnership</strong><br>ASML has announced a strategic partnership with Mistral AI, which involves a significant investment of 1.3 billion EUR. This collaboration aims to enhance ASML’s product offerings through AI integration, focusing on improving lithography systems for faster and more efficient semiconductor manufacturing.</p><p><img src="https://nan/" alt="ASML Partnership"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://www.nikonprecision.com/nikon-launches-new-dry-arf-scanner-for-fine-patterning-across-logic-memory-and-sensors/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>NSR-S333F ArF Scanner Now Open for Orders</strong><br>Nikon has launched its latest ArF scanner, the NSR-S333F, designed for high overlay accuracy and productivity. This scanner, built on advanced technology, is set to meet the growing demand for precision in semiconductor manufacturing.</p><p><img src="https://www.nikonprecision.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/S333-Image-from-Nikon-Corp-website.jpg" alt="Nikon Scanner"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/lithography/361912-via-multipatterning-regardless-of-wavelength-as-high-na-euv-lithography-becomes-too-stochastic/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Via Multipatterning Regardless of Wavelength</strong><br>A detailed analysis highlights that the minimum metal pitch for the 2nm node could reach 20 nm or less, necessitating advanced multipatterning techniques. This chart underscores the increasing complexity and need for innovation in semiconductor patterning as technology advances.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Fred-Chen-EUV-2025.png" alt="Via Multipatterning"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/first-stage-of-nanoscale-imaging-in-positive-tone-euv-photoresists-the-impact-of-polymer-sequence-berkeley-lab-columbia-hill/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>First Stage Of Nanoscale Imaging In Positive-Tone EUV Photoresists</strong><br>Researchers from Berkeley Lab have published insights into how the polymer sequence in positive-tone EUV photoresists affects imaging processes. Their findings could refine the understanding of resist performance and lead to improved resolution in semiconductor manufacturing.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_560372105-04-15-24.jpeg" alt="Research on Photoresists"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/pldc-a-robust-mpc-solution-for-any-mask-shape-with-zero-impact-on-turnaround-time/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>PLDC: A Robust MPC Solution for Any Mask Shape</strong><br>At SPIE Photomask Japan 2025, Micron discussed their new pixel-level dose correction technology, PLDC, which enhances efficiency in mask shops. This development signals a significant leap towards optimizing mask production processes for advanced semiconductor fabrication.</p><p><img src="https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Figure1.png" alt="PLDC Technology"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates as we continue to cover the latest innovations and developments in the semiconductor industry!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251008_lithography_newsletter</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Lithography/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Technology" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Technology/"/>
    
    <category term="Lithography" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Lithography/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductor" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductor/"/>
    
    <category term="Partnership" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Partnership/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Double Duty Logic Block Architecture Enabling Concurrent LUT and Adder Chain Usage</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251003_Double-Duty-Logic-Block-Architecture-Enabling-Concurrent-LUT-and-Adder-Chain-Usage/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20251003_Double-Duty-Logic-Block-Architecture-Enabling-Concurrent-LUT-and-Adder-Chain-Usage/</id>
    <published>2025-10-02T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-10-02T22:17:53.563Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20251003_machinelearning_newsletter_gpt-4o-mini.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">    Your browser does not support the audio element.  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://semiengineering.com/double-duty-logic-block-architecture-enabling-concurrent-lut-and-adder-chain-usage-nanyang-technological-univ-et-al/">News</a></h2><p><strong>Double Duty Logic Block Architecture Enabling Concurrent LUT and Adder Chain Usage</strong><br>A recent paper by researchers at Nanyang Technological University and partners introduces the Double Duty logic block architecture, allowing for concurrent usage of look-up tables (LUTs) and adder chains in FPGAs. This approach enhances arithmetic density and reduces area by up to 21.6% in adder-intensive circuits, while maintaining critical path delay.</p><p><img src="https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_1104488381-03-26-2025-scaled.jpeg" alt="Double Duty FPGA"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/events/362123-webinar-the-path-to-smaller-denser-and-faster-with-cpx-samtecs-co-packaged-copper-and-optics/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>The path to smaller denser and faster</strong><br>Samtec is set to host a webinar on October 21, discussing its innovative co-packaged copper (CPC) and co-packaged optics (CPO) technology, termed CPX. This development allows for advanced speeds of 224 Gbps, effectively integrating copper and optics for improved performance in data centers and AI applications.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Webinar-%E2%80%93-The-Path-to-Smaller-Denser-and-Faster-with-CPX-Samtecs-Co-Packaged-Copper-and-Optics-1200x398.png" alt="Samtec Webinar"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/3dic/361970-ai-everywhere-in-the-chip-lifecycle-synopsys-at-ai-infra-summit-2025/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>AI Everywhere in the Chip Lifecycle: Synopsys at AI Infra Summit</strong><br>At the AI Infra Summit, Synopsys illustrated how AI influences every phase of chip development, reducing design times by up to 40% and improving energy efficiency due to the expected fifty-fold growth in AI workloads by 2028. Their unified AI-driven ecosystem integrates design and verification, streamlining the semiconductor development process.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Godwin-Talk-Summary-AI-Infra-Summit-2025-1200x750.png" alt="AI Infra Summit"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/361711-neurosymbolic-code-generation-innovation-in-verification/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>Neurosymbolic code generation. Innovation in Verification</strong><br>A novel research paper from Rice University and collaborators proposes a neurosymbolic approach to automated code generation, significantly enhancing the accuracy of Java method generation. The method integrates symbolic reasoning with neural networks, achieving an impressive 86% success rate in syntax correctness checks compared to traditional large language models.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Innovation-New.jpeg" alt="Neurosymbolic Code Generation"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/tekstart/361951-ceo-interview-with-howard-prakash-of-tekstart/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Howard Pakosh of TekStart</strong><br>Howard Pakosh, CEO of TekStart, discusses the evolution of his company into a venture builder focused on semiconductors and AI. He highlights the challenges of supply chain fragility and energy efficiency while showcasing their Newport initiative, which delivers performance-per-watt advancements for Edge AI applications, addressing critical needs in various sectors.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/HP_biopic_2-740x1200.jpg" alt="Howard Pakosh"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned for more updates as we continue to bring you the latest in semiconductor and AI technology advancements.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20251003_machinelearning_newsle</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Machinelearning" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Machinelearning/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="Innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="Semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/Semiconductors/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Analog Bits Steps into the Spotlight at TSMC OIP</title>
    <link href="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250930_Analog-Bits-Steps-into-the-Spotlight-at-TSMC-OIP/"/>
    <id>https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/20250930_Analog-Bits-Steps-into-the-Spotlight-at-TSMC-OIP/</id>
    <published>2025-09-29T22:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-09-30T12:08:57.919Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;">  <audio controls>    <source src="/opensemi/podcasts/20250930_device_newsletter_gpt-4o-mini.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">    Your browser does not support the audio element.  </audio></div><h2 id="News"><a href="#News" class="headerlink" title="News"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/ai-drives-pcie-aspirations/">News</a></h2><p><strong>AI Drives PCIe Aspirations</strong><br>As the PCI-SIG gears up for the upcoming PCIe 8.0, the focus shifts to enhancing data rates and addressing the needs of next-gen applications, particularly in AI and automotive sectors. PCIe 8.0 aims for a staggering 256 GT&#x2F;s, while PCIe 7.0 has already made strides with its 128 GT&#x2F;s, emphasizing low latency and improved power efficiency. The evolution of PCIe is crucial to maintain backward compatibility while catering to the rapid changes in technology needs.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/edac_fig17_hispeed_card_edge_connectors.jpg" alt="PCIe Aspirations"></p><hr><h2 id="Launches"><a href="#Launches" class="headerlink" title="Launches"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ip/analog-bits/362122-analog-bits-steps-into-the-spotlight-at-tsmc-oip/">Launches</a></h2><p><strong>Analog Bits Steps into the Spotlight at TSMC OIP</strong><br>At the TSMC Open Innovation Platform Forum, Analog Bits introduced innovative IPs including LDOs and embedded clock LC PLLs, showcasing their capabilities on TSMC’s advanced N3P and N2P processes. Recognized as TSMC’s OIP Partner of the Year for the second consecutive year, Analog Bits highlighted the importance of power management in next-gen applications, especially for AI and automotive systems.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Analog-Bits-Steps-into-the-Spotlight-at-TSMC-OIP-1200x535.png" alt="Analog Bits at TSMC"></p><hr><h2 id="Charts"><a href="#Charts" class="headerlink" title="Charts"></a><a href="https://www.eetimes.com/cybersecurity-expectations-peak-as-genai-lands-in-the-trough/">Charts</a></h2><p><strong>Cybersecurity Expectations Peak as GenAI Lands in the Trough</strong><br>Gartner’s Hype Cycle for Supply Chain Strategy illustrates the current state of technologies where supply chain cybersecurity has reached its peak, while generative AI is facing disillusionment. The complex integration of GenAI into existing systems raises significant cybersecurity concerns, indicating a challenging road ahead for its scalability and practicality in real-world applications.</p><p><img src="https://www.eetimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/cybersecurity.keyboard.jpg" alt="Cybersecurity Hype Cycle"></p><hr><h2 id="Research"><a href="#Research" class="headerlink" title="Research"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/ceo-interviews/361937-ceo-interview-with-jiadi-zhu-of-cdimension/">Research</a></h2><p><strong>CEO Interview with Jiadi Zhu of CDimension</strong><br>Jiadi Zhu, the CEO of CDimension, discusses the company’s revolutionary approach to semiconductor materials, focusing on 2D materials that promise to overcome silicon’s limitations. With a vision for the future of computing that includes enhancements in power efficiency and noise reduction for quantum computing, CDimension aims to redefine chip design and scalability in a rapidly evolving technology landscape.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Jiadi-headshot-1200x800.jpg" alt="Jiadi Zhu"></p><hr><h2 id="Insight"><a href="#Insight" class="headerlink" title="Insight"></a><a href="https://semiwiki.com/artificial-intelligence/361705-arm-lumex-pushes-further-into-standalone-genai-on-mobile/">Insight</a></h2><p><strong>Arm Lumex Pushes Further into Standalone GenAI on Mobile</strong><br>Arm’s new Lumex platform illustrates a significant leap in mobile AI capabilities, allowing for robust on-device generative AI applications without relying on cloud infrastructure. The innovative CPU architecture and new core designs enable real-time interactions and efficient processing, marking a shift in how AI can be integrated into everyday mobile experiences.</p><p><img src="https://semiwiki.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/chatbot-on-Lumex-min-1200x643.png" alt="Arm Lumex"></p><hr><p>Stay tuned with us for the latest developments in the semiconductor industry, as we continue to bring you the most relevant news and insights!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/opensemi/podcasts/20250930_device_newsletter_gpt-</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="Device" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/categories/Device/"/>
    
    
    <category term="AI" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/AI/"/>
    
    <category term="innovation" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/innovation/"/>
    
    <category term="chip design" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/chip-design/"/>
    
    <category term="semiconductors" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/semiconductors/"/>
    
    <category term="industry news" scheme="https://blackfireagent.github.io/opensemi/tags/industry-news/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
